[音乐响起--字幕精校中--By Persisan]
[MUSIC PLAYING]
DAVID MALAN：好的，这是CS50。
DAVID MALAN: All right, this is CS50.
这是第一周，第二周。
And this is week one, our second week.
今天，回想一下，我们将专注于另一种称为
And today, recall that we'll focus on this other programming language called
C。
C.
我们给了你最后一瞥，其中
And we gave you a little glimpse of this last time, wherein
我建议将此代码显示在屏幕上
I proposed that this code here on the screen
你很快就会知道如何编程（如果还没有的话）。
is something that you will soon know how to program, if not already.
但是可以说它看起来和它有很大的不同
But suffice it to say it looks quite a bit dissimilar to what
我们看了上周，当然是Scratch，还有更多
we looked at last week which, of course, was Scratch, which was much more
好玩，更生动。
playful, much more graphical.
因此，请允许我从今天的一开始就声明，对于我们大多数人来说，
And so allow me to disclaim right from the get go today that for most of us,
今天会感觉有点像消防水带。
today will feel like a bit of a fire hose.
实际上，在这里被描绘为麻省理工学院的一个老黑客，
In fact, pictured here as an old hack from MIT,
其中一些勤劳的老人挂了一个真正的消火栓
wherein some industrious seniors hooked up an actual fire hydrant
到喷泉。
to a water fountain.
俗话说，从麻省理工学院接受教育
The saying being that getting an education from MIT
就像从消防栓上喝水一样。
is like drinking from a fire hydrant.
今天会有这样的感觉。
Today will feel a little bit like that.
因为这是一个特殊的场合，你实际上并没有
Because this is sort of a special occasion that you don't really have
场合经常描述。
occasion to describe very often.
但这是我们所有人都要学习一种新语言的地方。
But it's one in which we're all going to learn a new language.
确实，这不是我们每天都要做的事情。
And indeed, that's not something we do every day.
因此，乍一看，它看起来
And so at the first glance, it's going to look
像很多新的语法，很多新的想法。
like a lot of new syntax, a lot of new ideas.
但是，请允许我放心，很快会变成这样，
And yet, allow me to reassure, that what will soon look like this,
这个C代码在本质上是一回事
this C code here, is fundamentally the same thing
你已经看到，现在通过Scratch进行了尝试。
that you've seen and now experimented with last week by way of Scratch.
也就是说，在另一种编程语言中
That is to say, within this other programming language
C，它比较传统，它更多基于文本，更多基于键盘，
C, which is more traditional, which is more text-based, more keyboard-based,
我们仍然会看到函数，条件，布尔表达式，循环，
we're still going to see functions, conditions, Boolean expressions, loops,
等等。
and so on.
他们看起来都会有些不同。
They're going to all look a little different.
但是想法是一样的。
But the ideas are the same.
就像第一次走进某人的家一样
And so much like when walking into someone's home for the very first time
铺开土地，看到很多东西
and getting the lay of the land and seeing a lot of things
你以前从未见过的东西，你通常不关心所有
that you haven't seen before, you typically don't care about all
这些视觉细节。
of those visual details.
你可能只是简单地向前走并坐下。
You might just simply walk forward and sit down.
今天同样，我们将看到很多细节
Similarly today, we're about to see a whole lot of details
在这种编程语言的世界中。
in the world of this programming language.
但是眼下的目标是一眼就忽略一切
But the goal at hand is to ignore things at first glance
我们不一定理解并束缚那些想法，
that we don't necessarily understand and latch onto those ideas that
从上周开始熟悉。
are familiar from last week.
那么，我们如何着手编写计算机程序呢？
So how do we go about actually writing computer programs?
我们如何才能很好地编写它们？
How do we go about writing them well?
因此，让我建议，有一些指示灯可以
And so allow me to propose that there's a few guiding lights that
应该指导代码编写。
should guide writing of code.
其中之一当然是正确性。
One, of course, is correctness.
上周我们进行了探索，你的代码的正确性
And we explored this last week, whereby the correctness of your code
只是说它是否按预期工作。
just speaks to does it work as intended.
当你双击某个图标时，当你运行某些命令时，
When you double click some icon, when you run some command,
你或其他人编写的程序是否正常运行？
does the program that you or someone else wrote behave correctly?
它按照它说的做吗？
Does it do what it says?
但是编写好的软件还有其他方面
But there's other aspects to writing good software
和编写好的程序。
and writing good programs.
这与设计有关。
And that has to do with design.
上周我们提到了一点。
And we alluded a little bit this last week.
但是通过设计，它更像是一种定性，更主观的衡量，
But with design it's more of a qualitative, a more subjective measure,
你的代码编写得如何。
just how well written your code is.
试想一下，例如，从上一堂必须写论文的课开始，
So imagine, for instance, from taking a class where you have to write essays,
你当然可以提出非常正确的论据。
you could certainly make very correct arguments.
但是通过写很长的文字，你可以提出非常正确的论据，
But you could make very correct arguments by writing very long,
乱句子，重复自己，一般不写作
rambling sentences, repeating yourself, and generally not writing
一篇很好的论文或论文。
a very good essay or paper.
现在可能是正确的。
Now it might be correct.
那份纸上没有你的英语课，
There's nothing in that paper for your English class,
历史记录类，或者你说的任何不正确的内容。
history class, or whatever it may be that you said that was incorrect.
但是你可能不会在上面得到很好的评分，
But you might not get very good marks on it,
因为它的设计不是很好。
because it's just not very well-designed.
同样，在编程世界中，
And so similarly, in the programming world,
是否有实际上不仅仅编写正确代码的想法，
is there this notion of actually writing not only correct code,
但设计合理的代码。
but well-designed code.
在这里，你不会重复自己。
Wherein you don't repeat yourself.
你编写的代码相当有效。
You write code that's fairly efficient.
它没有完成比实际需要更多的工作。
It doesn't do more work than it actually needs to.
最后，让我为今天的课程提出建议，
And then lastly, let me propose for today onward in this class,
当你需要记住第三条轴时
that there's a third axis you should keep in mind when
涉及编写好的代码。
it comes to writing good code.
这与风格有关。
And that has to do with style.
这更多的是美学。
This is much more of an aesthetic.
因此，在类似撰写论文的世界中，
So this, in the analogous world of writing an essay,
会使用良好的标点符号，大写吗？
would be are using good punctuation, capitalisation?
你要缩进新段落吗？
Are you indenting new paragraphs?
那些从根本上讲的美学
And those kinds of aesthetics that fundamentally
不要改变你所说的正确性，
don't change the correctness of what you're saying,
不一定会改变你所提出的论点的质量，
don't change necessarily the quality of the arguments that you're making,
但是你的文章风格，就像你的代码风格一样，
but the style of your essay, much like the style of your code,
使你的代码更具可读性。
makes your code much, much more readable.
因此，在编写良好的代码时，你首先需要它
So when it comes to writing good code, you want it first
而且最重要的是要正确设计
and foremost to be correct, but also well well-designed
而且样式也不错。
and also well-styled.
再次，你很希望在撰写论文时希望
Much like, again, you would when writing an essay that you would hope
也会很好地反映你的能力。
would reflect well on your capabilities as well.
因此，例如在编写代码时，
So when it comes to writing code, like this, for instance,
上周有人提出的第一个C程序
this first C program that someone last week proposed quite
只需在屏幕上打印出来，你好，世界。
simply prints out on the screen, hello, world.
好吧，我们如何去编写这段代码？
Well, how do we go about writing this code?
上周，我们去了Scratch.MIT.edu编写了代码
Last week we wrote code by going to Scratch.MIT.edu
然后拖放拼图。
and then dragging and dropping puzzle pieces.
今天将有所不同。
Today is going to be a little different.
我们将在这里继续使用其他工具。
We're going to use a different tool here on out.
而且我们将更多地使用键盘
And we're going to use our keyboard much more
比我们的鼠标实际编程。
than our mouse to actually program.
但要这样做，我们将继续介绍
But to do so, we're going to go ahead and introduce
这学期的几种工具中的第一个，即CS50 IDE。
the first of several tools this semester, this one, known as CS50 IDE.
IDE是首字母缩写，是编程中的一种艺术术语，
IDE is an acronym, a term of art in programming,
代表集成开发环境。
that stands for Integrated Development Environment.
在这种情况下，这只是一种奇特的说法，
Which is just a fancy way of saying, in this context,
CS50 IDE是CS50自己的基于Web的编程环境。
that CS50 IDE is CS50's own web-based programming environment.
它本身并不特定于CS50。
And it's not specific to CS50 per se.
我们仅添加了许多对教育有用的功能
We've simply added a number of educationally useful features
在互联网上任何人都可以使用的第三方云工具之上。
on top of a third party cloud tool that anyone on the internet can use.
我们自己的版本位于此URLide.cs50.io。
And our own version thereof lives at this URL, ide.cs50.io.
因此，欢迎你立即使用该URL。
So you're welcome to follow along at that URL today.
但是你不需要在演讲过程中本身。
But you need not during lecture itself.
但是，对于即将到来的问题以及以后的问题，
But on this upcoming problem set and beyond,
你将实际使用该工具并对其更加熟悉吗？
will you actually use and get more familiar with this tool hands on.
因此，让我继续并在此处打开此工具。
So let me go ahead and open up this tool here.
所以我已经提前登录了。
So I've already logged in in advance.
你在这里看到的是可供你使用的基本用户界面。
And what you see here is the basic user interface that's available to you.
幸运的是，只有几个显着特征
And fortunately, there's only a couple of salient features
我们现在需要指出。
that we need to point out right now.
所以在屏幕顶部，它只是
So at the top of the screen here, it's just
一个大的黑色矩形，稍后将用代码填充。
a big black rectangle that in a moment is going to be filled with code.
就像使用Google文档一样
Much like using Google documents or something
这样，你可以在其中创建新标签和创建新文件，
like that, where you can create new tabs and create new files,
这是我要进行编程的地方，
this is where I'm going to do my programming,
沿着屏幕顶部。
along the top of the screen.
而在最下面的是我们现在的情况
And along the bottom is what we're, in a moment,
开始调用我们的终端窗口。
going to start calling our terminal window.
我可以在此终端窗口中实际运行命令并最终
It's in this terminal window that I can actually run commands and ultimately
运行我的实际代码。
run my actual code.
但是，让我们继续在这种环境下编写我们的第一个程序
But let's go ahead and write our very first program in this environment
并意识到该工具的确不是CS50特有的。
and realize that this tool, indeed, is not very CS50 specific.
旨在代表一个非常常见的流行编程
It's meant to be representative of a very common popular programming
环境中，你拥有所谓的文本编辑器，
environment, where you have a so-called text editor,
或选项卡式窗口，你可以在其中编写代码，
or tabbed windows where you can write code,
还有一个终端窗口，你可以在其中实际运行命令。
and a terminal window where you can actually run commands.
我们的恰好存在于云中。
Ours happens to exist in the cloud.
但是你当然可以选择编程
But you can alternatively program, certainly,
这些天在你自己的Mac，PC或任何其他设备上。
on your own Mac, or PC, or any other device these days.
但坦率地说，它往往只涉及一个不重要的数字
But frankly, it tends to involve just a non-trivial number
早期的技术困难，尤其是当我们所有人
of technical difficulties early on, especially when we all
具有不同版本的Mac OS和Windows等。
have different versions of Mac OS and Windows and the like.
因此，这种基于云的环境仅确保在第0天，
So this cloud-based environment just ensures that on day zero,
我们都可以拥有相同的精确编程经验。
we can all have the same exact programming experience.
因此，我将继续执行此操作。
So I'm going to go ahead and do this.
我将继续前进，转到“文件”和“新文件”。
I'm going to go ahead and go up to File and New File.
这将创建一个新标签，默认情况下名为Untitled1，
And this is going to create a new tab, by default called Untitled1,
不太有趣。
not very interesting.
因此，我现在将转到“文件和保存”。
So I'm going to now go up to File and Save.
默认情况下，我将把该文件另存为
And by default, I'm going to save this file as, for instance,
名称hello.c。
the name hello.c.
所以我想用这种语言编写我的第一个程序
So I want to write my very first program in this language called
C.我要打个招呼。
C. I'm going to call my file hello.
但我将以名为.c的文件扩展名结尾。
But I'm going to end it in a file extension called .c.
这确实是惯例。
And that's indeed the convention.
编写C程序时，它们应以.c结尾。
When writing C programs, they should end with .c.
就像你可能还记得的Scratch程序一样，它们以.sb3结尾。
Just like Scratch programs, as you may recall, end in .sb3.
所以我要继续，只需单击此处的绿色按钮
So I'm going to go ahead and simply click the green button here
这就是所谓的保存。
that's called Save.
除了名称和标签之外，什么都不会改变。
Nothing is really going to change except for the name and the tab there.
现在，我在左上角看到此选项卡称为hello.c。
Now I see at top left that this tab is called hello.c.
现在，我可以开始键入任何想要的内容了。
And now I can start typing anything I want.
坦率地说，我只是从内存中键入
And frankly, I'm just going to type from memory
我们上周和不久前看到的第一个程序。
the very first program we saw last week and just a moment ago.
我现在要包括stdio.h，无论现在是什么。
I'm going to do include stdio.h, whatever that is for now.
我现在要去做int main（void），不管现在是什么。
I'm going then going to do int main(void), whatever that is for now.
我要用花括号。
I'm going to use the curly brace.
然后，可以说合上那个大括号。
And then close that curly brace, so to speak, thereafter.
在这里，我要继续执行printf（“ hello，world”）
And in here, I'm going to go ahead and do printf("hello,world") followed
用分号。
by a semicolon.
现在，我脑海中浮现出了很多文字。
Now that was a whole lot of text right off the top of my head.
这是你很快就会想到的一种肌肉记忆
This is the kind of muscle memory that you'll soon
在编写程序时进行开发。
develop when writing a program.
我当然已经做过很多次了。
I've, of course, done this many times before.
这样我就可以做到了。
So I was able to just do it off the top of my head.
但是稍后，我们将梳理一下所有不同的线条和字符
But in a moment, we'll tease apart what all of the various lines and characters
我键入的内容确实可以。
that I typed actually do.
但是我现在想做的就是运行该程序。
But what I'd now like to do is run this program.
上周我们猜想这只会打个招呼，世界。
We conjectured last week that this is just going to print hello, world.
但是如何？
But how?
好吧，在我们的Mac，PC和手机的世界中，
Well, in the world of our Macs and PCs and phones,
如果我们要实际运行程序，只需点击一个图标即可。
we would all just tap an icon if we want to actually run a program.
今天不是这种情况，因为现在我们
That's not going to be the case today, because now we're
在更多的传统编程环境中。
in more of a traditional programming environment.
我们现在所处的环境要求
The environment that we're now in requires
我多使用键盘，
that I use my keyboard a little bit more,
或所谓的命令行界面或CLI。
or what's known as a Command Line Interface, or CLI.
这与图形用户界面或GUI或GUI形成对比，
This is in contrast with a Graphical User Interface, or G-U-I, or GUI,
这就是描述Mac OS窗口，iOS和Android的内容。
which is what describes Mac OS windows, iOS, and Android.
但是在命令行界面中，我必须做所有事情
But in a command line interface, I have to do everything
在所谓的命令行。
at a so-called command line.
到此为止，我指的是这种闪烁
And by that, I'm referring to this blinking
在屏幕底部提示。
prompt along the bottom of my screen.
再次在屏幕底部，我
Along the bottom of my screen here, again, I
被描述为终端窗口，我将在其中键入命令，
described as the terminal window, where I'm going to type commands,
这是我的命令行界面。
and this is my command line interface.
我在这里输入的任何内容都会发送到此计算机
Anything I type here is going to get sent to this computer
并希望在自己的硬件上执行。
and hopefully execute on its own hardware.
那么我该怎么做呢？
So how do I do this?
那我该怎么办？
And what do I do?
好吧，当然，要抓住的地方是用C或Python编写代码时
Well, the catch, of course, is that when writing code in C or Python
或恰好存在的Java或其他多种语言，
or Java or bunches of other languages that happen to exist,
那真的是要由我和你，人类来写和理解的。
that's really meant to be written and understood by me and you, the humans.
但是上周，唯一的语言是什么，
But per last week, what is the only language,
从某种意义上说，计算机能够理解？
in a sense, that computers understand?
布莱恩，我们可以为此请人吗？
Brian, could we call on someone for this?
电脑只会说什么语言？
What language do computers only speak?
因为我认为上周我们离开的地方之间存在脱节
Because I think there's a disconnect between where we left off last week
以及如果我正在编写现在看起来像这样的代码，我们目前所处的位置。
and where we're currently at if I'm writing code that now looks like this.
辛迪，计算机会说什么语言？
Cindy, what language do computers speak, would you say?
听众：二进制。
AUDIENCE: Binary.
DAVID MALAN：二进制。
DAVID MALAN: Binary.
并详细说明一下。
And just elaborate a little bit.
回顾一下，你所说的二进制是什么意思？
What do you mean by binary, to recap?
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yes.
因此，他们使用1和0来表示所有内容。
So they use 1's and 0's to represent everything.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
他们使用1和0来表示所有内容。
They use 1's and 0's to represent everything.
上周我们只关注数字和字母
And last week we focused on only things like numbers and letters
颜色，图像，视频和声音等等。
and colors and images and videos and sound and so forth.
但是我们实际上并没有谈论内置功能，哪些计算机也
But we didn't actually speak to built in functionality, which computers also
用0和1表示。
use 0's and 1's to represent.
那就是说，这些天计算机当然有能力打印
That is to say computers, of course, have the ability these days to print
屏幕上的东西。
something on the screen.
还有打印的概念，功能，功能，
And that notion of printing, that function, that functionality,
也可以说是在计算机的机壳下面表示的
also is represented underneath the hood of a computer, so to speak,
由0和1的某种模式组成。
by some pattern of 0's and 1's.
也就是说，我刚才输入的所有内容，
Which is to say that everything I just typed,
即使有点像英语
even though it kind of sort of looks like English
并以一种清晰的方式向你问好印刷品，世界，计算机，讽刺意味的是，
and kind of sort of clearly says print hello, world, the computer, ironically,
不知道我刚才打的是什么。
does not know what it is I have just typed.
为了让它了解我刚刚输入的内容，
In order for it to understand what I've just typed,
我实际上需要将其转换为0和1。
I need to actually convert it to 0's and 1's.
因此，实际上，此过程的下一步
And so, indeed, the next step in this process
是要用我在这里用C编写的描述为我的源代码的方式，
is to take what I'll describe as my source code, written here in C,
上周，我们也看到了源代码，它只是图形化的。
and last week, too, we saw source code, it was just graphical.
那是Scratch中的那些拼图。
It was those puzzle pieces in Scratch.
这是我的源代码，尽管它是神秘的，但至少我是这样，
This is my source code that, even though cryptic, is something I, at least,
人类，最终可以读写。
the human, eventually can read and write.
但是我需要从字面上将其转换为0和1的模式
But I need to literally convert it to patterns of 0's and 1's
计算机可以理解的。
that the computer can understand.
现在我如何到达这一点？
Now how do I get to this point?
好吧，值得庆幸的是，我们上周有了一个心理模型
Well, thankfully, we have a mental model from last week
涉及解决问题。
that involves problem solving.
这是一个问题。
And here's a problem.
我如何获取以这种称为C的语言编写的源代码，
How do I take source code, written in this language supposedly called C,
并将其转换为计算机可以理解的0和1？
and convert it to 0's and 1's that the computer understands?
好吧，我敢说，我的输入将成为我的源代码。
Well, my input, I daresay, is going to be my source code.
理想情况下，我的输出将是我们称为机器代码的东西。
And my output, ideally, is going to be what we'll call machine code.
机器码只是描述0的艺术术语
Machine code is just a term of art describing the 0's
和计算机可以理解的1。
and 1's that computers understand.
上周我们没有使用该表达式。
We didn't use that expression last week.
但这只是在右侧引用0和1，在左侧引用C代码。
But this just refers to 0's and 1's on the right and C code on the left.
所以这引发了一个问题，好吧，我的源代码和机器之间是什么
So that invites the question, well, what is between my source code and machine
代码？
code?
如果我将源代码输入到众所周知的黑匣子中，
If I take my source code and feed it into the proverbial black box,
我如何从黑匣子中取出计算机的0和1
how do I get out of this black box the 0's and 1's that the computer
懂吗？
understands?
好吧，我需要一个特殊的程序，
Well, I need a special program that we're
开始调用编译器。
going to start calling a compiler.
编译器是可以免费下载的程序，
A compiler is a program that you can download for free,
或支付当天的费用，这是一个设计好的程序
or pay for back in the day, that is a program designed
将源代码转换为机器代码。
to convert source code to machine code.
所以，如果我想真正解决，我需要做的所有事情
So all I need do if I want to actually solve
如前所述的问题，因此我用C编写了这段代码
the problem as stated earlier, whereby I have written this code in C
现在我需要将其转换为0和1
and I now need to convert it to 0's and 1's, I just
需要授予自己访问编译器的权限。
need to give myself access to a compiler.
事实证明，CS50 IDE中存在其中一种。
And it turns out one of those exists within CS50 IDE.
这是你可以在自己的Mac或PC或类似设备上下载的工具。
And this is a tool you could download on your own Mac or PC or the like.
现在，我们将把这个工具描述为非常简单的称呼
And for now, we're going to describe that tool as being quite simply called
“制作。”
"make."
从字面上看，如果我想编写程序，我就是
Literally, if I want to make my program, I'm
继续并输入make hello。
going to go ahead and type make hello.
然后，我将使用一些神秘的语法来运行它，
And then I'm going to run it with a little bit of a cryptic syntax,
。/你好。
./hello.
但是，让我们看看将这些结合在一起的实际效果。
But let's see that in action to tie this all together.
我将光标移到终端窗口，
I'm going to move my cursor down into my terminal window,
或我的命令行界面。
or my command line interface.
我将按字面意义打招呼。
And I'm going to literally type hello.
注意，我没有输入make hello.c。
Notice I am not typing make hello.c.
我正在输入实际上要制作的程序的名称
I'm typing the name of the program I actually want to make
我只是想给这个程序打个招呼。
and I just want to call this program hello.
编译器将从此命令推断
The compiler is going to infer from this command
我实际上打算编译一个名为hello.c的文件。
that I actually intend to compile a file called hello.c.
我要继续并按Enter。
I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter.
有一些疯狂的神秘输出。
There's some crazy cryptic output.
改天再说。
More on that another day.
但是我看不到任何严重的红色错误消息的事实
But the fact that I don't see any big scary red error messages
是一件好事。
is a good thing.
这意味着我的程序已成功编译。
This means that my program compiled successfully.
为什么？
Why?
只是没有黄色或红色消息要说其他话。
There's just no yellow or red messages to say otherwise.
但是现在，如果我想实际运行该程序，
But now, if I want to actually run this program,
我需要键入另一个类似于double的命令
I need to type a different command that's the analog of double
点击Mac或PC或手机上的图标。
clicking an icon on your Mac or PC or phone.
我将按字面意思输入./hello。
I'm going to type literally ./hello.
./hello本质上就像是说进入计算机上的当前文件夹
./hello essentially is like saying go into the current folder on the computer
我正在使用并寻找一个名为hello的程序。
I'm using and look for a program called hello.
我要继续并按Enter键，瞧，世界。
I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter and voila, hello, world.
现在，我再次在屏幕上看到一个美元符号和一些其他文本。
Now I see, again, a dollar sign and some other text on the screen.
我们将稍微说明一下这是什么意思。
And we'll tease apart in just a bit what this means.
但是请注意，这个美元符号只是持续不断的视觉提醒
But notice, this dollar sign is just a constant visual reminder
提示所在的位置，可以在其中键入更多命令的位置。
of where my prompt is, where I can type more commands.
计算机确实完成了我所要求的。
And the computer has done literally what I asked.
它打印出你好，世界。
It printed out hello, world.
现在，它正在等待我的第二条命令。
And now it's waiting for my second command.
所以这就像只是在猫的嘴里打个招呼，打个比方。
So that was the analog of just printing hello, world out of the cat's mouth
上个星期。
last week.
但是，我们当然可以做得更多。
But surely we can do more than this.
但是，让我们将其与上周的工作联系起来。
But let's tie it back to what we did last week as well.
因此，并非此处的所有内容都如此不同。
So that not everything here is all that dissimilar.
所以回想一下上周，我们有职能。
So recall that last week, we had functions.
事实证明，尽管我们没有
And it turns out we had something called arguments, even though we didn't
必然如此形容他们。
necessarily describe them as such.
因此，功能就像一个小程序。
So a function is like a mini-program.
这是你在写作时可以使用的动作或动词
It's an action or a verb that you can use when writing
你自己的程序可以执行某些操作。
your own program that does something.
上周我们看到了发言权障碍。
We saw the say block last week.
上周我们看到了等待的机会。
We saw the wait block last week.
这些是动词或动作，或更常见的功能。
Those were verbs, or actions, or more generally noticed functions.
但是函数也可以接受输入，调用，我们上周确实看到了。
But functions can also take inputs, recall, and we did see that last week.
如今，我们将开始调用函数参数的输入，
And nowadays, we're going to start calling inputs to functions arguments,
可以这么说。
so to speak.
它们的另一个术语是参数。
Another term for them is parameters.
但是出于所有意图和目的，它们都是同义词。
But for all intents and purposes, those are synonyms.
参数是函数的输入。
Arguments are the inputs to functions.
那么，让我们考虑一下，从上周开始，
So let's consider then, from last week, the say
我们上次看到的方块，只是想说出来
block that we saw last time, which simply is trying to say out
猫的嘴，你好，世界。
of the cat's mouth, hello, world.
好吧，让我继续，如果可以的话，将其转换为相应的C代码，
Well, let me go ahead and convert this, if you will, to corresponding C code,
只是为了强调这两种语言在本质上是多么相似
just to emphasize how similar, fundamentally, these two languages
即使在语法上C在外观上绝对不同。
are, even though syntactically C absolutely looks visually different.
事实证明，如果你想用C语言说些话，
It turns out that if you want to say something in C,
像我一样使用这种基于文本的语言，
using this text-based language like I just did,
你不会写说。
you're not going to write say.
相反，你将要写印刷品。
You're instead going to write print.
这实际上是个谎言。
That's actually a bit of a white lie.
你不会说印刷品。
You're not going to say print.
实际上，你将要说printf，这是我们最终会看到的原因。
You're actually going to say printf, for reasons we'll eventually see.
这意味着打印格式化的东西。
It means print a formatted something or other.
因此，printf是Scratch中C语言的类似物。
So printf is the analog in C of say in Scratch.
现在注意在C中，我已经有了这个开放的括号
Now notice in C, I've got this open parenthesis
和圆括号，这很好地是卵形的。
and closed parenthesis that, nicely enough, are kind of ovular in shape.
并注意，它们有点模仿白色椭圆形
And notice that they kind of mimic the white oval
上周我们在其中提供了意见。
into which we provided input last week.
所以在这两个括号之间
So in between those parentheses are going
作为我对该函数printf的输入，也称为参数。
to be my inputs to this function printf, otherwise known as arguments.
但是，本周它们将有所不同。
But they're going to be a little different this week.
是的，我要打个招呼，世界，中间用逗号隔开，
Yes, I'm going to say hello, world, with a comma in between,
在语法上，就像上周一样。
grammatically, just like last week.
但是在C语言世界中，我必须更加具体一些。
But in the world of C, I have to be a little more particular.
我还必须在左右添加双引号。
I also have to add double quotes on the left and the right.
而且，有些烦人的是，我还必须添加一个分号
And, somewhat annoyingly, I also have to add a semicolon
在此代码行的末尾。
at the end of this line of code.
因此，就像英语或许多人类语言一样，
So just like in English, or in a lot of human languages,
例如，你用句号结尾一个句子，
you end a sentence, for instance, with a period,
在许多行代码中，你将用C编写
in many lines of code you will write in C
在这种情况下，你还必须使用分号来结束你的想法。
you've also got to finish your thought, in this case, with a semicolon.
因此，这是最右边的方法
So this, then, on the right, is the closest way
分别将左侧的内容从Scratch转换为C。
of translating this thing on the left from Scratch to C respectively.
因此，想法仍然是相同的。
So the ideas are still the same.
但是语法看起来有些不同。
But the syntax looks a little different.
最终，我们必须根深蒂固，
And we've just got to ingrain in ourselves, ultimately,
这些模式是什么以及这些人类惯例是什么。
what these patterns are and what these human conventions are.
但是请注意，我们刚才所做的工作遵循与上周相同的范例。
But notice that what we just did follows the same paradigm as last week.
但是，让我们在本周再添加一些术语。
But let's add a little more terminology this week.
上周，我们将黑匣子描述为可能是算法，
Last week, we described the black box as potentially being algorithms,
最初。
initially.
然后我们开始调用它们的功能。
And then we started calling them functions.
函数只是算法的编程版本，实现
Functions are just a programmed version of an algorithm, the implementation
在软件中的代码算法的概念。
of an algorithm in code, in software.
因此，此处的功能可能表示为采用现在已经知道的输入
So a function might be represented here as taking inputs otherwise known now
作为参数。
as arguments.
但是事实证明，函数至少可以完成两种不同类型的事情
But it turns out that functions can do at least two different types of things
在编程领域。
in the world of programming.
我们已经看过这些东西，但是我们没有描述它们
And we've seen these things already, but we didn't describe them
就像我们今天要做到的一样。
quite as particularly as we will today.
当一个函数接受输入时，就是说参数，
When a function takes inputs, that is to say arguments,
就像你好一样，世界是Scratch中say块的输入
just like hello, world is an input to the say block in Scratch
或C语言中的printf函数，这些函数可能具有所谓的副作用。
or the printf function in C, functions can have what are called side effects.
回想一下，我们上次确实看到了这一点。
And recall, we did see this last time.
当我们使用say块时，它确实输出了一些内容。
When we used the say block, it did output something.
但是从技术上讲，它具有副作用，视觉上的副作用。
But more technically, it had a side effect, a visual side effect.
当我上周使用say块和本周使用printf函数时，
When I used the say block last week and the printf function this week,
你会在屏幕上看到一些东西。
you see something on the screen.
也就是说，是某种形式的输出。
And that is, yes, some form of output.
但这与其他形式的输出有些不同
But it's a little different from a different form of output
我们上次看到的。
that we saw last time.
因此，功能的副作用通常是视觉上的
So a side effect of a function is often something visual
在屏幕上发生的情况，例如文本或音频。
that happens on the screen, like text or audio in that case.
但是我们将要看到的其他功能是功能
But there's this other feature of functions that we're going to see
并利用今天称为返回值的方法，其中一个函数可以真正地
and leverage today known as return values, where a function can really
只是给你一个价值。
just hand you back a value.
它不会在屏幕上说出来。
It's not going to say it on the screen.
它不会发出声音。
It's not going to vocalize it audibly.
它将以某种方式将其传递回给你，程序员，
It's going to just pass it back to you in a way that you, the programmer,
可以重用该函数的任何输出
can reuse whatever the output of that function
是，理想情况下甚至将其存储在变量中。
was, ideally storing it even in a variable.
例如，回想一下上周我们问过人类
So for instance, recall last week that we asked the human
他们的名字通过这个Ask块。
their name by way of this ask block.
这个白色椭圆形的Ask块的输入是，你叫什么名字。
And the input to the ask block in this white oval was, what's your name.
然后回想一下，上个星期这个问题块有点特殊。
And then recall that this ask block was a little special last week.
因为它使我们能够访问人类最终输入的内容。
Because it gave us access to whatever the human ultimately typed in.
也就是说，上周的ask块实际上返回了一个值。
And that is to say that the ask block last week essentially returned a value.
它不仅会盲目地在屏幕上显示人类输入的任何单词。
It didn't just blindly display whatever word the human typed in on the screen.
不，它在某种意义上隐喻地返回了它
No, it instead returned it in some sense metaphorically
并将其存储在一个名为answer的特殊变量中。
and stored it in a special variable called answer.
同样，这就是区别。
And so, again, that's the difference.
say块实际上在屏幕上说出一些内容。
The say block literally says something on the screen.
并立即产生视觉效果。
And there's an immediate visual effect.
使用Ask块，输入你的姓名后，
With the ask block, after you type in your name,
你不会在屏幕上看到你的姓名被打印或再次显示。
you don't see your name printed or displayed again on the screen.
取而代之的是，你的名字隐藏在一个变量中，
Instead, your name is sort of tucked away in a variable,
就像数学家将数字存储在x或y或z这样的变量中一样。
just like a mathematician would store a number in a variable like x or y or z.
上个星期，我们的责任就在程序员身上
The onus was then on us, the programmer, last week
最终用我的名字来做某事
to eventually do something with the value, my name, that
在那个叫做答案的变量中。
was in that variable called answer.
那么，我们本周如何将上周的Ask块翻译为C？
So how are we going to translate last week's ask block to C this week?
好吧，事实证明在C中有不同的方法可以做到这一点，没有一个
Well, it turns out there's different ways to do this in C, none of which
除非你使用所谓的库，否则非常容易。
are very easy unless you use what's called a library.
库是别人写的代码。
A library is code that someone else has written.
确实，我们今天将使用的一件事
And indeed, one of the things we'll use today
是所谓的CS50库，它是一堆代码，不是很多，
is the so-called CS50 library, which is a bunch of code, not terribly much,
员工和我写的只是为了使做简单的事情变得更容易。
that the staff and I wrote just to make it easier to do simple things.
这些是我们将完全起飞的训练轮
These are training wheels of sorts that we'll take off completely
在几周的时间内。
within a few weeks' time.
但是为了快速起步，
But in order to get started quickly, it's
这样将使操作变得更容易，例如从用户那里获取文本。
going to make it easier to do things like getting text from the user.
因此，字符串是编程世界中的艺术术语。
So string is a term of art in the programming world.
字符串是文本。
A string is text.
这是一个词。
It's a word.
这是一封信。
It's a letter.
这是一段。
It's a paragraph.
这是一页文字。
It's a page of text.
它只是某种形式的文本。
It's just text in some form.
字符串是计算机科学家所说的文本。
String is what a computer scientist would call text.
get_string是一个我们编写的函数，我们将
get_string is a function that we wrote that we will
提供给你确实需要输入。
provide to you that does take inputs.
请注意，根据C此处的括号，它可以接受输入。
Notice, per the parentheses here in C, it can take input.
该输入可能是什么？
What might that input be?
好了，就像问块一样
Well, just like the ask block, it's going
是人类最终应该看到的提示。
to be a prompt that the human should ultimately see.
因此，除了使用此功能之外，还有更多的事情要做。
So there's a bit more involved, though, than just using this function.
当你在C语言中使用get_string时，正如我们将在实时演示中很快看到的那样，
When you use get_string in C, as we will soon see in a live demo,
你想用人的名字做某事。
you want to do something with the human's name.
为了以人的名字做某事，
And to do something with the human's name,
仅仅相信Scratch还不够
it's not quite sufficient to just trust that Scratch
会为你将其放入变量中。
will put it in a variable for you.
与大多数编程语言一样，在C语言中，它学究得多。
In C, as with most programming languages, it's a lot more pedantic.
例如，如果你希望某些内容以变量结尾，
Like, if you want something to end up in a variable,
你必须自己做。
you've got to do it yourself.
麻省理工学院不会为你神奇地将其放在答案变量中。
MIT is not going to magically put it in an answer variable for you.
你必须自己做。
You have to do it yourself.
因此，你只需提供所需变量的名称，
So to do this, you simply come up with the name of the variable that you want,
是x还是y或z，或更令人信服的是，
be it x or y or z, or more compellingly, answer,
然后你使用等号，即单个等号。
and you use an equal sign, a single equal sign.
即使在数学上这通常意味着在C的情况下相等，
And even though in math this generally implies equality, in the context of C,
和大多数编程语言一样，实际上等号
and most programming languages, the equal sign actually
就是我们所说的分配。
means what we'll call assignment.
这意味着有效地复制右边的内容
It means, effectively, copy whatever is on the right
进入左边的任何东西。
into whatever's on the left.
因此，如果在右手边有一个功能，其作用在生活中
So if on the right-hand side there's a function whose purpose in life
就是问人类他们叫什么名字
is to ask the human what their name is, that name
最终将被从右复制到左
is going to get copied from right to left ultimately
放入这个称为答案的变量中。
into this variable called answer.
麻省理工学院在Scratch中自动为我们做到了。
MIT did that automatically for us in Scratch.
在C语言中，你必须自己做。
In C, you have to do it yourself.
但是你也必须更加特别。
But you have to be a little more particular, too.
事实证明，在C语言世界中，你不能只拥有变量。
It turns out that in the world of C, you can't just have variables.
你必须事先告诉计算机你想要什么类型的变量。
You have to tell the computer in advance what type of variable you want.
具体来说，我要告诉计算机变量类型
And specifically, I'm going to tell the computer that the type of variable
我要成为一个字符串。
I want is going to be a string.
这样做的惯例是你从字面上写出类型的名称
And the convention for doing so is you literally write the name of the type
你想要的字符串是到目前为止我们唯一看到的字符串。
that you want, string being the only one we've seen thus far.
然后，编写变量的名称。
Then you write the name of the variable.
然后，再次为该变量从右到左分配一个值，
And then, again, to assign a value to that variable from right to left,
我们必须在这里使用单个等号。
we have to use the single equal sign here.
而现在，只是一个短暂的停顿。
And now, just a quick pause.
布赖恩，如果我们可以为此请人，
Brian, if we could call on someone for this,
即使你以前从未编程过，如果你已经动心了
even if you've never programmed before, if you've taken to heart
我之前的建议之一。
one of my pieces of advice earlier.
我仍然想念一些东西。
I'm still missing something.
我要如何完成此Scratch代码的翻译
How might I want to finish the translation of this Scratch code
到右侧的C？
to C on the right-hand side?
你能说出什么缺失？
What is missing from what you can tell?
如果你之前进行过编程，则很有可能会立即跳出来。
If you've programmed before, odds are it will jump right out.
如果你以前从未编程过，
If you've never programmed before, you'll
必须回想一下我之前说的话。
have to think back on what I said earlier.
雅各布，你怎么看？
Jacob, what do you think?
听众：分号？
AUDIENCE: Semicolon?
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
只有一个愚蠢的分号
There's just one single, stupid semicolon
该行末尾缺少的内容，这对于向计算机表明是必须的
missing at the end of the line, which is necessary to make clear to the computer
到此为止。
that this is the end of this thought.
我觉得这很愚蠢。
And I sort of impugn it as stupid.
老实说，这是学习编码的最大挫败之一，
Because honestly, one of the biggest frustrations when learning how to code,
正如今天，本周及以后发生的那样，
as will now happen today and this week and beyond,
最初，你会忘记分号之类的愚蠢事物，
is initially you're going to forget stupid things like the semicolon,
否则你将忘记单引号或括号，
or you're going to forget a single quote mark, or a parenthesis,
或类似的东西。
or things like this.
我今天能提供的最重要的建议
And the most important advice I can give today
只是不要让那些愚蠢的事情感到沮丧。
is just try not to get frustrated by those kinds of stupid things.
有趣得多。
It's a lot more interesting.
在生活中，了解功能和循环非常有用
It's a lot more useful in life to understand functions and loops
和条件，不要让自己沮丧
and conditions and not to let yourself get frustrated
老实说，随着实践的发展，会出现一些次要的美学问题。
by the more minor aesthetic things that honestly will just come with practice.
因此，如果你犯的第一个错误是缺少分号，
So if the very first mistake you make is missing a semicolon,
这需要10分钟一个小时才能弄清楚
and it takes you 10 minutes, an hour to figure out what
你的代码有错，完全正常。
is wrong with your code, totally normal.
这些挫败感很快就会消失。
And those frustrations go away quite quickly in time.
这样我们就可以将一个功能转换为另一个功能。
So we then have this translation of one function to another.
我们还能从这里拿走它吗？
Where else can we take it from here?
好吧，让我们来看看另一种翻译
Well, let's take a look at one other translation
我们在那个Ask块之后使用的
that we used after that ask block.
上周，在我们问了人类的名字之后，
Last week, after we asked the human their name,
例如，通过为函数提供输入并获得一些输出，
as by providing an input to the function and getting some output,
然后，我们继续对Ask的返回值或输出进行处理。
we then proceeded to do something with the return value or output of ask.
再次，我们问了人类他们的名字。
Again, we asked the human their name.
上周神奇地从头开始，将名称放入了答案变量。
Scratch magically, last week, put the name into the answer variable.
但是后来我做了一些事情。
But then I did something with it.
这就是我要区别副作用的意思，这种情况只是在发生
And this is what I mean to distinguish side effects, which just kind of happen
对你来说，就像在屏幕上打印的东西一样，
to you, like something printing on the screen,
就像猫从嘴里说出一些话，而不是返回值，
like the cat saying something out of its mouth, versus a return value,
这是一条信息，就像人类键入的名字一样
which is a piece of information, like a name a human has typed
存放在程序员可以稍后使用的地方。
in being stored somewhere where you, the programmer, can make use of it later.
这不是发生在你身上。
It's not happening to you.
它正交给你以后使用。
It's being handed to you for subsequent use.
上周，为了一口气打个招呼逗号世界，
And last week, in order to say hello comma world all in one breath,
可以这么说，我们有点不得不堆叠这些拼图
so to speak, we kind of had to stack these puzzle pieces
在彼此的顶部，使输出连接到say的输入。
on top of one another, making the output of join the input of say.
在C语言中，尽管这是一些新语法，但实际上要容易一些。
In C, this is actually a little easier even though it's some new syntax.
同样，printf将成为类似的说法。
Again, printf is going to be the analog for say.
我们刚才已经看到了。
And we've seen that a moment ago.
我们仍然要加上括号。
We're still going to have the parentheses.
我们仍然要使用分号。
We're still going to have the semicolon.
那么现在输入里面有什么呢？
So what goes inside now the input?
我如何提供问候，回答C？
How do I provide hello, answer to C?
好吧，我将继续用双引号打个招呼，但是，
Well, I'm going to go ahead and do hello, in double quotes, but then,
这种奇怪的新语法，％s。
this strange new syntax here, %s.
这就是我们所说的格式代码，格式代码，因此
This is what we're going to call a format code, a format code, and hence
printf中的f。
the f in printf.
Printf不仅打印东西。
Printf doesn't just print things.
它也可以打印格式代码。
It can print format codes as well.
这只是在这里说出一些实际值而已的花哨语法。
And this is just fancy syntax for saying plug in some actual value here.
不要从字面上打印出来。
Don't print out s literally.
这是字符串s的占位符。
This is a placeholder for what will be s, a string.
好吧，我想放什么呢？
Well, what do I want to put there?
这也是新的东西。
Here's something new, too.
在Scratch中，如果一个函数有两个输入，
In Scratch, if you had two inputs to a function,
你将有两个这样的椭圆形，而另一个
you would have two ovals like this and this one
在这里，你可以在其中输入单词或数字，也可以将变量拖动到其中。
here that you could either type words or numbers into or drag variables into.
在C语言中，根本没有椭圆或图形的概念。
In C, there's no notion of ovals or graphics at all.
因此，我们只是去上学，只用逗号。
So instead, we're just going to go old school and just use a comma.
如果在括号之间使用逗号作为参数
If you use a comma in between the parentheses as the arguments
或功能的输入，这会将左侧的功能分开
or inputs to a function, that's going to separate the one on the left
从右边的那个开始，因此类似于
from the one on the right, thereby being analogous to having
在Scratch世界中有两个椭圆形
two ovals in the world of Scratch now there's
在这里可能在视觉上有些混乱。
something that's potentially a little visually confusing here.
当然，这里和这里实际上有两个逗号。
There's actually two commas here, of course, and here.
但是请注意重要的细节。
But notice the important detail.
第一个是英文语法逗号
That first one, that's an English grammatical comma
我已经在加引号的字符串（加引号的文本短语）中添加了内容。
that I've put inside of my quoted string, my quoted phrase of text.
这与编程无关。
That has nothing to do with programming.
那只是与英语有关。
That just has everything to do with English.
这个逗号不在双引号中，
The fact that this comma is outside of those double quotes,
但是，这意味着它在称为C的语言中非常重要。
though, means it's significant in this language called C.
它将第一个参数与第二个参数分开。
And it separates first argument from second argument.
这样，我们现在有能力
And so in this way do we have the ability now
也以这种稍微新颖的方式使用printf在屏幕上说些什么。
to also say something on the screen using printf in this slightly new way.
因此，让我继续前进，并真正做到这一点。
So let me go ahead then and do this for real.
让我回到CS50 IDE。
Let me go back to CS50 IDE.
我将继续进行该程序
And I'm going to go ahead and go back into this program
在这里考虑片刻，我们如何
here and consider for just a moment how we
可以改进这个最初打印的程序
can improve upon this very first program which literally just prints
你好，世界。
hello, world.
没那么有趣。
Not that interesting.
我可以整天运行它。
I can run it all day long.
它会说同样的话。
It's going to say the same thing.
现在如何从用户那里获得输入？
How do I now get input from the user?
好吧，事实证明，我可以简单地对此代码进行一点增强。
Well, it turns out that I can simply enhance this code a little bit.
让我继续，先进行Scratch的翻译，
Let me go ahead and per the translation of Scratch earlier,
让我做类似字符串的回答，等于get_string（“你叫什么名字？”）。
let me do something like string answer equals get_string("What's your name?").
因此，我实际上是在键入我们刚才在C中看到的内容。
So I'm literally typing out what we saw in C a moment ago.
我要记住我在这里的分号。
I'm going to remember my semicolon over here.
然后，我现在必须更改第二行代码，不要打招呼，
And then I have to change this second line of code now to not say hello,
世界，而是向％s打个招呼。
world, but instead to say hello, %s.
然后，在双引号之外，我要用逗号
And then, outside of the double quotes, I'm going to do a comma
然后从字面上提供答案一词，
and then provide literally the word answer, which
是该变量的名称。
is the name of that variable.
但是我还没有完成。
But I'm not quite done.
这有点微妙。
And this is a little subtle.
而且，在某些时候，你总是会忘记这一点。
And invariably, you'll forget this at some point, too.
为了使用get_string，我必须使用这个东西
In order to use get_string, I have to use this thing
称为CS50库，是工作人员编写的代码
called the CS50 library, code that the staff wrote
你没有默认访问权限。
that you don't have default access to.
为了做到这一点，我需要添加一行代码
And in order to do that, I need to add one line of code
我们将稍作详细解释。
that we'll explain in more detail in a little bit.
但就目前而言，只需相信通过添加以下代码行即可
But for now, just take it on faith that by adding this line of code
在最顶部，包括CS50.h，现在
at the very top, include CS50.h, that will now
允许我访问get_string函数，否则
give me access to the get_string function, which I otherwise
将无法访问。
wouldn't have access to.
好吧，现在我要回到终端窗口。
All right, now I'm going to go back to the terminal window.
并注意这里的二分法。
And notice the dichotomy here.
如果我只是运行./hello，那会很热情
If I just run ./hello, sort of enthusiastically,
让我们看看我的新程序做什么。
let's see what my new program does.
不幸的是，我将感到失望。
I'm about to be, unfortunately, disappointed.
因为它仍然向世界问好。
Because it still says hello, world.
你可能会直观地意识到问题所在，
And you might realize intuitively what the problem, of course,
这是我实际上尚未重新编译为代码的地方。
here is I haven't actually recompiled to the code.
因此，每当你更改代码时，
And so any time you make a change to your code,
仅通过文件保存或控制来保存文件是不够的
it does not suffice to just save the file via file save or Control
或Command-s，我需要重新编译。
or Command-s, I need to recompile it.
并重新编译我的代码，没什么大不了的。
And to recompile my code, that's not such a big deal.
我只输入make hello，输入。
I just type make hello, enter.
用手指交叉，没有黄色或红色的恐怖文字。
Cross my fingers that there's no yellow or red scary text.
一切都很好。
This is all good.
看来已经编译成机器码了。
It seems to have compiled into machine code.
现在，我可以重新输入./hello。
Now I can retype ./hello.
然后输入
and enter.
你会看到我的程序正在运行并在等我。
And you'll see now my program is running and waiting for me.
让我继续输入我的名字，大卫打招呼，大卫。
Let me go ahead and type my name, David enter hello, David.
让我继续并在清除屏幕后再次运行它。
Let me go ahead and run it again after clearing the screen.
让我再运行一次。
Let me run it again.
这次，我叫布莱恩。
And this time, let's say my name is Brian.
我问好，布莱恩。
And I say hello, Brian.
与我们在Scratch中所做的非常相似，
So quite similar to what we did in Scratch,
但是到目前为止，到目前为止，我们仅通过键盘就可以更有效地完成所有操作。
but now we're more powerfully doing this all thus far via my keyboard alone.
好吧，所以很多。
All right, so that was a lot.
我们打了招呼，世界超级快离开了我的记忆
We wrote hello, world super quickly off the top of my memory
然后对其进行了增强，现在可以接受用户的输入了。
and then enhanced it to now take input from the user.
让我在这里暂停。
Let me pause here.
如有任何疑问，欢迎你提问
If there are any questions, you're welcome to ask
通过聊天让员工或同学回答。
via chat for either staff or classmates to answer.
但是，如果你想在Zoom中举起虚拟手，
But if you'd like to raise your virtual hand in Zoom,
请随意，以便我可以在此处澄清或说明任何内容。
please feel free so that I can clarify or expound on anything here.
是的，Ryan有问题吗？
Yeah, question from Ryan?
听众：我在聊天中问过这个问题。
AUDIENCE: I had asked this in the chat.
但是答案之前的字符串不是变量的名称。
But so the string before the answer, that's not the name of the variable.
因此，假设你可以使它像字符串A或其他任何字符串。
So hypothetically, you could make it, like, string A or string anything else.
字符串名称后面紧跟着什么是重要的？
It just matters what comes after string is the name of the variable?
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的。
DAVID MALAN: Exactly.
真的很好的问题。
Really good question.
在Scratch的世界中，你需要
In the world of Scratch, you were required
使用称为“答案”的变量。
to use the variable called "answer."
在C语言中，我们可以完全灵活地完成自己想做的事情。
In C, we have the complete flexibility over what we want to do.
因此，正如瑞安（Ryan）提议的那样，我可以将变量的名称简称为A。
So as Ryan proposed, I could change my variable's name to just A for short.
我也必须在其他地方更改它，
I would have to change it elsewhere, too,
明确说明正在使用的变量
to make clear that the variable being used
是同一个，只是名字不同。
is the same one by a different name.
很好
That's perfectly fine.
但是，这是我们现在要讨论的一种更好的样式的地方。
But here's where we now get into a matter of better style.
拥有一个仅称为A的变量，它实际上并不适合自己
Having a variable called just A, it doesn't really lend itself
代码的可读性。
to the readability of your code.
我现在可以浏览一下我的代码，就像
I might now glance at my code and be, like,
变量A是什么？
what is the variable A. It's a little better when
编写好的代码实际上更加冗长
it comes to writing good code to actually be more verbose
在这种情况下，请使用“ answer”之类的实际字词。
and using an actual word like "answer" in this case.
确实，即使我一直将x和y和z描述为
Indeed, even though I keep describing x and y and z as the go
数学家的变量，那些真的
to variables for a mathematician, those really
在笛卡尔平面的上下文之外什么也没说。
say nothing outside the context of a Cartesian plane.
因此，在用C或Scratch或其他方式编写的程序中，
So in a program that you write in C or Scratch or anything else,
使用描述性变量名也是一个好习惯。
using descriptive variable names is a matter of good style as well.
乔纳森，交给你。
Jonathan, over to you.
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
只是一个简单的问题。
Just a quick question.
我们为什么必须每次都编译代码？
How come we have to compile the code every single time?
与不同的IDE不同，如果你只运行代码，
And unlike different IDEs, which if you just run the code,
它会自动编译。
it automatically compiles.
为什么我们必须手动执行此操作？
Why do we have to manually do it?
戴维·马兰：是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah.
真的很好的问题。
Really good question.
为什么你必须继续重新编译代码？
Why do you have to keep recompiling the code?
简短的答案仅仅是因为这就是C的方式。
The short answer is just because this is the way C is.
这是一种较古老的语言，至今已有数十年历史了。
It's an older language, decades now old.
因此，那时一切都非常有意。
And so back then, everything was very deliberate.
用户界面不是最重要的。
User interface was not the top priority.
例如，性能是这样。
Performance instead was, for instance.
因此，如今，出现了更高级的集成开发环境。
And so nowadays, there are fancier integrated development environments.
你们当中有些人可能已经使用了在线代码学院（codecademy）或co.org等工具，
And some of you might have used things like codecademy online, or co.org,
实际上，通常会有一个播放按钮
where there's very often literally a play button that you can just
在用户界面中单击，它将只播放你的程序
click in the user interface, and it just plays your program
或运行你的程序。
or runs your program.
我们在这堂课上正在向你展示
What we're doing in this class is showing you
这些按钮在做什么。
what those buttons are doing.
因此，如果你确实在这样的环境中使用，似乎可以实现此目的，
So if you do use in an environment like that that seems to automate this,
它仍在发生。
it's still happening.
但是出于我们的目的，当然是在学期开始时，
But for our purposes, certainly at the beginning of the semester,
我们将自己手动进行。
we're going to do it manually ourselves.
在学期末，当我们完全引入另一种语言时，
Later in the term, when we introduce a different language altogether,
例如，Python，然后有点像你
for instance, Python, then kind of, sort of you
不再需要编译了，但是在接下来的几周内会进行更多的编译。
don't need to compile anymore, but more on that in a few weeks.
好问题。
Good question.
索菲亚？
Sophia?
交给你。
Over to you.
听众：我有一个问题-
AUDIENCE: I had a question about--
我在源代码中注意到
I noticed in the source code that there's
字符串末尾的反斜杠（如n）。
a backslash like n at the end of the string.
即使只是一行，每次都需要吗？
Is that necessary for every time, even if it's just one line?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
你在其他地方看到的反斜杠n有点令人讨厌。
This backslash n that you're seeing elsewhere, a bit of a spoiler.
但是，是的，让我们继续解决我们已经看到的这个问题，
But yeah, let's go ahead and fix this problem that we've seen,
即使我有点无视。
even though I'm kind of ignoring it.
你知道，现在有一点特别之处。
You know, this now gets a little particular.
但是，老实说，这看起来有点愚蠢。
But this looks kind of stupid, honestly.
它打招呼，Brian tilde斜杠美元符号。
It says hello, Brian tilde slash dollar sign.
就像，那不是我想要的输出。
Like, that is not my intended output.
我只是想打个招呼，布莱恩，或者打招呼，大卫。
I literally only wanted to say hello, Brian, or hello, David.
这里的视觉伪像，美元符号，代字号和斜线
This visual artifact here, the dollar sign and the tilde and the slash
与我的终端窗口有关，此命令行环境
have to do with my terminal window, this command line environment
我正在使用。
that I'm using.
老实说，只是有点挑剔，
And honestly, just to be a little nitpicky,
坦白说，它可能应该换上新的一行。
frankly, it should probably be on a new line.
它应该只是在自己的行上，所以不要与我自己的输出混淆。
It should just be on its own line so it's not confused with my own output.
正如索菲（Sophie）所指出的，对此有一个解决方案。
And as Sophie notes, there is a solution to this.
但是，同样，每隔一周，你需要在编写算法时
But, again, per last week, you need to m when writing algorithms
反过来，代码也必须非常精确。
and in turn, code, you have to be super precise.
我没有在代码中告诉计算机
Nowhere in my code have I told the computer
将光标移动到下一行。
to move the cursor to the next line.
因此，我可以通过在％s之后立即执行反斜杠n来明确地执行此操作
So I can do that explicitly by doing backslash n immediately after the %s
但仍在双引号内。
but still inside of the double quotes.
这是告诉计算机的简写形式，
This is shorthand notation for what would be telling the computer,
将光标移动到下一行。
move the cursor to the next line.
现在你可能会认为，好吧，为什么我不像这样按Enter键？
Now you might think that, well, why don't I just hit Enter like this?
即使这对我们大多数人来说都是新事物，只要说
And even though this is all might be new to most of us, suffice it to say
感觉就像很快就会变得混乱。
this just feels like it's going to get messy quickly.
如果你在代码中间点击Enter键，
If you start hitting Enter in the middle of your code,
那可能不是正确的解决方案。
that's probably not the right solution.
因此，程序员几年前决定
So instead, programmers years ago decided
提出反斜杠n之类的速记符号，否则称为
to come up with shorthand notation like backslash n, otherwise known
作为向计算机发出信号的转义字符，请在此处添加新行。
as an escape character that signals to the computer, put a new line here.
所以反斜杠n是换行符。
So backslash n is new line.
让我继续进行重新编译。
And let me go ahead and recompile this.
保存文件后，让我继续打个招呼。
After saving my file, let me go ahead and do make hello.
看来编译OK了。 。/你好。
It seems to compile OK. ./hello.
让我继续输入Brian的名字。
And let me go ahead and type in Brian's name again.
瞧，输出还是一样，但是有点干净。
And voila, still the same output, but it's a little cleaner.
因此，我们现在在管家方面要好一些。
So we're being a little bit better about housekeeping now.
真的很好的问题。
Really good question.
是BJ吗？
BJ is it?
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yes.
所以我有一个问题是为什么你没有
So one question I had is why don't you have
调用函数get string以便你请求输入？
to call the function get string in order for you for it to ask for input?
就像，当你将输入分配给变量答案时，它仍然会询问你的输入。
Like, it still asked your input when you assigned it to the variable answer.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：啊，这是一个很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Ah, really good question.
例如，为什么我不必调用get字符串，
Why don't I have to call get string, for instance,
通过自己放置一条线？
by putting it on a line of its own?
C和许多编程语言的工作方式是
The way that C and a lot of programming languages work is they
例如，将评估整行代码，
will evaluate an entire line of code, for instance,
至少在这种情况下，我在第6行从右到左的位置。
what I have here on line six from right to left, at least in this context.
当你像我在此处那样在代码中使用等号时，
When you have an equal sign in the code like I do here,
告诉你首先要执行的计算机，
that's telling the computer you first have to execute,
就是按照右边所说的去做。
that is do what is said on the right-hand side.
然后不管那个东西的输出是什么，
And then whatever the output of that thing is,
将其存储在左侧。
store it on the left-hand side.
所以它确实正在执行，我们现在正在散布一些东西
So it is indeed getting executed, we're just now spreading things out
如果可以的话，可以在更长的代码行上这样做。
on longer lines of code, if you will, if that makes sense.
所以get字符串正在执行，因为它出现在该行上。
So get string is getting executed because it appears on that line.
好的。
All right.
坦率地说，我们一直认为是理所当然的，
So we've been taking for granted, frankly,
这些程序的一些细节可能是
a few details of these programs that it's probably
公平地开始开玩笑。
only fair to start teasing apart.
例如，有int，main，void，
For instance, there was that int, main, void,
以及其他许多语法
and a whole bunch of other syntax.
因此，让我们来梳理一下其他一些代码行
So let's tease apart some of these other lines of code
我只是从记忆中敲出了我的头顶，但是有点
that I just typed off the top of my head from memory, but kind of do
需要在你编写的每个C程序中都存在。
need to be there in every C program you write.
让我们至少开始理解其中的一些细节。
Let's at least start to make sense of some of that detail.
回想一下，在Scratch中，我们一开始总是启动我们的程序
Recall that in Scratch, we always started our programs initially
单击绿色标志时。
with when green flag clicked.
最终，我们看到了其他拼图碎片，例如当你听到某个事件时，
We eventually saw some other puzzle pieces, like when you hear an event,
或摄像机运动时。
or when there's camera motion.
但这确实开始了我们在Scratch中编写的大多数程序。
But this really kick started most of the programs that we wrote in Scratch.
绿旗单击拼图时的C中的类似物是什么？
What is the analog in C of the when green flag clicked puzzle piece?
本质上就是这个。
It's essentially this.
今天我们将不花时间详细解释
We won't spend time in detail today explaining
为什么是int，为什么是void，为什么有花括号，为什么有括号。
why it's int, why it's void, why there's curly braces, why there's parentheses.
仅出于今天的目的，让我规定
For today's purposes only, let me just stipulate
这是绿色标记单击拼图时的模拟结果。
that this is the analog for this when green flag clicked puzzle piece.
你刚开始要启动程序
You've just got to start your programs initially
可以这么说。
with this kind of boilerplate code, so to speak.
我们将开始更详细地解释这一点。
We will start to explain this in much more detail.
但就目前而言，只要相信这一点
But for now, just take on faith that this
是你开始编写程序的方式。
is how you start writing a program.
但是，到目前为止，我们当然已经编写了一些程序。
But there's, of course, a little more to the programs we've written thus far.
特别是，我们已经看到了称为标头文件的两件事。
And particularly, we've seen a couple of things called header files.
这是另一个艺术术语，指的是用该语言编写的文件
This is another term of art that refers to a file written in the language
名为C，名称的后缀不是.c，而是.h。
called C whose name ends with not .c, but with .h.
因此，我们之前已经看到了以下内容。
So we've seen these before as follows.
回想一下，这是我们上周在Scratch中编写的最简单的程序。
Here, recall, was the simplest program we wrote last week in Scratch.
当你单击绿色标志时，它只是打个招呼，世界。
It just says hello, world when you clicked on the green flag.
这是模拟，右侧是更完整的模拟，
This is the analog, the more complete analog on the right,
该程序的今天。
of that program today.
但是有一些缺失。
But there's something missing.
而且可能在你们当中有些人跳出来了，
And it's probably jumping out at some of you,
因为该程序比以前短了一点。
because the program is a little shorter than it was before.
缺少的东西，这是这里的线。
Something's missing, which is this line here.
我刚才是从内存中写出来的，但是它指的是一个文件
And I just wrote that from memory earlier, but it's referring to a file
称为stdio.h，代表标准输入输出点h。
called stdio.h, which stands for standard input output dot h.
io是计算机世界的首字母缩写
So io is an acronym in the computer world
通常只是指输入和输出。
that just generally refers to input and output.
因此标准io.h只是一个非常流行的文件
So standard io.h is just a very popular file
在C程序中使用的功能
that is used in C programs that gives you the ability
从用户那里获取输入和输出。
to get input and output from the user.
它通过为你提供printf来实现，
And it does so by providing you with printf,
例如，哪个当然可以让你
for instance, which of course, allows you
通过这些副作用产生某种形式的输出
to generate some form of output via those side effects
我们之前介绍过的
that we described earlier.
但是当我编写其他程序时，回想一下，
But when I wrote my other program, recall,
正如BJ先前指出的那样，实际上得到了字符串，
that actually had get string, as BJ noted earlier,
我可以从用户那里获得一行文字，
where I can get a line of text from the user,
我完全需要其他东西。
I needed something else altogether.
刚才我们添加了第二个头文件CS50.h。
And that's when we added, a moment ago, a second header file called CS50.h.
因此，这些头文件仅使你可以访问更多功能
So these header files just give you access to more functions
比你可能会自动从使用的语言中得到的，
than you might automatically get from the language you're using,
这是C。
which here is C.
精神上很相似，上周回想一下，
It's similar in spirit, recall last week,
当我开始在Scratch的扩展菜单中随意拨弄时
when I started poking around Scratch's extension menu
我使用了翻译块和语音块，
and I used the translate block and the voice block,
扩展菜单下隐藏的一种更高级的功能。
the sort of fancier features that were buried under the extensions menu.
在Scratch中使用扩展名类似于在C中使用头文件。
Using an extension in Scratch is similar to using a header file in C.
它使我可以使用比你以前获得的功能更多的功能
It's giving me access to a bit more functionality than you otherwise get
可以说是免费的。
for free out of the box, so to speak.
好吧，让我继续提出
All right, well, let me go ahead and propose
我有很多不同的方式
that there are so many different ways in which I
在编写这些程序的过去几分钟中可能搞砸了。
could have screwed up over the past few minutes of writing these programs.
正如我暗示的那样，我可能省略了分号。
I might have omitted a semicolon, as I implied.
我可能没有关闭报价。
I might have not closed my quotes.
我可能把括号弄错了。
I might have gotten my parentheses wrong.
我可能完全拼错了单词。
I might have misspelled words altogether.
我有很多方法可以搞砸该程序。
There's many different ways I could have screwed that program up.
坦率地说，从记录上来说，我有点像我没拧螺丝一样
And frankly, off the record, I'm sort of crossing my fingers that I didn't screw
一起建立我们的第一个程序。
up our very first program together.
但总是在某个时候，也许不是你的第一个程序，
But invariably, at some point, maybe not your first program,
但是在学习如何编程或学习如何用C编程的早期，
but early on in learning how to program or learning how to program in C,
你会搞砸的。
you will screw up.
而且你将要打错字。
And you're going to make some typo.
你的理解之间会有一些脱节
There's going to be some disconnect between what your understanding is
以及你要让计算机执行的操作。
and what you're trying to get the computer to do.
这就是说，有一些工具，谢天谢地，
And this is to say there are tools, thankfully,
可以帮助你解决这些问题。
that can help you solve those problems.
其中第一个称为help50。
And the first of which is called help50.
名称以50结尾的任何工具都是专门为
Any of the tools whose names end with 50 are specifically
由CS50员工撰写的面向教育的临时培训
educationally oriented, written by CS50 staff, that are temporary training
我们上课的前几个星期要使用的轮子
wheels that we'll use for the first several weeks of the class
但最终，可选地，从某种意义上讲
but then eventually, optionally, take away in the sense
你将不再需要它们。
that you won't need them anymore.
所以help50是一个正在执行的命令
And so help50 is one command that's going
使你可以解决你可能无法解决的问题
to allow you to troubleshoot problems that you might not otherwise
显然可以在你自己的代码中看到。
see obviously in your own code.
让我去模拟如下。
And let me go and simulate this as follows.
让我回到我们的第一个程序
Let me go back to the very first program that we
用C编写，这很简单，它只说了一个世界。
wrote in C, which was quite simply this one whereby it only said hello, world.
我可能在这里有几个不同的地方。
And there's a few different places I could have screwed up here.
例如，假设我有点超前
For instance, suppose I was getting a little ahead of myself
我在程序顶部承认了标准的io.h文件。
and I admitted the standard io.h file at the top of my program.
意思是现在我的电脑不
The implication is that now my computer is not
将要知道什么是printf，因为标准io.h中并未包含它。
going to know what printf is, because it hasn't been included via standard io.h.
因此，让我们看看错误消息是什么。
So let's see what the error message is.
希望这将是一个非常不言自明的信息
Hopefully, it'll be a very self-explanatory message
完全有道理。
that makes perfect sense.
让我继续重新编译该程序，
Let me go ahead and recompile this program,
知道它已经不正确了。
knowing it already to be incorrect.
哦，天哪。
And oh, my God.
就像，我的错误行多于实际的代码行。
Like, I have more lines of errors than I actually have lines of code.
这是编程的现实。
And this is kind of a reality of programming.
很多编程语言，很多工具，
A lot of programming languages, a lot of tools,
坦率地说，在设计时并没有考虑到易用性，
frankly, were not designed with ease of use in mind,
或用户友好的想法。
or user-friendliness in mind.
他们在设计时确实考虑了简洁性和精确性。
They were really designed with succinctness and precision in mind.
不幸的是，他们倾向于假设观众是
And they tend, unfortunately, to assume that the audience is
和编写程序的人一样技术。
as technical as the person who wrote the program.
当然，这可能会适得其反，当你只是学习如何
This, of course, can backfire when you're just learning how
首先编程
to program in the first place, and you have
这样可以理解疯狂的神秘输出。
to make sense of crazy cryptic output like this.
今天，我们不必专注于每个单词
Today we don't have to focus on every single word that's
在屏幕上输出，但让我们开始识别模式。
been outputted on the screen, but let's start to recognize patterns.
走进新的空间并认识到
Walking into a new space and just recognizing
物理世界中熟悉的对象，让我们现在用代码来完成。
familiar objects in the physical world, let's now do that with code.
也许最重要的是要注意的是，当你搞砸时
The most important thing, perhaps, to take notice of is that when you mess up
并且你在代码中犯了一些错误，以致你的程序甚至无法
and you make some mistake in your code such that your program doesn't even
从源代码编译成机器代码，
compile from source code into machine code,
很有可能你会看到错误输出顶部的线索
odds are you're going to see a clue toward the top of the erroneous output
告诉你混乱的文件名
that tells you the name of the file where you messed up
以及你搞砸的行号。
and the line number where you messed up.
三个代表第三行，然后五个可能
Three implying line three, and then five might
暗示该行中的哪一列或什么字符，
imply what column or what character in that line,
但这是否有用取决于特定的问题。
but it depends on the particular problem if that's that useful.
所以在第三行，我得到一个错误，隐式声明了库函数
So on line three, I am getting an error, implicitly declaring library function
类型为int const char star的printf。
printf with type int const char star.
我的意思是，像谁知道那意味着什么？
I mean, like, who knows what that even means?
你最终会。
You will eventually.
但是就今天而言，这仅意味着出了一些问题。
But for today, it just means something bad went wrong.
而且你可能看不到它。
And you might not see it.
你可能不知道，如果我没有告诉你，
You might not know, if I hadn't told you,
我故意删除了这一行。
that I intentionally deleted that line.
因此，让我们看看使用此工具是否无法理解这一点。
So let's see if we can't make sense of this by using this tool.
Help50是CS50员工编写的工具，
Help50 is a tool written by CS50 staff that
将有助于翻译奥术秘密计算机
will help translate arcane cryptic computer
传达给更多人性化建议和问题的消息
messages to more human friendly advice and questions
你的教学研究员或助教可能会为你提供帮助，
that you're teaching fellow or teaching assistant might offer you,
例如，在办公时间范围内。
say, in the context of office hours.
因此要使用help50，而不是一次又一次地运行相同的命令
So to use help50, instead of running the same command again and again
并看到相同的错误输出，字面上恰好是正确的帮助50
and seeing the same erroneous output, literally just right help50
首先，在你的终端窗口中，然后编写相同的确切命令
first, at your terminal window, then write the same exact command
你出于任何原因而苦苦挣扎，然后按Enter。
that you're struggling with for whatever reason, and hit Enter then.
将会发生的是将运行同一命令。
And what will happen is the same command will get run.
我们将使用help50程序分析该输出是什么。
We will analyze, using the help50 program, what that output is.
我们将尝试以黄色突出显示我们所识别的内容。
And we'll try to highlight in yellow the stuff we recognize.
然后将其翻译为更人性化的语言。
And then translate it to more human friendly language.
例如，在运行help50之后，我们要求获得帮助，点对点。
For instance, after running help50, we're asking for help, dot dot dot.
这是黄色，这是我们认识的东西，
In yellow here is the thing we recognize,
哦，工作人员以前见过这个问题。
oh, the staff have seen this problem before.
然后在这里，你是否忘了包含stdio.h，其中printf
And then down here, did you forget to include stdio.h, in which printf
被声明为文件的顶部？
is declared atop of your file?
所以希望，如果我们认识到这个问题，
So hopefully, if we recognize the problem,
我们可以指导你解决这种反问
we can guide you with this sort of rhetorical question
这使你意识到，哦，是的。
that makes you realize, oh, yes.
那是我做错的事。
That's what I did wrong.
现在，我可以回到这里，移至文件顶部，
So now I can go back up here, move to the top of my file,
并添加include stdio.h。
and add include stdio.h.
现在注意，如果我重新打个招呼，瞧，问题就完全消失了。
And now notice, if I rerun make hello, voila, the problem is gone altogether.
我们可以整天这样做。
And we could do this all day long.
有很多地方要弄乱。
There's so many places to mess up.
例如，我现在省略分号。
For instance, I omit the semicolon now.
让我继续，不用分号立即打个招呼。
Let me go ahead and make hello now without the semicolon.
现在，我们将获得不同的错误消息。
Now we're going to get a different error message.
你会再次看到我搞砸的文件名hello.c。
And you'll see, again, the name of the file where I messed up, hello.c.
这次是在第五行。
This time it's on line five.
这是真的，因为行号向下移动
And that's true because the line numbers moved down
在我在那里添加更多东西之后。
after I added more stuff up there.
你可以在表达后看到预期的分号。
And you can see expected semicolon after expression.
所以这有点简单。
So this one's a little more straightforward.
但是你可以在此命令上运行help50，
But you could run help50 on this command,
同样，只是为了获得一些更明确的建议。
too, just to get back a little more explicit advice.
所以help50随时会成为你的朋友
So help50 will be your friend any time you
使你的代码无法实际编译时遇到了麻烦。
are having trouble getting your code to actually compile.
好吧，让我现在做其他不好的事情。
Well, let me do something else that's bad now.
我一直在刻意编写相当漂亮的代码。
I've very deliberately been writing fairly pretty code.
我已经缩进了printf这个词。
I've indented the word printf.
我在这里包括一些空白行。
I included some blank line up here.
为了清楚起见，我放了这些花括号，
Just to make it clear, I've put these curly braces,
可以这么说。
so to speak, on their own lines.
但是坦率地说，我的计算机或CS50 IDE并不是那么特别。
But frankly, my computer, or CS50 IDE is not so particular.
从技术上讲，我可以摆脱这一空白行。
I could technically get rid of this blank line.
我可以将花括号移到这里。
I could move this curly brace way up here.
我可以完全摆脱这种压痕，并按自己的方式移动它。
I could get rid of this indentation altogether and move it on its own line.
然后我可以将花括号移到这里。
And then I could just move this curly brace up here.
因此，编写的程序现在只有两行，而不是六行。
Thereby writing a program that's now only two lines long, not six.
但希望已经，即使你以前从未编程过，
But hopefully already, even if you've never programmed before,
这可能应该以错误的方式摩擦你。
this should probably rub you the wrong way.
就像现实世界中的人一样
This is like people in the real world that
不要在他们的社交媒体帖子中使用标点符号
don't use punctuation in their social media posts
或他们的电子邮件或短信。
or their emails or the text messages.
他们只是不断地进行下去。
They just kind of go on and on and on.
是的，信息在那里。
And yes, the information is there.
你可以收集他们正在尝试交流的内容。
You can glean what it is they're trying to communicate.
但是，天哪，这很烦人。
But my God, is it annoying.
很难读。
It's hard to read.
发生错误的可能性更高
There's probably a higher probability that there's a mistake
而且很难找到它，因为事情没有很好地平衡
and it's going to be harder to find it because things aren't nicely balanced
在左侧，右侧，顶部和底部。
on the left and on the right and on the top and the bottom.
因此，这就是糟糕的风格。
So this is what would be described as bad style.
我的程序仍然正确。
My program is still correct.
我有stdio.h，我有分号，以及其他所有内容。
I've got the stdio.h, I've got the semicolon, and everything else.
但这真的很糟糕。
But it's really bad style.
因为这很丑。
Because it's just ugly.
没有太多的空白。
There's not much white space.
没有很多空白行或缩进
There's not a lot of blank lines or indentation
这使你和我更容易从上到下阅读此内容。
that just make it easier for you and I to read this thing from top to bottom.
因此请注意，它确实可以编译。
So notice, it does compile.
所以help50不会帮助我解决此问题，因为它可以编译。
So help50 is not going to help me fix this problem because it compiles OK.
但是它可以运行另一个我们称为style50的程序。
But it can run another program that we're going to call style50.
这是另一种以教育为导向的工具
This is another educationally oriented tool
安装在CS50 IDE中，可以让你找出
that's installed in CS50 IDE that allows you to figure out
如何改善代码风格。
how to improve the style of your code.
因此，当我在此更漂亮的代码上运行style50时，它的确看起来不错。
So when I run style50 on this prettier code, it indeed looks good.
但是它仍然在给我建议。
But it's still giving me advice.
它告诉我添加一些称为“注释”的内容。
It's telling me to add something called comments.
一群人在Scratch的世界中发现了这一点。
And a bunch of you figured this out in the world of Scratch.
你可以添加一些便利贴或便利贴
You can add little sticky notes or post-it notes
刮擦那些自我的笔记
to Scratch that are sort of notes to self
会提醒你某事，或者向你的讲师解释
that remind you what something does, or maybe explains to your teaching fellow
或助教什么事情。
or teaching assistant what something does.
C也支持这些。
C supports these as well.
举例来说，如果我只是想在这里做个学究的人，
So for instance, if I just wanted to be really pedantic here and make
清楚人类正在阅读我的代码，我正在尝试做的事情，
clear to the human reading my code what I'm trying to do,
我可以说一些问候用户的话。
I could say something like greet user.
并注意此处的语法。
And notice the syntax here.
我在现有代码行的上方添加了新行，
I've put a new line above my existing line of code,
而且我已经缩进了，所以一切都排队了
and I've similarly indented it so everything lines up
外观精美。
visually beautifully.
我已经完成了斜杠斜杠，说，嘿，编译器，这是一条评论。
I've done slash slash, which says, hey, compiler, this is a comment.
这仅适用于人眼。
This is for human eyes only.
本质上，这不是实际的C代码。
This is not actual C code, per se.
然后我按空格键。
Then I hit the spacebar.
然后我只输入了一个英语短语。
And then I just typed out an English phrase.
这可以是任何口头语言。
And this could be any spoken language.
但是我继续打招呼用户。
But I went ahead and typed greet user.
为什么？
Why?
好吧，这只是在提醒我自己
Well, it's just a reminder to myself what
以下代码行的目的是向用户致意。
the purpose of the following line of code is, to greet the user.
例如，这比打个招呼世界更好。
This is marginally better, for instance, than saying print hello, world.
让我问你，即使你从来没有
And let me just ask you, even if you've never
为什么在第一个评论更好之前编程
programmed before why is the first comment a better
比第二个评论好吗？
comment than the second?
就像，为什么我要说（如果有的话）向用户打招呼而不是打印
Like, why should I say, if anything, greet user instead of print
你好，世界以这些评论的形式出现。
hello, world in the form of these comments.
是的，Olivia，你如何看待？
Yeah, Olivia, what do you think?
听众：好的。
AUDIENCE: OK.
它告诉你代码的目的。
It tells you the purpose of the code.
DAVID MALAN：是的，代码的目的是什么？
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, the purpose of the code as opposed to what?
你在区分什么？
What distinction are you making?
听众：准确地告诉你它在做什么。
AUDIENCE: Versus telling you exactly what it's doing.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的，是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, exactly.
如果你的注释与实际代码几乎相同，
If your comment is almost identical to the actual code,
你并没有真正向读者传达更多的信息，更不用说了
you're not really conveying much more information to the reader, let alone
将来自己。
yourself in the future.
更概括地说，这行代码的目的是做什么，
Explaining it more generally, what the purpose of this line of code is to do,
是向用户打招呼，这更具描述性。
is to greet the user, that's a little more descriptive.
老实说，现在这个程序超级公平
Now to be super fair, honestly, this program
太短了，即使style50是的，
is so short that even though style50, yes, would
宁愿你添加一些注释，如果你的程序确实
prefer that you add some comment, if your program really
简化为一行代码，你可能不需要在此处添加注释。
reduces to one line of code, you probably don't need a comment here.
但是，几乎所有其他程序
However, pretty much every other program we're
以后要在这里写的不只是一个
going to write here on after is going to be more than just one
主代码行，例如此printf。
main line of code, like this printf.
所以很快就会有意义
So it's going to make much more sense soon
来，我们将要实际添加
to come that we're going to want to actually add
给我们的代码一些实际的注释。
to our code some actual comments.
好吧，让我在这里介绍一个最后的工具
Well, let me introduce one final tool here
这将有助于我们解决目前的问题
that will help us solve problems as we proceed now
编写更复杂的程序。
to write more sophisticated programs.
这是check50。
And this is check50.
该工具专门用于实验室或问题集中，
This is a tool specifically that you'll use either in labs or in problem sets,
该课程的编程作业，以实际检查
the course's programming assignments, to actually check
你代码的正确性。
the correctness of your code.
因此，尽管help50只能帮助你通常地编译代码，
So whereas help50 just helps you compile your code typically,
当根本不编译时，style50会有所帮助
when it's not compiling at all, style50 helps
你改善了代码风格，请检查50
you improve the style of your code, check50
会对照一些自动化测试来检查代码的正确性
will check the correctness of your code against some automated tests
我们员工写的与任何东西都一致的
that we, the staff, have written that are consistent with whatever
作业问题实际上是。
the homework problem actually is.
因此，我们编写了一些测试以确保你的代码正常运行
So we write some tests to make sure that your code is working correctly
根据我们自己的规格。
as per our own specifications.
那么我应该如何运行check50？
So how might I run check50?
这将完全取决于问题集或实验室。
This will totally depend on the problem set or the lab.
而且，我们将始终在问题集或实验中，
And we will always, in the problem set or lab,
告诉你键入哪个命令以进行check50。
tell you what command to type for check50.
你不一定要自己弄清楚这件事。
It's not something you could necessarily figure out on your own.
我碰巧记得我们有一张支票，
I happen to remember that we have a check, that
是一项测试，称为CS50 /问题/你好。
is a test, called CS50/problems/hello.
奇怪的是你将永远不会运行相同的命令。
Odds are you will never run this identical command.
同样，在问题集或实验中，我们将始终告诉你键入什么。
Again, in the problem set or lab, we will always tell you what to type.
除非我们告诉你要使用哪种测试，否则你将不知道要键入什么内容。
You won't know what otherwise to type unless we tell you what test to use.
这将现在将我的文件hello.c上载到名为
This is going to now upload my file hello.c to a service called
GitHub，再次是共享代码的流行工具。
GitHub, which again is a popular tool for sharing code.
我们使用它来收集提交的信息。
We use it to collect submissions for this.
然后输入密码。
I'm going to then type in my password.
你不会看到它。
You won't see it.
相反，你会在网页中看到星号或项目符号。
You'll instead see asterisks or, like, bullets in a web page.
我要继续，然后按Enter。
I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter then.
这将验证我的代码。
It's going to verify my code.
它会做一些思考。
It's going to do some thinking.
现在正在上传，点对点。
It's uploading now, dot dot dot.
现在，我们只是在等待互联网做出回应。
And now we're just waiting for the internet to respond.
因为在CS50服务器上的某个地方，
Because somewhere on CS50 servers, we are
在编译代码后运行代码，在本例中为我的代码，
running your code after compiling your code, or in this case mine,
并确保是的，它的实际行为应有的表现。
and making sure, yes, it actually behaved as it should have.
希望你通常会看到一堆绿色的笑脸
And what you'll typically see, hopefully, are a bunch of green smiley
面对的是，你的代码存在，是的，你的代码可以编译，
faces saying yes, that your code exists, yes, that your code compiles,
是的，例如，它可以打印世界。
and yes, for instance, it prints hello, world.
有时你可能会看到红色的皱眉面孔，
Sometimes you might see red frowny faces,
这表示不可以，根据实验，你的代码无法正常运行
which means no, your code did not work exactly as it should, per the lab,
或问题集。
or of the problem set.
在这一点上，它回到你所需要的绘图板上
At which point, it's back to the drawing board on your part to figure out
到底需要在这里修复什么。
exactly what needs to be fixed up here.
有时你会看到黄色的输出，只是一张黄色的笔直的脸
Sometimes you'll see yellow output with just a straight yellow face, which
只是意味着我们甚至无法运行特定测试
just means we weren't even able to run a certain test
因为其他一些测试已经失败。
because some other test already failed.
所以它是相对快速的反馈
So it's meant to be relatively quick feedback
甚至在提交并称呼它之前，先检查代码的正确性。
on the correctness of your code before you even submit it and call it a day.
而check50指令将始终伴随着问题本身
And check50 instructions will always be accompanied by the problem itself
在实验室或问题集中。
in the lab or problem set.
因此，这里有一些最终命令。
So some final commands here now.
在此终端窗口中，我不仅可以运行make和./hello，还可以做更多的事情，
Within this terminal window, I can do more than just run make and ./hello,
或我程序的名称是什么。
or whatever my program's name is.
我可以做的不只是help50和style50
And I can do more than help50 and style50
而Check50证明我确实以CS50 IDE的形式使用了
and Check50 it turns out that I'm really using, in the form of CS50 IDE,
我自己的服务器在云中。
my own server in the cloud.
是的，我正在使用一个网站。
So yes, I'm using a website.
但是CS50 IDE的真正含义是，就像你自己的服务器
But what CS50 IDE really is, it's like your own server
或你在云端的计算机。
or your own computer in the cloud.
在互联网上的某个地方，你拥有自己的用户名和密码
Somewhere out there on the internet, you have your own username and password
以CS50 IDE的形式。
in the form of CS50 IDE.
而且只有你可以访问你编写的文件，你所使用的程序
And only you can access the files that you write, the programs that you
写入存储在此IDE中的内容。
write that are stored in this IDE.
现在，我将吸引其他一些功能。
And there's a few more features I'll now draw our attention to.
也许最友好的一个是左上角的这个小文件夹图标。
Perhaps the most friendly one is this little folder icon at top left.
如果我单击此小文件夹图标，你将
If I click this little folder icon, you'll
现在查看通常称为文件浏览器的文件
now see what's generally called a file browser
或文件树，仅是图形表示
or a file tree, which is just a graphical representation
在这种情况下，我的帐户或IDE中文件的大小。
of the files in my account, or in my IDE, in this case.
它看起来类似于Mac OS。
It looks similar to Mac OS.
它看起来类似于Windows。
It looks similar to Windows.
这只是内置在IDE中的图形用户界面
And this is just a graphical user interface built into the IDE
这样，例如，如果我通过单击此x小按钮关闭我的标签
so that, for instance, if I close my tab by clicking this little x button up
在这里，我想重新打开文件，就像你一样
here, and I want to reopen the file, much like you
可以想象在Mac或PC上就这么简单
would imagine on a Mac or PC, it's as simple
双击左侧的文件。
as double clicking the file on the left-hand side.
但是请注意，我没有点击“ hello”。
But notice I didn't click on hello.
因为请注意会发生什么。
Because notice what happens.
如果我打招呼，我的天哪，这是怎么回事？
If I open hello, my gosh, like, what is going on here?
这真是一团糟。
This is kind of a mess.
有发红。
There's redness.
有圆点。
There's dots.
有人对我为什么要看到自己看到的东西有任何想法吗？
Any thoughts from someone on why I'm seeing what I'm seeing?
因为在某些时候，你很可能会偶然，
Because odds are you will, accidentally, at some point,
单击诸如hello的文件，而不是单击诸如hello.c的文件。
click on a file like hello instead of on a file like hello.c.
莎拉，你怎么看？
Sara, what do you think?
听众：这是一个二进制代码。
AUDIENCE: It's a binary code.
这就是机器语言。
So it's the machine language.
因此，除了他们用C编写的代码外，它不允许用户看到它们。
So it doesn't allow the user to see them, besides the code they write in C.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的，是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, exactly.
你试图在此选项卡中查看的是二进制代码0和1。
What you're trying to look at in this tab is binary code, 0's and 1's.
但是，从技术上讲，这些0和1是
However, those 0's and 1's are technically
目前被误解为ASCII字符，
being misinterpreted at the moment as ASCII characters,
或Unicode字符。
or Unicode characters.
因此回想一下上周，ASCII是数字和字母之间的映射。
So recall from last week, ASCII is this mapping between numbers and letters.
当然，数字只是0和1的模式。
And numbers, of course, are just patterns of 0's and 1's.
这看起来很神秘，因为我们试图误解0和
And this looks super cryptic, because we're trying to misinterpret 0's and
1代表它们是ASCII字符。
1's as though they're ASCII characters.
回想一下，还有更多的ASCII和Unicode字符
And recall that there's many more characters in ASCII and Unicode
而不是A到Z。还有数字，其中有一些无法打印的字符。
than A through Z. And the numbers, there's some unprintable characters.
确实，我们在这里看到的所有时髦之处
And indeed, all the funkiness we're seeing here
只是对0和1的误解
is just a misinterpretation of 0's and 1's that
是计算机的指令，计算机的机器代码是
are instructions to the computer, machine code for the computer being
被误解为文本。
misinterpreted as text.
因此，如果你无法编辑这样的二进制文件，可以这么说，
So if you can't edit a binary file like this, so to speak,
当你做这样的事情时，你应该关闭你好
you should just close hello when you do something like that
并确保你双击并打开了实际的源代码
and make sure you've double clicked on and opened your actual source code
文件。
file as well.
因此，我们已经看到了字符串。
So we've seen strings.
还有其他数据类型。
And there's other data types.
还有其他功能。
And there's other functions.
还有循环和条件等等。
And there's loops and conditions and so much more.
我认为我们现在是时候休息一下，让我们沉浸在一个好时机。
I think we're at a good point now to perhaps take a break, let this sink in.
我们为什么不继续休息七分钟呢？
Why don't we go ahead and take a seven minute break?
当我们继续时，我们将介绍C的其他一些功能
And when we resume, we'll introduce a few more features of C
并将它们与上周在Scratch中看到的进行比较。
and compare them against what we saw last week in Scratch.
所以我们七分钟后见。
So we'll see you in seven minutes.
好吧，我们回来了。
All right, we are back.
所以回想一下，我们是在看这个图形用户的
So recall where we left off was we were looking at this graphical user
界面在左上方。
interface at top left.
文件浏览器，即文件树，仅提供给我们更多图形访问
The file browser, the file tree, that just gives us more graphical access
到我们帐户中的文件。
to the files in our account.
但是，现在让我们在终端窗口中以老式的命令行方式进行操作。
But let's now do this the old school command line way in my terminal window.
事实证明，使用我们的终端窗口，
So it turns out that using our terminal window,
我们不仅可以编译代码并运行代码并运行check50样式，help50，
can we not only compile code and run code and run check50 style, help50,
等等，我们也可以操作文件
and the like, we can also manipulate files
和文件夹，甚至碰巧都存在于我的IDE中。
and folders, even, that happen to exist in my IDE.
那是我可以访问云中计算机的位置。
That is in the computer I have access to here in the cloud.
我建议的第一个命令是键入ls。
And the first command I've proposed is that we type ls.
Ls是list的简写形式。
Ls is shorthand notation for list.
很简单，ls列出了当前文件夹中的文件或文件夹。
And quite simply, ls lists the files or folders in your current folder.
因此，这就像双击Windows中的“我的文档”文件夹，
So this would be like double clicking on your My Documents folder in Windows,
或Mac OS中的文档。
or documents in Mac OS.
Ls仅列出内容。
Ls just lists the contents.
现在，你好，你好有点奇怪。
Now, notice hello is a little weird.
它以绿色突出显示，并且后面有一个星号。
It's highlighted in green and there's an asterisk after it.
这只是该文件可执行的视觉提示。
And that's just a visual cue that that file is executable.
也就是说，该程序可以与./hello一起运行。
That is, that is a program that you can run with ./hello.
星号不是文件名的一部分。
The star is not part of the file name.
当然，我们会看到hello.c。
And of course, we see hello.c.
现在，假设我想重命名我的文件。
Now, suppose that I wanted to maybe rename my file.
好吧，就像在Mac OS或Windows中一样，
Well, I could, much like in Mac OS or Windows,
我可以在这里浏览文件浏览器。
I could go up to the file browser up here.
我可以控制单击或右键单击。
I could Control click or Right click.
并注意有很多菜单选项
And notice there's a whole bunch of menu options
就像在你自己的计算机上一样弹出。
that pop up just like on your own computer.
我可以在此处重命名该文件。
And I could rename the file right up here.
但总的来说，我们将在命令行中执行操作
But generally speaking, we're going to do things at the command line
只是因为，像今天这样的一些行动简陋
only because, rudimentary as some of these operations today
是的，对我来说它将是一个功能更强大的命令行界面。
are, it's going to be a much more powerful command line interface for me.
因此，假设我改变主意，你知道吗？
So suppose I change my mind, and you know what?
我不喜欢这个版本的你好。
I don't like this version of hello.
我想删除该程序并重新开始。
I want to delete that program and start over.
严格来说，我不需要删除任何问候。
Strictly speaking, I don't need to delete hello ever.
我可以重新编译它，它会不断变化和变化。
I can just recompile it, and it will keep getting changed and changed.
但是，如果确实要删除它，则可以键入rm hello，然后按Enter。
But if I do want to remove it, I can type rm hello, and then hit Enter.
然后会问我，删除常规文件你好吗？
And then I'll be asked, remove regular file hello?
这只是我确实要删除的视觉确认。
That's just a visual confirmation that I do indeed want to delete.
我可以输入y或yes或类似的答复。
And I can type y or yes or some such reply.
如果我按y再按Enter，似乎什么也没发生，
And if I hit y and Enter, nothing seems to happen,
但请注意左上方的情况。
but notice what happened up here at top left.
请注意，hello现在不见了，只剩下hello.c。
Notice that hello is now gone, leaving only hello.c.
而且，如果我再次键入ls，现在我只会看到我的代码文件。
And if I type ls again, now I see only my code file.
也许现在我想更改此程序，但我不
Maybe now I want to change this program, and I don't
想写hello.c，但是再见。
want to write hello.c, but goodbye.c.
好吧，让我关闭那里的标签。
Well, let me close the tab up there.
是的，我可以去右键单击它或按Control键单击它，
And yes, I could go and Right click or Control click on it,
但是同样，我们不需要使用图形界面。
but, again, we don't need to use the graphical interface.
让我继续，转而做mv hello.c再见。
Let me go ahead and instead do mv hello.c goodbye.c.
Mv是移动命令。
Mv is the move command.
即使将其称为“重命名”而不是“ move”会很好，
And even though it would be nice if it's called rename instead of move,
移动只是将一个文件移动到另一个位置或另一个名称。
move just moves one file to another location or to another name.
所以，如果我做mv hello.c再见。
So if I do mv hello.c goodbye.c.
注意发生在左上角的事情。
Notice what happened at top left.
现在，我的同一个文件称为goodbye.c。
Now my same file is called goodbye.c.
如果再次输入ls，我可以看到它确实已重命名。
And if, again, I type ls, I can see that it's indeed renamed.
现在，让我继续并将其移回，因为我
Now, let me go ahead and move that back because I
希望继续使用我的hello.c程序。
want to stay on my hello.c program.
但是，假设我想开始整理文件。
But suppose I want to start organizing my files.
稍后，我们将开始编写更多程序，
In a moment we're going to start writing more programs,
所以我的帐户会有所增加
and so my account is going to get a little bit
在今天的过程中，越来越多的文件杂乱无章。
messy with more and more files over the course of today.
因此，假设你要创建一个文件夹，也称为目录。
So suppose you want to create a folder, otherwise known as a directory.
我将继续输入make目录的mkdir。
I'm going to go ahead and type mkdir for make directory.
然后是我要制作的目录的名称，例如演讲。
And then the name of the directory I want to make, for instance, lecture.
你可以随心所欲地调用它，但是如果我在演讲中，我正在编写代码，
You can call it anything you want, but if I'm in lecture, I'm writing code,
也许我想将今天的所有文件存储在演讲目录中。
maybe I want to store all of today's files in a lecture directory.
当我在其中单击Enter时，请注意此处的文件树中发生了什么。
When I hit Enter there, notice what happens in my file tree up here.
我现在看到一个演讲文件夹。
I now see a lecture folder.
如果单击三角形，则该三角形为空，因为我没有在其中放置任何东西。
If I click the triangle, it's empty because I haven't put anything in it.
因此，让我继续并将hello.c移到演讲文件夹中。
So let me go ahead and move hello.c into the lecture folder.
MV hello.c讲座，现在让我按Enter。
Mv hello.c lecture, and now let me hit Enter.
瞧，现在注意它嵌套在此演讲文件夹中。
And voila, now notice that it's nested inside of this lecture folder.
实际上，如果我现在输入ls作为列表，我只会看到演讲文件夹。
And indeed, if I now type ls for list, I only see the lecture folder.
不幸的是，我现在没有访问权限
Unfortunately, I kind of now don't have access
到此命令行环境中的hello.c
to hello.c within this command line environment
除非我进入那个目录。
unless I change into that directory.
现在，在Mac和PC的世界中，很明显，
Now, in the world of Macs and PCs we, obviously,
只需双击一个文件夹，瞧，我们就在其中。
would just double click on a folder and voila we're inside of it.
在命令行界面中，你需要更加谨慎。
In a command line interface you need to be more deliberate.
所以我要做cd，用于更改目录，
So I'm going to do cd, for change directory,
然后讲课，然后我要继续并按Enter。
then lecture, and then I'm going to go ahead and hit Enter.
现在注意，现在可能更有意义
And now notice, and now it might make more sense
为什么在这整个过程中，我们一直看到蓝色的波浪号斜线。
why this whole time we've been seeing in blue this tilde lecture slash.
代字号仅表示我所谓的主目录。
The tilde just means my so-called home directory.
就像我自己的帐户一样，我自己的默认文件夹（例如我的文档和窗口）
Like my own account, my own default folder, like my documents and windows,
或Mac OS上的文档。
or documents on Mac OS.
这就是代字号（tilde）的简写形式。
That's what tilde represents in shorthand notation.
演讲是我现在所在的文件夹的名称。
Lecture is the name of the folder that I am now inside.
就像我双击Mac OS或Windows上的讲座一样
So it's as though I double clicked on lecture in Mac OS or Windows
打开一个文件夹。
to open a folder.
现在，我在终端窗口中的该演讲目录中。
Now I'm inside this lecture directory in my terminal window.
因此，如果我现在键入ls enter，我应该看到瞧，
So if I now type ls enter, I should see voila,
我移入的hello.c文件。
the hello.c file that I moved into it.
现在，让我撤消此操作，因为我要继续
Now, let me undo this because I'm going to go ahead
并暂时简化一些操作。
and keep things a little simpler for now.
并假设我想将hello.c移至以前的位置。
And suppose that I want to move hello.c into where it previously was.
最后一段语法。
Last piece of syntax.
我们将其称为上级文件夹的简称。
There's this shorthand notation for what we'll call a parent folder.
因此，就像在家谱中一样，有父母和孩子的概念，
So just like in family trees, there's the notion of parents, and children,
和孙子等等。
and grandchildren, and so forth.
在具有文件夹的计算机系统中也是如此。
That's also true in computer systems that have folders.
和文件夹内的文件夹。
And folders inside of folders.
和文件夹里面的文件夹里面的文件夹。
And folders inside of folders inside of folders.
有一个层次结构，就像一棵家谱。
There's a hierarchy there much like a family tree.
因此，如果我想将hello.c上移一个级别，
So if I want to move hello.c one level up,
我实际上可以做mv hello.c空格点。
I can actually do mv hello.c space dot dot.
就像说将文件移到上方的文件夹中一样。
And that's like saying move this file to the folder up above.
当我这样做时，请注意左上方发生的情况。
When I do that, notice what happened at top left.
现在hello.c不在演讲文件夹中，而是在它下面。
Now hello.c is not inside of the lecture folder, but below it.
确实，如果我现在在演讲文件夹中键入ls，那么这里什么也没有。
And indeed, if I type ls now in the lecture folder, there's nothing there.
我如何在这些文件夹的家族树中上移自己的一级？
How do I move myself up one level in the family tree that are these folders?
让我继续，然后键入cd空格点。
Let me go ahead and type cd space dot dot.
因此，将目录更改为我的父母。
So change directory to my parent.
点点只是意味着你的父母。
Dot dot just means your parent.
在上方的文件夹中，输入。
The folder up above, Enter.
而现在，我显然只是在波浪号之间
And now, I'm apparently in just tilde slash,
同样，这是你自己的主目录的隐喻速记符号-
which is, again, cryptic shorthand notation for your own home directory--
你的“我的文档”或“文档”文件夹。
your My Documents or documents folder.
最后，如果我在此处输入ls，则说明课程文件夹已经完成。
And if, lastly, I type ls here, I'm done with this lecture folder.
我不想麻烦将内容存储在文件夹中。
I don't want to bother storing things in a folder.
我不能删除，就像我打过招呼一样，
I can do not rm for remove, like I did to get rid of hello,
但是rmdir删除目录。
but rmdir to remove a directory.
瞧，它不见了。
And voila, it's gone.
而且，我撤消了之前所做的所有各种更改。
And I've undone all of the various changes that I made earlier.
但也许现在更有意义了
But perhaps now it makes a little more sense
为什么我早些做某事。
why I was doing something earlier.
让我打开我的hello.c文件。
Let me open up my hello.c file.
让我再次打招呼，那是我们离开的地方。
Let me make hello again, which is way back where we left off.
回想一下，我一直都在打点斜线打招呼。
And recall that all this time I've been doing dot slash hello.
好吧，为什么呢？
Well, why is that?
就像点点指向你的父目录一样，
Well, just as dot dot refers to your parent directory,
单点表示你的当前目录。
a single dot refers to your current directory.
因此，即使这看起来有点愚蠢，
So even though this looks a little silly,
点斜杠打招呼只是一种非常明确的方式
dot slash hello is just a very explicit way
告诉计算机，运行名为hello的程序
of telling the computer, run the program called hello
就在我当前目录中
that's right here in my current directory.
点表示当前目录。
Dot means current directory.
点点表示父目录。
Dot dot means parent directory.
因此，我们终于看到了为什么我去过
And so there we see, finally, why I've been
一直打点斜杠打招呼。
typing dot slash hello all this time.
再次，这只是做某事的文字模拟
But again, it's just the textual analog of doing something
例如在Mac OS或Windows中双击图标。
like double clicking on an icon in Mac OS or Windows.
因此，还有其他命令，随着时间的流逝，你将接触到这些命令。
So there's other commands too, and over time you'll get exposed to these
并将其用于各种问题。
and use them for various problems.
例如，用于复制的Cp是另一个。
Cp for copy, for instance, is yet another.
还有许多其他命令，但这只是标准命令。
And many others, but these are all just standard commands.
它们不是CS50特有的。
They are not CS50 specific.
允许我们操作文件和文件夹的标准命令
Standard commands that allow us to manipulate files and folders
在这样的计算机上。
in a computer like this.
还有马克斯的问题。
And question from Max.
听众：嗨。
AUDIENCE: Hi.
是的，对不起。
Yeah, sorry.
我只是想知道。
I was just wondering.
我不太了解hello程序之间的区别
I don't really understand the difference between the hello program
和hello.c程序。
and the hello.c program.
似乎上面没有点c的那个东西什么也没用。
It seems like the one that doesn't have dot c on it isn't used for anything.
戴维·马兰：哦，是的。
DAVID MALAN: Oh, it is though.
所以回想一下，我们在故事中有两件事。
So recall that we have two things in the story.
我们有源代码，这就是我一直在编写的C代码。
We have source code, which is the C code I've been writing.
然后是机器码，即零
And then machine code, which is the zeros
以及计算机可以理解的内容。
and ones that the computer understands.
我已经在名为hello.c的文件中编写了所有代码。
I have been writing all of my code in the file called hello.c.
但是用make编译之后，make程序
But after I compile it with make, the make program
创建一个名为hello的新文件，该文件在技术上仅包含零
creates a new file called hello that technically contains only zeros
和一个。
and ones.
那就是我实际上的机器代码
And that is the machine code that I'm actually
当我做点斜线问好时运行。
running when I do dot slash hello.
再说一次，我可以使用rm，并且可以摆脱hello程序
So again, I can use rm and I can get rid of the hello program
就像我以前一样。
just like I did before.
现在我们回到故事的开始
And now we're back at the very beginning of the story
我们从头开始编写此代码的地方。
where we wrote this code from scratch.
如果我现在输入make，现在让我这样做，请ls。
If I now type make, and let me do this now, ls.
注意，我只有一个文件。
Notice I've only got one file.
现在让我打个招呼。
Let me now do make hello.
我看到了神秘的输出，但是如果我再次输入ls，现在我有两个文件。
I see that cryptic output, but if I type ls again, now I have two files.
那是因为只有带有星号的绿色是可执行的。
And that's because only the green one with the asterisk is executable.
那就是编译器为我创建的机器代码。
That is the machine code that the compiler has created for me.
我应该说并拒绝，我一直在讲一个白色的谎言
And I should say and disclaim, I've been telling a little bit of a white lie
今天。
today.
Make本身实际上不是编译器。
Make itself is not actually a compiler.
下周我们将确切地了解make的工作。
We'll see next week exactly what make is doing.
但这使我们更容易实际编译我们的代码，
But it's making it easier for us to actually compile our code,
但是下一次会更多。
but more on that next time.
好的。
All right.
因此，到目前为止，我们仅看到了字符串，但结果却是在C语言中，
So we've seen only strings thus far, but it turns out in C,
在许多语言中，还有其他一些称为类型或数据类型的东西。
and in a lot of languages, there's other things known as types or data types.
也就是说，你可以拥有变量和值
That is to say, you can have variables and values
不仅是文本字符串，而且可能是整数，
that aren't just strings of text, but that are maybe integers,
像数字，一，二，三，四。
like numbers, one, two, three, four.
或者可能是浮点值（例如3.14159）或其他此类值。
Or maybe floating point values, like 3.14159, or other such values.
你可以具有布尔值，只能为true或false。
You can have Boolean values, which are only true or false.
你可以包含单个字符的字符或字符。
You can have characters or chars, which are single characters.
这就是说，在像C这样的语言中，实际上有很多数据
This is to say, within a language like C there's actually a whole bunch of data
你可以使用的类型。
types that are available to you.
字符串只是其中之一。
String is only one of them.
而且，这里的清单甚至更多，
And there's even more than are on this list here,
但这只是我们今天将看到的一些最常见的列表
but this is just a list of some of the most common ones that we'll see today
我们将在下一周的第一个问题集中使用
and we'll use this coming week in the first problem set
这样你不仅可以告诉计算机将值存储在变量中，
that allow you to tell the computer not only to store a value in a variable,
但是要在变量中存储哪种类型的值。
but what type of value to store in a variable.
此外，我们在CS50库中还有很多其他功能。
Moreover, we have in the CS50 library a whole bunch more functions.
我们已经看过get_string了。
We've seen get_string already.
但是类似地，我们创建了一些函数
But similarly have we created functions that you
可以用于问题集，实验等
can use for problem sets, labs, and beyond that
允许你通过get_char获得单个字符。
allow you to get a single character via a get_char.
这样可以使你通过get_int获得一个整数。
That can allow you to get an integer via get_int.
那可以让你得到一个浮点数
That can allow you to get a floating point
值，这是描述实数的一种好方法，
value, which is a fancy way of describing a real number,
使用get_float使用小数点。
with a decimal point using get_float.
但是事实证明，这些数据类型（例如int和float）中的每一个，
But it turns out that each of these data types, like int and float,
只有有限的位数。
only have a finite number of bits.
回想一下上周我们玩过的灯泡
And recall from last week that we played around with light bulbs
然后我们更广泛地使用零位和零位
and we played around with bits and zeros and ones more generally.
事实证明，这些数据类型中的每一种，
It turns out that every one of these data types,
char，double，floats，int，long，string等，全部
char, double, floats, int, long, string, and so forth, all
使用特定数量的位。
use a specific number of bits.
结果表明int（例如C中的整数）仅使用32位。
And it turns out that int, for instance, integers in C, only use 32 bits.
直到你希望计数高于大约4的时间之前，这都是很棒的
And that's great until such time as you want to count higher than roughly 4
十亿，这是你无法做到的。
billion, at which point you can't.
今天晚些时候，我们将看到，如果你仅使用特定数量的位
We'll see later today that if you're only using a specific number of bits
你只能进行如此高的计数，因此存在其他数据类型。
you can only count so high, and so there exist other data types.
例如，很长。
For instance, a long.
长整数是C中仅使用64位的另一种数字。
A long is another type of number in C that just uses 64 bits.
因此，它使你更具表达力，并提供更多零和一的模式
So it gives you way more expressiveness, way more patterns of zeros and ones
甚至更高。
to count even higher.
同样，双精度值类似于浮点值。
Similarly, a double is like a floating point value.
带有小数点的实数，其后还有一些数字。
A real number with a decimal point and some number of digits after it.
双精度字使你可以拥有比浮点数更多的数字。
A double allows you to have even more digits after it than a float would.
因此，我们稍后将看到并使用其中一些数据类型。
So we'll see and use some of these data types in just a bit.
同样，Printf不仅可以打印出字符串，还可以打印出字符串
Printf, similarly, has the ability to print out not only strings
如我们所见，还使用其他数据类型使用了不同的格式代码。
as we saw, but also using different format codes other data types as well.
这些有点神秘，可以根据需要查找这些东西，
These are a little more cryptic and it's fine to look these things up as needed,
但最终你会根深蒂固它们以了解常见的用例。
but you'll eventually ingrain them for common use cases.
百分比c将成为打印单个字符的占位符。
Percent c is going to be the placeholder for printing a single character.
可以说，百分比c为一个字符。
Percent c for a char, so to speak.
f的百分比将为浮点值。
Percent f is going to be for a floating point value.
因此，如果你要打印带小数点的实数，
So if you want to print out a real number with a decimal point,
你将使用百分比f。
you're going to use percent f.
如果要使用打印f打印整数，
If you want to print an integer using print f,
你将使用百分比i作为整数。
you're going to use percent i for integer.
如果要打印字符串，我们已经看到了percent s。
If you want to print a string we've already seen percent s.
如果要打印一个长整数，也就是
And if you want to print a long integer, a.k.a.
很长一段时间，你将要使用百分比li。
long, you're going to use percent li.
甚至还有其他一些，但是这些也许是最常见的一些。
And there's even others, but these are perhaps some of the most common.
这就意味着，C确实确实需要你，程序员，
And it just means that, again, C really needs you, the programmer,
确切地说。
to be precise.
你不能只是说，打印此。
You can't just say, print this.
你必须告诉printf如何打印变量或值
You have to tell printf how to print the variable or the value
你正在传递给它。
that you're passing into it.
最后，事实证明，在C中
And then lastly, it turns out that in C there's
一堆运算符，当然是数学运算符，还有其他运算符
a whole bunch of operators, certainly mathematical ones and bunches of others
也一样
as well.
就像刮开整个操作员工具包一样。
Just like Scratch out a whole toolkit of operators.
到目前为止，C还支持加，减，
And suffice it to say for now that C also supports addition, subtraction,
乘法，除法，甚至余数
multiplication, division, and even the remainder
运算符，用百分号表示。
operator, which a little cryptically is represented with a percent sign.
不要与printf的格式代码混淆，
Not to be confused with printf's format codes,
但这就是说，计算机的某些最早使用，
but this is to say that some of the earliest uses of computers, of course,
都是在电子表格程序中以数学为导向的。
were all mathematically oriented in spreadsheet programs.
像Excel和Google之前的VisiCalc之类的程序
Programs like VisiCalc and the like back before there was Excel and Google
电子表格。
spreadsheets.
而且他们当然是计算机，他们非常擅长支持数学。
And they certainly, computers, are very good at supporting math.
因此，这些只是现在将要看到的一些运营商
And so these are just some of the operators that will now see
可供我们使用。
are available to us.
因此，让我继续执行此操作。
So let me go ahead and do this.
让我在清理东西后回到我的IDE
Let me go back to my IDE after cleaning things
起，然后重新开始，终端窗口中什么也没有，也没有打开任何选项卡。
up, and starting fresh with just nothing in my terminal window and no tabs open.
让我这次继续写我的下一个程序
And let me go ahead and write my next program this time
使用更多这些功能。
using some more of these functions.
我将继续在此处创建一个名为additioning.c的文件。
I'm going to go ahead and create a file up here called addition.c.
所以additional.c，但是我可以称呼它为我想要的任何东西，
So addition.c, but I could call this anything I want,
但是添加点c很重要。
but it's important to add the dot c.
否则，计算机将不会知道其实际来源
Otherwise the computer will not know that it's actual source
代码而不是机器代码。
code as opposed to machine code.
让我继续使用CS50库。
And let me go ahead and make use of the CS50 library.
因此，让我包括cs50.h。
So let me include cs50.h.
让我包括stdio.h，以便可以使用诸如get_int和printf之类的东西。
Let me include stdio.h, so that I can use things like get_int and printf.
然后，为了今天的目的，
And then, again, for today's purposes,
我将先做int main void，然后做花括号。
I'm just going to do int main void, and then the curly braces.
再说一次，今天，只要相信这一点就可以了。
And again, for today, just take on faith this is necessary.
但是我们会在一两周内解释为什么
But we'll explain within a week or two exactly why
我们继续写int main void。
we keep writing int main void.
但就目前而言，这就像赢得绿色标志的拼图一样。
But for now, it's like the win green flag clicked puzzle piece.
现在让我继续，从用户那里获取一个整数。
Let me go ahead now and get an integer from the user.
假设我现在的目标不是编写一个程序
Suppose my goal now is not to write a program that
获取一串文本并打印出你好，Brian或你好，David。
gets a string of text and prints out hello, Brian, or hello, David.
让我继续写一个可能会问的程序
Let me go ahead and write a program that maybe asks
两个整数，两个数字，然后将它们加在一起。
for two integers, two numbers, and then just adds them together.
因此，让我使用代码使计算器最简单。
So let me make the simplest of calculators using code.
好吧，我将继续声明一个名为
Well, I'm going to go ahead and declare a variable called
x，就像数学家一样。
x, just like a mathematician would.
我将为其分配调用get_int的值。
And I'm going to assign it the value of calling get_int.
我只说x冒号。
And I'll just say something like x colon.
我可以说任何我想说的，x是什么？
I could say anything I want, what is x?
但是我将保持简单，只说x冒号。
But I'm going to keep it simple and just say x colon.
分号结束了我的想法。
Semicolon to end my thought.
再说一次，在精神上与我之前对弦乐所做的类似，
So again, similar in spirit to what I did with string before,
但是现在我正在使用get_int从用户那里获取数字或整数。
but now I'm using get_int to get a number or an integer from the user.
这里引用的参数或参数是输入
The quoted parameter here or argument is the input
get_int，这将是人类看到的提示。
to get_int, which is going to be the prompt that the human sees.
等号，回想，是赋值运算符，
The equals sign, recall, is the assignment operator,
也就是说，复制右侧的返回值-
which says, copy the return value on the right--
人类希望输入的整数-
the integer that the human hopefully will type in--
在左边。
over to the left.
左边说，给我一个变量x
And the left says, give me a variable called, x,
并让我在其中存储整数。
and let me store integers in it.
因此，在此之前，我们在左侧使用string，在右侧使用get_string。
So before, we use string on the left and we used get_string the right.
现在唯一的区别是左边的int
The only difference now is int on the left,
因为我要一个数字，右边是get_int。
because I want a number, and get_int on the right.
然后，让我继续并再次执行此操作，并获得另一个号码。
Then let me go ahead and do this again and get another number.
Get_int，我只是说，冒号。
Get_int, and I'll just say, y colon.
但是我可以再说一遍，什么是问号，或者什么是英语。
But again, I could say, what is y question mark, or anything in English.
但是最后一行将是有趣的。
But the last line is going to be the interesting one.
现在，我要继续进行打印，例如
Now, I'm going to go ahead and print out for instance,
这两个数字的总和。
the sum of these two numbers.
但是，printf再次接受一个输入，告诉它确切地打印出什么内容。
But printf, again, takes an input that tells it what to print out exactly.
所以我现在还不能真正输入数字，因为我不知道
So I can't really type a number here yet because I don't know
人类将要输入的内容。
what the human is going to type in.
所以我要放一个占位符。
So I'm going to put a placeholder.
我要说的是百分之一，在这里放一个数字，
I'm going to percent i, which says, put a number here,
我只是不知道那是什么。
I just don't know yet what it is.
然后为了保持清洁，我要
And then just to keep things clean, I'm going
做反斜杠n（刚才说），也给我换行。
to do backslash n, which just says, give me a new line also.
这只是将光标移至下一行的美学细节
That's just an aesthetic detail to move the cursor to the next line just
保持清洁。
to keep things clean.
但是现在printf将有第二个论点。
But now printf is going to take a second argument.
而且，无论你之前是否进行过编程，
And whether you've programmed or not before--
布莱恩，如果可以的话，让我们去找听众中的某人
Brian, let's go to someone in the audience if we could--
如果此程序的目的，我应该在逗号后面键入什么
what should I type after the comma if the purpose of this program
只是简单地将两个数字相加？
is quite simply to add two numbers together?
即使你以前从未编程过，也要根据现有的运算符进行编程
Even if you've never programmed before, based on the operators that exist
以及到目前为止我们已经看到的一些语法，
and some of the syntax we've seen thus far,
你在这里输入什么直觉？
what would your instincts have you type here?
即使你以前从未这样做过。
Even if you've never done this before.
圣地亚哥，你怎么看？
Santiago, what do you think?
听众：我会说只写x加y。
AUDIENCE: I would say to just write x plus y.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：是的，它是如此简单和直接。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, it is simple and as straightforward as that.
X加y是正确的直觉。
X plus y is the right intuition.
我将在最后添加一个分号以完成我的想法。
I'm going to add a semicolon to the very end just to finish my thought.
但是确实，在这种情况下，计算机和C
But indeed, computers, and C in this case,
完全理解算术和数学运算，所以只需键入
absolutely understand arithmetic and mathematical operations, so just type
你是什么意思。
what you mean.
我现在要继续并保存文件，然后在下面进行浏览。
I'm going to go ahead now and save the file and go down below.
而且我不再输入make hello了。
And I'm not going to type make hello anymore.
现在，我要键入make add，因为那是我文件的名称
Now I want to type make addition, because that is the name of my file
隐含地。
implicitly.
加法c。
Addition.c.
我想编译成一个名为“加法”的程序。
I want to compile into a program called addition.
希望这是我的手指，没有犯任何错误。
Hopefully, this is where I cross my fingers, I didn't make any mistakes.
我将继续进行添加。
And I'm going to go ahead and run make addition.
一切顺利，没有错误消息。
All this well, no error messages.
如果我犯了一个错误，甚至没有编译，
If I had made a mistake and it didn't even compile,
help50可能是我的下一个直觉。
help50 might have been my next instinct.
现在，我将继续运行点斜杠加法。
Now I'm going to go ahead and run dot slash addition.
并注意，我首先被提示输入x。
And notice, I'm first prompted for x.
我要去做一个。
I'm going to go ahead and do one.
接下来，我提示你输入y。
I'm next prompted for y.
我要继续做一次。
I'm going to go ahead and do one again.
瞧，正如圣地亚哥所建议的，我的确在屏幕上看到x加y，
And voila, as Santiago proposed, I indeed see on the screen x plus y,
或值二。
or the value two.
而且我没有硬编码两个。
And I didn't hardcode two.
无论x加y的实际结果如何，我都用i代替。
I substituted in using i whatever the result of x plus y actually is.
现在注意，get_int函数的某些功能为你服务。
Now notice, some of the features of the get_int function for you.
假设你不是很合作，请输入cat作为x。
Suppose that you're not being very cooperative and you type in cat for x.
请注意，get_int只会忽略你并再次提示你。
Notice that get_int just ignores you and prompts you again.
如果我输入狗，它会忽略我并再次提示我。
If I type in dog it ignores me and prompts me again.
如果我输入1.23，它将忽略我并再次提示我
If I type in 1.23, it ignores me and prompts me again
因为在这种情况下，它需要一个整数。
because it wants an integer in this case.
像一，二，三，四这样的数字。
A number like one, two, three, four.
或负一，二，三，四或零，或高于或低于此值。
Or negative one, two, three, four, or zero, or anything above or below.
很好，我现在将合作并给予第一。
So fine, I'll cooperate now and give it the number one.
与y相同。
Same for y.
它将忽略任何非整数输入。
It's going to ignore any non-integer input.
因此，如果这次我给它一个类似两个的数字，
So if I give it a number like two this time,
我希望得到三个答案。
I'll hopefully get the answer of three.
好的。
All right.
所以我们在C中有一个基本的计算器。我们正在使用一些基本的构建
So we have a basic calculator in C. We're using some basic building
像以前一样阻止。
blocks as before.
我们已经有了这些头文件，它们使我可以访问get_int和printf
We've got these header files, which just give me access to get_int and printf
分别。
respectively.
但是，假设现在我想算得更高。
But suppose now I want to count up even higher.
你知道吗？
You know what?
让我尝试这样的事情。
Let me try something like this.
让我再次运行该程序。
Let me run this program once more.
让我有点贪心。
And let me get a little greedy.
大约40亿。
How about 4,000,000,000.
大概-好吧-确切地说-
So roughly-- well, exactly--
40亿。
4 billion.
那是我要输入的号码。
That's the number I want to type in.
请注意，x不喜欢那样。
Notice that x does not like that.
因此，get_int不接受40亿。
So get_int does not accept 4 billion.
好吧，让我尝试一下30亿。
Well, let me try it maybe 3 billion.
嗯。
Uh-huh.
不喜欢那样
Didn't like that.
二十亿左右呢？
How about 2 billion?
好，那个工作了。
OK, that one worked.
让我在这里暂停。
Let me pause here.
可能是怎么回事？
What's going on perhaps?
再一次，我们的工作人员写了get_int，所以我们
Now again, we the staff wrote get_int, so we
是那些拒绝猫，拒绝狗和拒绝的人
are the ones that are rejecting cats, and rejecting dogs, and rejecting
40亿甚至30亿。
4 billion, and even 3 billion.
但是在这种情况下，它还不太清楚。
But in this case, it's a little less clear.
为什么我们拒绝40亿和30亿呢？
Why did we reject 4 billion and 3 billion do you think?
基于迄今为止的一些定义。
Based on some of the definitions thus far today.
为什么会这样呢？
Why might this be?
纳撒尼尔，你怎么看？
Nathaniel, what do you think?
听众：号码大小有上限
AUDIENCE: There's a cap on the size of the number
因为20亿的大小之后会占用太多的位和字节。
since it would take too many bits and bytes after the size of 2 billion.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：完美。
DAVID MALAN: Perfect.
因此，整数又在C中实现为这些整数。
So integers, again, are implemented in C as these things ints.
事实证明，整数仅使用32位。
Ints only use, it turns out, 32 bits total.
而且你只会知道，通过教它
And you would only know that by having been taught it
或查找特定的计算机系统。
or looked it up for a particular computer system.
但是在CS50 IDE和大多数现代系统上，它们的整数只有32位。
But they on CS50 IDE, and most modern systems, an integer is only 32 bits.
然后，这引发了一个问题，
And that then invites the question, well,
如果你有32位或灯泡，你能算多高？
if you've got 32 bits or light bulbs, how high can you count?
嗯，结果是有32个灯泡或比特，
Well, it turns out with 32 light bulbs, or bits,
你大约可以算出40亿。
you can count roughly as high as 4 billion.
你绝对可以算出高达30亿。
You can absolutely count as high as 3 billion.
但是，get_int仍然拒绝它。
And yet, get_int still rejecting it.
但这是因为get_int函数广泛支持整数
But that's because the get_int function supports integers broadly
讲，不仅包括正数，
speaking, which includes not only positive numbers,
而且还有负数和零。
but also negative numbers and zero.
而且要注意的是，如果你想同时支持两个正数
And the catch is that if you want to support both positive numbers
和负数，则可以代表40亿左右的可能总值。
and negative numbers, you can represent 4 billion or so total possible values.
但是，如果你想在数字上向左偏右
But if you want to go as far to the left and as far to the right on the number
我正在描述的行。
line that I'm describing.
你只能算出正面向上的数字高达20亿
You can only really count as high as 2 billion in the positive direction
负向则为负20亿。
and negative 2 billion in the negative direction.
因为那仍然可以给你40亿，
Because that still gives you a total of 4 billion,
但不超过30亿或40亿。
but not nearly as high as 3 billion or 4 billion.
那么，这里的解决方案是什么？
So what might the solution here be?
好吧，我记得前面曾提到过，还有其他数据类型。
Well, I recall earlier noting that there's other data types.
不仅是整数和字符串，而且还有长整数，从字面上看
Not just ints and strings, but also longs, which literally
是较长的整数，即64位。
are longer integers, namely 64 bit.
因此，让我继续尝试。
So let me go ahead and try this.
让我继续，将get_int更改为get_long。
Let me go ahead and change get_int to get_long.
此get_int到get_long。
This get_int to get_long.
让我将此int更改为long，并将此int更改为long。
Let me change this int a long, and this int to a long.
所以相同的程序，相同的计算器，但我
So same program, same calculator, but I'm
现在使用另一种数据类型
now using a different data type that's just
将使用更多的位来存储值。
going to use more bits to store values.
让我再次运行make add以重新编译程序。
Let me run make addition again to recompile my program.
而且，该死。
And, oh, damn it.
我搞砸了。
I screwed up.
因此，让我们看看是否无法在这里收集出什么问题。
So let's see if we can't glean what's wrong here.
让我向上滚动。
Let me scroll up.
而且我对此不够强调。
And I can't emphasize this enough.
有时-我在这里很幸运，但我只犯了一个错误，
Sometimes-- I got lucky here and I only have one mistake, apparently,
在错误消息中-这并不少见
in the error messages-- it is not going to be uncommon
就像两行代码一样，你将遇到两个错误（10个错误）。
for you to have two errors, 10 errors, in like two lines of code.
这是因为有时当你的代码中有错误时，
This is because sometimes when you have errors in your code,
编译器有时会感到困惑。
the compiler sometimes just gets confused.
如果弄得很困惑，它就会开始思考一切
And if it gets sufficiently confused, it starts thinking everything
是你实际代码中的错误。
is an error in your actual code.
因此，最重要的要点是，无论
So the most important takeaway is that no matter
你似乎有多少错误，请始终向上滚动到输出的顶部
how many errors you seem to have, always scroll up to the top of the output
并首先解决第一个错误。
and address the first error first.
这就是为什么我在窗口中向上滚动以立即在所键入内容的下方查看，
So that's why I scrolled up in my window to look immediately below what I typed,
进行加法，这是第一个错误。
make addition, and here's the first error.
第10行的Addition.c
Addition.c on line 10.
好的。
All right.
我看不到第10行，所以让我向上滚动代码。
I can't see line 10, so let me scroll my code up.
这是关于格式的一些说明，它指定类型为int，
And it's saying something about format specifies type int,
但是该参数的类型为long。
but the argument has type long.
我们之前从未见过此错误，但我想我可以从中推断出这一错误。
We haven't seen this error before, but I think I can infer from this.
即使不熟悉，也不是超级神秘。
It's not super cryptic even though it's unfamiliar.
我认为这意味着我记得的百分比是整数。
I think what this means is that percent i recall was for integers.
我认为我需要的是用于长整数的不同格式代码，其中
I think what I need is a different format code for long integers, which
会变成李。
is going to be li instead.
那是我早些时候的小备忘单。
And that was from my little cheat sheet earlier.
因此，让我继续尝试一下。
So let me go ahead and try this again.
将i更改为li后进行加法。
Make addition after changing the i to an li.
确实有效。
That indeed works.
现在让我做-
Now let me do--
哎呀，错字。
oops, typo.
现在让我加点斜杠。
Now let me dot slash addition.
现在，我输入4,000,000,000。
And now I'll type in 4,000,000,000.
40亿。
4 billion.
现在get_long很高兴，它将接受这么长的整数
Now get_long is happy, and it will accept such a long integer
因为它有足够的位。
because it has enough bits.
好吧，关于整数和长整型的问题，
All right, questions on types like ints and longs,
或类似get_int或get_long的函数。
or functions like get_int or get_long.
是的，彼得。
Yeah, Peter.
听众：是的。
AUDIENCE: Yeah.
当我输入20亿并且都是整数时，
When I typed 2 billion and both were integers, well,
最终，它只会给你错误的答案。
eventually it just gives you the wrong answer.
一些负数。
Some negative numbers.
那是因为位和字节吗？
Is that because of the bits and bytes?
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：的确如此。
DAVID MALAN: Indeed.
答案是一样的。
It's the same answer.
所以我没有证明，但是如果你同时输入了20亿
So I didn't demonstrate that, but if you inputed both 2 billion
x和y的20亿，然后尝试将它们加在一起，
for x and 2 billion for y and then you try to add those together,
从数学上讲，这将为你带来40亿美元。
that would give you mathematically 4 billion.
但同样，一个int不足以存储40亿个
But again, an int is not big enough to store 4 billion
如果我们也想代表负数
if we want to also be able to represent negative numbers.
彼得，你看到的是你无法适应
So Peter what you're seeing is that you can't fit
所允许的数据类型中的结果。
the result in the data type allowed.
一会儿我们会看到-
And we'll see in a moment--
实际上，在今天的那一刻，
in a little bit today, actually, what the ramifications of that
是，但是你所描述的症状是完全正确的。
are, but the symptom you're describing is exactly.
你试图将太大的数字填入有限的32位中。
That you tried to cram too big of a number into finitely many bits, 32.
当然，你可以通过切换到较长时间来避免该问题。
You can avoid that problem though, of course, by switching over to long.
让我尝试另一件事，这有点奇怪。
Let me try one other thing that's a bit curious.
让我继续，现在编写一个略有不同的程序。
Let me go ahead and write a slightly different program now.
我将其描述为truncation.c。
And I'm going to describe this as truncation.c.
花哨的词，但是我们马上就会知道这意味着什么。
Fancy term, but we'll see what this means in just a moment.
我要把自己放在首位，cs50.h。
I'm going to give myself at the top, cs50.h.
我要给自己stdio.h。
And I'm going to give myself stdio.h.
一旦开始第一个实验或问题，就可以了
And it's certainly fine, once you get started with the first lab or problem
设置，如果你需要更长的时间才能输入其中的一些内容。
set, if it takes you much longer to type some of these things out.
我只是为了增强肌肉记忆力。
I'm just doing it for muscle memory.
Int主要无效。
Int main void.
现在，我们可以在名为truncation.c的文件中使用新程序了。
And now we're good to go with a new program in a file called truncation.c.
我将继续，提示用户再次输入int。
I'm going to go ahead and prompt a user for an int, again.
所以就像以前一样。
So just like before.
我将像以前一样提示用户输入另一个int。
I'm going to prompt the user for another int, just like before.
然后，我将继续执行此操作。
And then I'm going to go ahead and do this.
这次我想做分割。
I want to do division this time.
因此，不仅仅是添加，这有点太容易了。
So not just a addition, that was a little too easy.
让我做个除法。
Let me do a division.
因此，让我给自己一个变量，z等于x除以y。
So let me give myself another variable, z equals x divided by y.
让我在这里停留片刻，然后问
And let me pause here for a moment and just ask
问题是，z应该使用哪种数据类型？
the question, what data type should I perhaps use for z?
这行代码尚不正确，因为你随时都可以回想起
This line of code is not yet correct, because recall that any time you
在左侧创建一个新变量，我是
create a new variable on the left here, I'm
需要在该变量名称的左侧添加一些内容
going to need to put something to the left of that variable's name
这样C就能知道我想要什么类型的变量。
so that C knows what type of variable I want.
到目前为止，我们已经看到了string和int以及long。
And thus far we've seen string and int and long.
那么，你是否建议对z使用其中之一？
So would you propose we use one of those or something else for z?
杰克呢。
How about Jack.
你怎么认为？
What do you think?
听众：会是浮标吗？
AUDIENCE: Would it be a float?
大卫·马兰：是的，所以浮动。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, so float.
因此，float是浮点值的缩写，它是程序员的
So float, which is short for floating point value, which is the programmer's
描述实数的方式。
way of describing a real number.
让我继续做。
Let me go ahead and do that.
一个浮点数。
A float.
而且我猜你对浮动的直觉是，
And I'm guessing your instincts for float were that, well,
如果你为x输入一个数字，为y输入另一个数字
if you type in one number for x and another for y
结果只是某种程度的一部分，所以
and the result is a fraction of some sort, so something
带小数点
with a decimal point.
我们需要将其存储在一个浮动中，以便我们实际上可以
We need to store it in a float so that we can actually
存储小数点后的数字。
store whatever the numbers are after the decimal point.
因此，让我们继续执行此操作。
So let's go ahead and do this.
现在让我继续进行打印。
Let me now go ahead and print this out.
f反斜杠n的百分数，因为这次我要打印浮点数。
Percent f backslash n, because I'm printing a float this time.
然后让我继续打印z的值。
And then let me go ahead and print out the value of z.
你知道吗？
And you know what?
只是为了好措施，让我也开始在这里练习良好的风格。
Just for good measure, let me start practicing good style here too.
因此从用户那里获得一个号码。
So get a number from user.
让我再给我自己评论。
Let me give myself another comment.
从用户那里获得另一个号码。
Get another number from user.
或者你知道吗？
Or you know what?
这似乎有点愚蠢。
This seems a little silly.
我可以合并这些行。
I can combine these lines.
我为什么不说，例如，从用户那里获得数字。
And why don't I just say, get, for instance, numbers from user.
这是注释你的代码的一种合理方法。
That's a reasonable way to comment your code.
然后让我们继续将x除以y。
And then let's just go ahead and divide x by y.
但这甚至有点学究
But even this is getting a little pedantic
因为你可以从代码中读取该信息。
because you can kind of read that from the code.
因此，在某些时候，我们甚至可能不需要对此发表评论。
So at some point we might not even need a comment for that.
因此，我们就这样简化一下。
So let's just simplify as such.
现在让我们继续进行编译。
Let's go ahead now and compile this.
让-来吧-
Make-- come on--
截断。
make truncation.
好的，它编译就可以了。
All right, it compiles OK.
我喜欢我们在这里使用浮子的方式。
And I like how we used a float here.
这确实是正确的。
That does feel correct.
因此，让我运行截断。
So let me run truncation.
让我继续输入例如x的4和y的2。
And let me go ahead and type in, for instance, 4 for x and 2 for y.
好，我喜欢
OK, I like that.
它是2.000，所以这是正确的数学计算。
It's 2.000, so that's the correct math calculation.
1除以2怎么样
How about 1 divided by 2.
因此x为1，y为2，为0.000000。
So x is 1, y is 2, and it's 0.000000.
好吧，也许那只是a幸。
All right, well, maybe that was just a fluke.
让我尝试再次运行它。
Let me try running it again.
2/3呢？
How about 2/3?
2除以3。
2 divided by 3.
那也不对。
That's not right either.
好的。
All right.
4/3呢？
How about 4/3?
让我们为x设置一个更大的数字，即4/3。
Let's put a bigger number for the x, so 4/3.
好的，离右边更近了。
OK, it's closer to right.
但这是本周的一个示例错误。
But this is an example, this week, of a bug.
这样我的代码就可以编译了。
So my code compile.
因此，从语法上讲这很好，但这是一个逻辑错误。
So syntactically it's fine, but this is a logical bug.
就像我以某种方式不正确地使用了C代码一样。
Like I've somehow used C code improperly.
那么这可能是怎么回事？
So what might be going on here?
为什么1除以2和2除以3都明显为零，
Why is 1 divided by 2 and 2 divided by 3 both apparently zero,
小数点后跟六个零。
followed by six zeros after the decimal point.
甚至4/3给我1.000000而不是1.33333。
And even 4/3 gives me 1.000000 instead of 1.33333.
妮娜，你觉得呢？
Nina, what do you think?
听众：因为使用int，它们无法识别小数。
AUDIENCE: Because with int they don't recognize decimals.
因此4/3问题3仅一次进入4，因此返回1。
So 4/3 question three only goes into 4 one time, so it returns a 1.
而且你需要使用其他类型的字符，
And you need to use other types of character,
如浮点数或双精度数（如果需要实际的小数）。
like a float or a double if you want the actual decimal.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：好的，是的。
DAVID MALAN: Yeah, exactly.
比我以前犯的错误更微妙。
This one's more subtle than the mistakes I've made before.
但是C和大多数编程语言一样，将带你真正地了解你。
But C, like most programming languages, is going to take you literally.
因此，如果在此表达式的右侧，在第11行
So if on the right hand side of this expression, on line 11,
我实际上是在做x除以y。
I am literally doing x divided by y.
你首先要问自己，好，x的类型是什么？
You first have to ask yourself, well, what is the type of x?
y的类型是什么？
What is the type of y?
如果它们都是整数，那么根据C的定义，
If they are both ints, by definition of how C works,
你将获得一个整数作为答案。
you are going to get back an integer as your answer.
因此，如果你将1除以2。
So if you do 1 divided by 2.
是的，数学上为0.50000。
Yes, mathematically that's 0.50000.
但是，如果将其转换为int形式，则x和y均为int形式，
However, if you convert that to an int, in so far as x and y are ints,
C的工作方式是截断小数点后的所有内容。
the way C works is it truncates everything after the decimal point.
因此它可以正确执行数学运算，但是因为你无法拟合浮点数
So it does the math correctly, but because you cannot fit floating point
值，则此后不能将小数点和数字都放在整数中，
values, you cannot fit decimal points and numbers thereafter in an integer,
你会失去小数点后的所有这些数字，因为你可以
you get you lose all of those digits after the decimal point because you can
仅将答案的整数部分放入整数中。
only fit the integer part of the answer into an integer.
我最终将结果保存在浮动中并不重要
It's not relevant that I'm saving the result ultimately in a float
因为为时已晚。
because that's too late.
数学已经在右侧完成。
The math has already been done on the right hand side.
所以是的，我在浮点数中存储一个整数，以便可以将其打印为浮点数，
And so yes, I'm storing an integer in a float so I can print it as a float,
但是为时已晚。
but it's too late.
小数点后的所有内容都已被丢弃。
Everything after the decimal point has already been thrown away.
那么这意味着什么，或者我该如何解决？
So what are the implications of this, or how could I fix?
好吧，我可以仔细检查并更改所有这些权利。
Well, I could go through and just change all of this right.
好吧，如果问题是x和y是整数，
Well, if the problem is that x and y are ints,
好吧，让我将它们更改为浮点数。
well, let me just change them to floats.
然后将其更改为此处，将x更改为浮点数，将y更改为浮点数，
And change this up here, change x to a float, change y to a float,
等等。
and so forth.
这样可以解决问题。
That would fix the problem.
但这是解决此问题的繁重解决方案。
But that's kind of a heavy handed solution to this problem.
遍历并更改所有代码。
Go through and change all of your code.
你可以变得更加聪明，然后
You can instead be a little more clever, and you
可以说服计算机将整数转换为浮点数
can convince the computer to convert an integer to a float
被称为铸造的东西。
by something known as casting.
所以我实际上可以进入这里，并使用新的语法我可以说float y。
So I can actually go in here, and using a new syntax I can say float y.
我什至可以做到，但并非绝对必要，
And I can even, for good measure, but it's not strictly necessary,
也对x做。
also do it to x.
你可以在C中将一种数据类型强制转换或类型转换为另一种数据类型
You can in C, cast or typecast one data type to another
只需在括号内加上所需的新数据类型即可。
by literally in parentheses just putting the new data type that you want.
如果将一个转换为另一个在数学上有意义，
And if it makes mathematical sense for one to be converted into the other,
电脑会帮你做。
the computer will do it for you.
所以我以这种方式告诉计算机，将x转换为浮点数，
So in this way I'm telling the computer, convert x to a float,
将y转换为浮点数，然后进行数学运算。
convert y to a float, then do the math.
因此，在我分别为x和y输入一和二之前，
And so before when I typed in one and two respectively for x and y,
现在就像我输入1.0和2.0。
now it's like I typed in 1.0 and 2.0.
1.0除以2.0在数学上将是0.5，
And 1.0 divided by 2.0 is going to be mathematically 0.5,
但是由于x和y现在已经提前转换为浮点数，
but because x and y now were converted in advance to floats,
答案将保持在0.5的浮动范围内。
the answer is going to remain a float, 0.5.
这就是将要存储在z中并最终打印出来的内容。
And that's what's going to get stored in z and ultimately printed.
因此，如果我重新运行截断功能，现在已经解决了此问题。
So if I rerun truncation having now fixed this problem.
让我做点斜杠截断。
Let me do dot slash truncation.
输入一，输入二。
Type in one, type in two.
我不必自己输入0.0。
I don't have to type the 0.0 myself.
计算机通过括号中的这些强制转换为我执行此操作。
The computer's doing that for me via these casts in parentheses.
现在我看到答案的确是0.5。
Now I see that the answer is indeed 0.5.
好的。
All right.
所以我们现在似乎有了一些非常基本的低级控制
So we seem to have now some very basic low level control
你可以使用该程序做什么。
over what you can do with the program.
现在让我们重新添加所有精美功能
Let's now add back all of the fancy features
上周我们从Scratch获得的
that we had from Scratch last week so we can
开始制作更多有趣的程序。
start making more interesting programs.
因此，变量和另一个称为语法糖的技术术语也是
So variables and another term of art called syntactic sugar is also
在C的功能中。
among C's features here.
所以回想一下上周，当我们想要一个名为
So recall from last week when we wanted to have a variable called
计数器设置为零。
counter set equal to zero.
我们可以像这样定义它。
We can go ahead and define it like this.
从今天开始，在C语言中，我们将改为说些什么
In C, starting today, we're going to instead say something
例如，计数器等于零。
like, counter equals zero.
但是我们还需要指定该变量的数据类型，
But we additionally need to specify the data type of that variable,
我们需要以分号结束我们的思想。
and we need to end our thought with a semicolon.
因此，尽管我们上周将计数器设置为零，但现在
So whereas we set counter to zero like this last week, now
它将在右侧非常简单地转换为此。
it's going to translate quite simply to this on the right hand side.
好吧，那之后呢？
Well, what comes after that?
好吧，如果我们想在上周将计数器变量加1，
Well, if we wanted to increment a counter variable last week by one,
在其中添加一个，我们非常简单地使用了这个拼图。
adding one to it, we used quite simply this puzzle piece.
这周我们需要更加明确，说出这样的话。
This week we need to be a little more explicit and say something like this.
Counter等于counter加1，并用分号结束思考。
Counter equals counter plus one, and semicolon to finish the thought.
现在，这在数学上似乎很矛盾。
Now, this might seem very mathematically paradoxical.
例如，计数器如何等于计数器加一？
Like, how can counter equal counter plus one?
就像，这在逻辑上是行不通的。
Like, that just doesn't work logically.
但是，在这种情况下，这不是等号。
But that's not the equal sign in this case.
与其他语言一样，在C语言中，
In C, as with other languages we'll encounter,
等号是从右到左的赋值运算符。
the equals sign is the assignment operator from right to left.
这就是说，加计数器加一，
So this is saying, take counter plus one,
并将该数学结果存储在左侧。
and store that mathematical result on the left.
因此，无论计数器是多少，都加一个，然后将结果存储在计数器中。
So whatever counter is, add one, store the result in counter thereafter.
有效地，将总数增加一倍。
Effectively, increasing its total by one.
现在，这是程序中非常常见的操作
Now this is a very common operation in programs
我们会在整个学期中看到你只想添加一些内容的地方
we'll see over the term where you just want to add something up
因为你想跟踪某物的数量。
because you want to keep track of the count of something.
事实证明，有一些语法糖，
So it turns out there's some syntactic sugar, which
意味着有一种不同的语法实现方式
means there's a different way of doing this syntactically that doesn't give
你尚未拥有的任何新功能
you any new capabilities that you didn't already
在C中使用。它只是使键入稍微更愉快或更快速。
have in C. It just makes it marginally more pleasant or quicker to type.
因此，C语言中的这一行代码与说这行代码相同
So this line of code in C is identical to saying this line of code
在C中。Counter加号等于一个分号表示在左边取变量
in C. Counter plus equals one semicolon means take the variable on the left
并添加一个。
and just add one to it.
而且它更加简洁，它只是
And it's slightly more succinct, and it just
使你的代码更具可读性，因为对于我们来说，事情变得更少了
makes your code a little more readable because it's just fewer things for us
人类必须阅读。
humans to have to read.
但是，你甚至可以更进一步。
But you can even do one step further.
存在其他语法糖，从而
Additional syntactic sugar exists, whereby
你甚至不需要键入此内容。
you don't even need to type this.
你可以改为只做计数器加号。
You can instead just do counter plus plus.
计数器加号是最短的手写符号
Counter plus plus is the shortest hand notation
在C中仅向变量添加一个。
in C for just adding one to a variable.
好的。
All right.
除变量外，截至上周，我们的工具包还包含哪些内容？
Besides variables, what else do we have in our toolkit as of last week?
好吧，上周我们在工具包中也有了这个概念，
Well, we also had in our toolkit last week the notion, of course,
条件。
of conditions.
情况就像路边的叉子
A condition was like a fork in the road that
可能会让你做这件事，这件事或其他事情
could allow you to do this thing, this other thing, or something else
共。
altogether.
例如，在Scratch中，如果我们想上周比较两个变量，
In Scratch for instance, if we wanted last week to compare two variables,
x和y用于不等式。
x and y for inequality.
x小于y吗？
Is x less than y?
如果是这样，则说x小于y。
And if so, say x is less than y.
我们如何将其转换为C？
How can we translate this to C?
好吧，语法将非常简单。
Well, the syntax is going to be quite simply this.
一些新东西。
Some new stuff.
还有更多的括号，还有更多的花括号。
Some more parentheses, some more curly braces.
但是，尽管是文本形式，但外观上看起来还是一样的。
But it kind of visually looks the same, albeit in text form.
我从字面上说，如果是空格，则在括号中我
I literally say, if a space, then in parentheses I
包括我的布尔表达式，回想一下上周的内容。
include my Boolean expression, recall those from last week.
X小于y是我的布尔表达式。
X less than y is my Boolean expression.
然后注意，我使用了一个开放的花括号和一个封闭的花括号。
Then notice I use an open curly brace and a close curly brace.
然后我只为一行或多行代码留空行
And then I'm just leaving a blank line for one or more lines of code
就像我上周一样。
just like I might of last week.
实际上，让我们在此处放置等效的代码行。
And in fact, let's put the equivalent line of code here.
使用printf打印出来，x小于y，反斜杠n。
Print out using printf, x is less than y, backslash n.
因此，我们之前已经完成了该翻译。
So we've already done that translation before.
说就像printf，就像现在就好像如果。
Say is just like printf, just like if now is like if.
严格来说，尤其是如果你已经编程过，
Strictly speaking, especially if you've programmed before,
如果你只需要这两个花括号，
you do not need these two curly braces if you only
条件中只有一行代码。
have one line of code inside of the condition.
但是，从样式上考虑，为了CS50和style50，
However, stylistically for CS50 and for style50's sake,
无论如何，总是在自己的行上包括这些花括号。
always include these curly braces nonetheless, and on their own lines.
好吧，我们在Scratch还能做什么？
All right, what else can we do in Scratch?
回想一下，如果没有的话，我们可以做。
Recall that we can do if else.
我们可以在叉子中选择一种方式，也可以在叉子中选择另一种方式。
And we can go either one way in the fork or the other way in the fork.
在C语言中，相应的代码将如下所示。
In C, the corresponding code is going to look like this.
所以它几乎和以前一样。
So it's almost the same as before.
我刚刚添加了其他内容，然后添加了另一个花括号和一个紧密的花括号。
I've just added else, and then another curly brace and a close curly brace.
而且，我只添加printf的内容。
And let me just add in the printf's.
你会发现在C语言中，这真的很像黑色和白色，
And you can see that in C this is really like the black and white,
上周非常图形化的基于文本的版本，
the text based version of what was very graphical last week,
但想法是一样的。
but the idea is the same.
你只需要开始认识括号的位置，
You just got to start to recognize where the parentheses go,
花括号在哪里，分号，
where the curly braces go, the semicolons,
以及所有类似的视觉内容。
and all that sort of visual stuff.
好吧，让我们再进行一次Scratch比较。
All right, let's make one more Scratch comparison.
这是我说过的，如果x小于y，则x小于y。
Here is one where I said if x is less than y, say x is less than y.
否则，如果x大于y，则说x大于y。
Else if x is greater than y, say x is greater than y.
否则，如果x等于y，则说x等于y。
Else if x equals y, then say x equal to y.
现在，这是Scratch和C分叉的地方。
Now, here is where Scratch and C diverge.
因为Scratch的意图是非常用户友好
Because Scratch is meant to be very user friendly
不需要对赋值运算符进行详细说明，MIT for Scratch
and not require long explanations of assignment operators, MIT for Scratch
只需使用等号进行相等即可。
just use the equal sign for equality.
而C使用等号从左到右进行分配，
Whereas C uses the equal sign for assignment from left to right,
但这意味着像以前一样平等。
but this means equality as before.
好的。
All right.
现在，请注意此处的区别。
Now, notice the difference here.
一切都是逐行翻译，
Everything is a line by line translation,
尽管我们可以将else如果放在同一行上，或者else在同一行上。
although we can put else if on the same line and else if on the same line.
除了这里是一种愚蠢的解决方法，对吗？
Except here is kind of a stupid workaround, right?
从某种意义上说，数十年前的人类一次意识到了射击。
In some sense humans decades ago realized, oh, shoot, at one point.
我们已经使用等号进行分配。
We've already used the equal sign for assignment.
我们现在使用什么来实现平等？
What do we use now for equality?
好吧，麻省理工学院忽略了这个问题，只使用了一个等号来表示相等性。
Well, MIT ignored that problem and just used a single equal sign for equality.
发明C语言和后续语言的计算机科学家
Computer scientists inventing C and subsequent languages
比较左右两个值是否相等时
when comparing two values on the left and right for equality
使用两个等号只是因为。
used two equal signs just because.
一个等号是从右到左的赋值。
One equal sign is assignment from right to left.
两个相等的符号是相等的比较。
Two equal signs is equality comparisons.
这两个值相等吗？
Are these two values equal?
但是你知道吗？
But you know what?
这不一定设计得很好。
This is not necessarily well designed.
它是正确的。
It is correct.
从逻辑上讲，我的临时代码和C代码都是正确的，
Logically both my scratch code and my C code is correct,
但是任何人都可以观察为什么代码不是
but can anyone make an observation as to why the code is not
设计得好吗？
necessarily well designed?
我的工作量超出了我的需要。
I'm doing a little more work than I need to.
我可以收紧这段代码。
I could tighten this code up a little bit.
我可以输入少一些的字符并完成
I could type slightly fewer characters and accomplish
同样正确的决策。
the same correct decision making.
在某种意义上，这段代码的设计不是很完美吗？
Any thoughts on in what sense this code is not perfectly designed?
[听不清]，交给你。
[INAUDIBLE], over to you.
听众：是的，所以你两次使用过别的方法。
AUDIENCE: Yeah, so you used else if two times.
你最终可能没有条件就使用了else。
You could have used else in the end and without the condition.
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：很好的观察。
DAVID MALAN: Really good observation.
我使用else两次，这在逻辑上是可以的。
I'm using else if twice, which logically is fine.
该代码是正确的。
This code is correct.
它在询问并回答正确的问题，但请考虑一下。
It's asking and answering the right questions, but consider this.
如果x小于y，则一种可能是在道路上一叉。
If x is less than y, is one possibility, one fork in the road.
否则，如果x大于y是第二个。
Else if x greater than y is the second.
从逻辑上讲，数学世界中唯一的其他可能性是什么？
What's the only other possibility logically in the world of math?
小于或大于或等于。
Either it's less than or greater than or equal to.
没有理由对这一点感到困惑，并明确提出第三个问题。
There's no reason to belabor the point and ask that third question explicitly.
让我们简化代码，并以此更好地进行设计。
Let's simplify the code and marginally better design it as this.
如果你建议的话，就摆脱其他。
Just get rid of the else if as you proposed.
没有那么干净，没有那么短，
Which isn't that much cleaner, isn't that much shorter,
但这确实避免了提出其他问题。
but it does avoid asking an additional question.
因此，现在可能只有两个，而不是问三个问题。
So instead of maybe three questions being asked, now there's only two.
坦率地说，如果你要编写大量代码或一次又一次地执行此操作
And frankly, if you're writing a lot of code or doing this again and again
再一次，这种差异很可能加起来，实际上
and again, that kind of difference might very well add up and indeed
现在给我们一些更好的代码。
give us now some better code.
因此，现在我可以使用这些条件了。
So now that I have the ability to use these conditions.
让我们实际尝试将其转换为程序。
Let's actually try converting this into a program.
让我继续并打开一个程序，
Let me go ahead and open up a program that I
事先写的叫做conditions.c。
wrote in advance called conditions.c.
和往常一样，我在两个文件的开头都有文件。
And I have at the top of the file my two includes as usual.
然后在这里，我几乎可以看到幻灯片上的内容，
And then down here, I have pretty much what we just saw on the slide,
加上两次对get_int的调用或使用。
plus two calls, or uses, of get_int.
然后我只是在这里问这个问题，如果x小于y。
And then I'm just asking this question down here, if x less than y.
否则，如果x大于y。
Else if x greater than y.
否则，请继续执行以下操作。
Else go ahead and do the following.
因此，这只是Scratch翻译的大部分内容的复制粘贴。
So it's just a copy paste pretty much of the Scratch translation.
让我继续做条件，再说条件。c
Let me go ahead and make conditions, which again, conditions.c
是文件名。
is the name of the file.
没有明显的错误。
No apparent mistakes.
因此，让我继续运行点斜杠条件，然后按Enter。
So let me go ahead and run dot slash conditions, Enter.
x将为1，y为2。
And x will be 1, y is 2.
实际上，x小于y。
And indeed, x is less than y.
如果我继续进行此操作，例如这次是10和5。
If I go ahead and run this, this time for instance, with how about 10 and 5.
X大于y。
X is greater than y.
最后，如果我继续使用4和4进行此操作。
And then lastly, if I go ahead and run this with 4 and 4.
X等于y。
X is equal to y.
所以我现在有一个添加条件的C程序
So I now have a C program that is adding conditions
对我来说，这实际上使我能够做出决定并打印出来
for me, which is actually then allowing me to make decisions and print out
一件事可能或另一件事。
one thing potentially or the other.
但是，让我做些更奇特的事情。
But let me do something slightly fancier.
让我继续开放另一个-
Let me go ahead and open up another--
让我从头开始编写此程序。
let me write this program from Scratch.
假设我要编写一个名为“ concept.c”的程序
Suppose I want to write a program called agree.c
激发了像这些愚蠢形式的想法
that stimulates the idea of like these stupid forms
使用某个软件时必须同意的
that you have to agree to when using a piece of software
第一次或类似。
for the first time or the like.
甚至在我不得不按顺序键入yes或y之前删除文件时
Or even when I deleted a file before I had to type in yes or y in order
继续。
to proceed.
让我继续，并在顶部包含cd50.h。
Let me go ahead and include cd50.h at the top.
让我继续前进，并在顶部包含stdio.h。
Let me go ahead and include stdio.h at the top.
然后是我的int main void，它是以前的复制粘贴。
And then my int main void, which is copy paste from before.
现在让我来做。
And now let me do this.
让我继续前进，获取用户的输入，甚至不说一个字。
Let me go ahead and get, not an input from the user, and not even a word.
让我们保持简单，只要求用户输入y或n，是或否。
Let's keep it simple and just ask the user for y or n, for yes or no.
让我继续给自己一个字符，我称它为c。
Let me go ahead and give myself a char, and I'll call it c.
但我可以称呼它为“答案”。
But I could call it anything, like answer.
但是如果我只有一个字符，c似乎是合理的。
But c seems reasonable if I only have one char.
让我继续调用函数get_char。
Let me go ahead and call the function, get_char.
让我问问，你是否同意，问号。
And let me just ask, do you agree, question mark.
然后让我继续进行比较。
And then let me go ahead and compare this.
因此，如果c等于y，那么让我继续打印出同意的反斜杠n。
So if c equals y, then let me go ahead and print out agreed backslash n.
否则，如果c等于n，那么让我继续进行打印，例如，不同意。
Else if c equals n, let me go ahead and print out for instance, not agreed.
现在很不幸，我在这里犯了几个错误，至少有一个
Now unfortunately, I've made a couple of mistakes here that at least one
其中一个可能比另一个更明显。
of which might be a little more obvious than the other.
关于我可能已经引入的错误或错误的任何想法
Any thoughts on what mistakes or bugs I might have introduced already
进入这个程序？
into this program?
有人吗
Anyone at all?
是的，奥利维亚（Olivia）。
Yeah, how about, Olivia.
你怎么认为？
What do you think?
听众：布尔的一件事
AUDIENCE: For one thing that for the Boolean
你确实使用了一个单一的等号而不是双重的。
you did use a single equals sign instead of the double.
戴维·马兰（David MALAN）：很好。
DAVID MALAN: Good.
所以我使用单等号而不是双，所以我需要解决这个问题。
So I use the single equal sign instead of double, so I need to fix that.
还有另一个更细微的错误。
And there's another even more subtle bug.
这是因为C在涉及其数据类型时非常具体。
And this is because C is very specific when it comes to its data types.
一直以来，我一直在对字符串使用双引号，
All this time I've been using double quotes for strings,
但是事实证明，在C中，当
but it turns out in C you have to use single quotes when
你正在比较单个字符。
you're comparing individual characters.
所以我要去这里，只更改y和n周围的引号
So I'm going to go in here and change only the quotes around y and n
用单引号引起来。
to be single quotes.
为什么？
Why?
因为我现在正在处理字符的世界。
Because I'm now dealing with the world of chars.
字符是单个字符，例如y或n。
Chars are individual characters like y or n.
当你谈论角色时，
And when you are talking about characters,
你需要像这样逐字地引用它们。
you need to quote them literally like this.
变量名c不需要用引号引起来。
The variable name, c, doesn't need to be quoted.
但是y和n确实需要用引号引起来。
But y and n do need to be quoted.
但是我不需要更改文件中的其他任何引号
But I don't need to change any of my other quotes in the file
因为这些仍然是实际的短语或句子的文本字符串。
because those are still strings of text that is actual phrases or sentences.
因此，让我继续尝试运行以达成共识。
So let me go ahead and try running make agree.
编译就可以了。
It compiles OK.
让我继续并运行点斜线表示同意。
Let me go ahead and run dot slash agree.
我同意吗？
Do I agree?
让我继续输入y。
Let me go ahead and type in y.
同意，我喜欢那样。
Agreed, I like that.
因此，让我尝试一下，不。
So let me try n, no.
不，我同意。
Not I agreed.
我省略了一个反斜杠n，所以让我来修复一下
And I left off a backslash n, so let me fix that real quick just
为了保持一致性。
for consistency.
让我重新编译我的程序，并假装从未发生过。
Let me recompile my program and pretend that never happened.
但是，现在让我非常合理地做到这一点。
But let me very reasonably now do this.
点斜线表示同意。
Dot slash agree.
我要同意。
I want to agree.
是的，资本y。
And yes, capital y.
没事
Huh, nothing happened.
那n大写N呢？
What about n, capital N?
没啥事儿。
Nothing happened.
但是该程序仍然有效。
But the program still works.
如果我做小写的话，它可以工作。
If I do lower case it works.
如果我在这里做小写的话，那就行了。
And if I do lower case there it works.
发生什么了？
So what's going on?
好吧，再一次，计算机只会带你一字不漏。
Well, again, the computer's only going to take you literally.
即使我们人类可能是，哦，这很好。
And even though we humans might be, oh, it's fine.
它是大写或小写。
It's upper case or a lower case.
你必须更加明确。
You have to be more explicit.
因此，我们可以提出以下两个问题。
So we can ask two questions as follows.
如果c等于我们可以做其他事情
We could do something like else if c equals
等于单引号中的资本Y。
equals capital Y in single quotes.
你可以再次想象，说出这样的同意。
You could imagine, again, saying agreed like this.
但是就像上周我开始复制和粘贴Scratch块一样，
But just like last week when I started copying and pasting Scratch blocks,
那可能不是很好的设计。
that's probably not very good design.
类似地，此代码块（第11至14行）几乎与第7行相同
Similarly, this block of code, lines 11 through 14, is almost identical to 7
到10
through 10.
让我们摆脱其中之一。
Let's just get rid of one of them.
让我们看看我们是否无法融合这些想法。
And let's see if we can't combine these thoughts.
让我表达一下，如果c等于y，或者c等于等于资本Y。
Let me express if c equals equals y, or c equals equals capital Y.
实际上，你可以使用此竖线
And indeed, you can use this vertical bar
运算符，这是逻辑或运算符，
operator, which is the logical or operator,
并同时说两个问题。
and actually say two questions at once.
事实证明，你可以使用and的概念来做到这一点，
It turns out you can do this with the notion of and, a logical
并使用＆符号。
and, by using ampersand ampersand.
还有更多时间。
More on those another time.
但是两条竖线等同于说，
But two vertical bars is the equivalent of just saying,
如果是在左侧还是在右侧
if this on the left or this on the right.
现在，如果我使用make保存并重新编译程序，
And now if I save and recompile the program with make
同意，点斜线也同意。
agree, and dot slash agree.
你会看到我可以以小写形式输入y或以大写形式键入Y，
You'll see that I can type in y in lowercase, or Y in uppercase,
现在就可以了。
and now it works.
再说一次，添加
So again, it would have been correct to just add
如果另一个，如果另一个。
another else if and another else if.
但是同样，这不是必须的，因为我可以将这些想法结合起来
But again, not necessary because I can combine these thoughts
并使我的程序设计得更好。
and make my program better designed.
还要注意，所有这些时间我一直都很虔诚
And notice too, all this time I've been very religiously
每次缩进花括号时都会缩进。
indenting every time I'm inside of curly braces.
每次我有一个if条件或else if时都缩进。
Indenting every time I have an if condition or an else if.
因此，我也希望表现出良好的风格美学。
So I'm manifesting, hopefully, good style aesthetics as well.
好的。
All right.
好吧，现在让我们考虑一下我们有没有能力
Well, now let's consider that we have the ability not
仅用于表达条件，但这些称为循环的东西又如何呢？
only to express conditions, but how about also these things called loops.
好吧，事实证明，在Scratch中，我们有非常简单的循环。
Well, turns out in Scratch we had very straightforward loops.
永远执行以下操作。
Do the following forever.
C有点笨。
C is a little clunkier.
C语言中没有永远的关键字，但是我们可以按照以下方式模仿这个想法。
There's no forever keyword in C, but we can mimic this idea as follows.
在C语言中永远翻译的最接近方法
The closest way to translate forever in C
实际上是在说一句，哪种具有正确的英语语义。
is actually to say while, which kind of has the right semantics in English.
就像，虽然确实如此，但要这样做，
Like, while something is the case, do this,
但你必须更加明确。
but you have to be even more explicit.
你不能只说一会儿，然后再说printf，世界。
You can't just say while and then say printf hello, world.
在C中发现，虽然类似于条件，
It turns out in C that while, similar to a condition,
一直在问一个问题，以决定是否继续。
is constantly asking a question to decide whether or not to continue.
再次非常类似于具有其自己的布尔表达式的条件。
Very similar, again, to a condition with its own Boolean expression.
因此，在C语言中使用while时，你必须在while一词后加上括号，
So with while in C, you have to have parentheses after the word while,
并且你必须在这些括号中提出一个问题。
and you have to ask a question in those parentheses.
你必须说类似x大于y，x小于y，
You have to say something like, x greater than y, x less than y,
或类似的东西。
or the like.
但这在某种意义上来说是一个极端的情况
But this is a bit of a corner case in the sense
如果你想永远做某事，
that if you want to do something forever,
谁在乎问题是什么。
who cares what the question is.
你只希望答案始终是肯定的。
You just want the answer always to be yes.
或用计算机术语来说，始终是真实的。
Or in computer terms, always to be true.
最直截了当地表达真实的方式
And the most blunt way to express true always
字面上写的是“真”。
is literally to write the word true.
因此，即使这看起来有些怪异，但在C语言中
So even though this looks a little weird, this in C
就是你故意诱导我们做些什么
is how you deliberately induce what we'll
调用一个永不停止的无限循环，因为根据定义始终为true
call an infinite loop that never stops because true is always by definition
真的。
true.
你甚至不必问一个更复杂的问题。
You don't even have to ask a more complicated question.
你可以放置小于号，大于号等。
You could put a less than sign, a greater than sign, or the like.
但是，如果你只希望某些事情永远发生，
But if you just want something to happen forever,
这是永远表达某些东西的最规范的方法。
this is the most canonical way to express something forever.
好吧，如果你想有限次地做某事怎么办？
Well, what if you want to do something finitely many times?
好吧，我们也可以在C语言中使用
Well, we can do that in C as well using what's
将被称为for循环或while循环。
going to be called a for loop, or a while loop.
好吧，让我们依次考虑这两个方面。
Well, let's consider both of these in turn.
因此，如果我想做50次操作，那是最机械的手动方式
So if I want to do something 50 times, the most mechanical manual way
我能想到的就像只是依靠我的手指，对不对？
I can think of is like just count on my fingers, right?
就像一，二，三一样，一直到50。
Like, one, two, three, all the way up to 50 somehow.
或我手上最多10个。
Or 10 maximally on my hands.
那么，如何在C语言中执行有限次的操作呢？
So how can I do something finitely many times in C?
好吧，我可以使用变量。
Well, I have at my disposal variables.
因此，让我给自己一个称为计数器的变量。
So let me give myself a variable called counter.
将其初始化为零分号。
Initialize it to zero semicolon.
数据类型将为int，因为我只是
And the data type will be int, because I just
需要像我的手指一样数数。
need to count much like on my fingers.
但是你知道吗？
But you know what?
Counter有点冗长。
Counter is a little verbose.
程序员在频繁计数时，从零开始递增计数
Programmers whenever they're counting frequently, just counting up from zero
然后，他们通常只会将i用作整数，或将c用作字符，
on up, they'll often just use i for integer, or c for character,
或s表示字符串。
or s for string.
你不想总是在你的代码中这样做。
You don't want to do that always in your code.
有时最好用更具描述性的名称来命名变量，
It's sometimes better for your variables to be more descriptively named,
但是对于一个愚蠢的变量，它只会从零开始计数，
but for a stupid variable that's just going to count from zero on up,
让我们保持简单并称之为i。
let's just keep it simple and call it i.
我现在可以再次做一会儿循环，但是现在我
I can now do a while loop again, but now I
不得不问一个问题，因为我不想让它永远运行下去。
have to ask a question because I don't want this running forever.
我希望它运行50次。
I want it running 50 times.
我可以问什么问题？
What question could I ask?
好吧，我为什么不检查一下。
Well, why don't I just check.
虽然我还不到50岁。
While i is less than 50.
这就好比数了50个手指。
So it's like counting up on 50 fingers.
让我从零开始计数，但不等于i等于50。
Let me start at zero and count up to, but not through i equals 50.
因此，只要我小于50，请执行以下操作。
So so long as i is less than 50, do the following.
我要怎么办
What do I want to do?
我想继续打印你好，世界。
I want to keep printing out hello, world.
你好，世界。
Hello, world.
但是我还没有完成。
But I'm not done.
因为在该循环的每个迭代中，在该循环的每个循环中，
Because on every iteration of this loop, on every cycle of this loop,
我需要在数学上再做一件事。
I need to do one more thing mathematically.
我需要添加另一个手指，添加另一个手指。
I need to add another finger, add another finger.
换句话说，我需要在i上加一个。
Or in other words, I need to add one to i.
因此，让我继续进行设置，使我等于现在的状态，再加上一个。
So let me go ahead and set i equal to whatever it is now, plus one.
但同样，我们有一些语法糖
But again, we have some syntactic sugar just
使它更清洁，更紧密。
to make this a little cleaner, a little tighter.
我可以做到我加等于一。
I could do i plus equals one.
或更简洁地说，我加加。
Or even more succinctly, i plus plus.
因此，即使比Scratch实施起来更令人讨厌
So even though this is way more annoying to implement than in Scratch
麻省理工学院只是在为你提供所需的内容，在C语言中，我们拥有所有的构建基块
where MIT just gives you what you want, in C we have all of the building blocks
现在具有变量和循环以实现重复的概念
now with variables and with loops to implement the notion of repeating
一些有限的次数。
some finite number of times.
但是还有另一种方法可以做到这一点。
But there's another way to do this.
正如你可能发现问题集为零，
And as you might have discovered with problem set zero,
在Scratch中有不同的方法可以实现相同的目标。
there's different ways to achieve the same goals in Scratch.
同样在C语言中，我可以做到这一点。
Similarly in C, I could do this.
我可以从1开始数到50。
I could just start counting at one and count up through 50.
因此键盘上没有大于或等于符号的键，
So there's no greater than or equal sign key on your keyboard,
最有可能，或小于或等于。
most likely, or less than or equal to.
因此，与其他语言一样，在C语言中，你仅使用两个字符。
So in C, as with other languages, you just use two characters.
你执行的操作少于符号，后跟等号。
You do less than sign followed by the equals sign.
表示小于或等于。
And that expresses less than or equal to.
所以这也是正确的。
So this is also correct.
如果我从一开始数，我需要数到50。
If I start counting at one I need to count through 50.
你可以这样做。
You can do this.
不要这样
Don't do this.
这是非常规的。
This is unconventional.
就像程序员通常一样，
And like programmers will conventionally,
上周开始的时候，我们总是从零开始
per last week when we started always counting from zero with all
灯泡熄灭，它们将从零开始，最多计数50。
the light bulbs off, they'll instead start at zero and count up to 50.
这将使你隐式获得零到49。
Which gives you zero through 49 implicitly.
这样做，而不是那样。
So do this, not that.
但这确实表明你可以解决
But this does speak to the fact that you can solve
问题有很多不同的方式。
problems in so many different ways.
从根本上讲，还有另一种方法。
There's another way, fundamentally, too.
我们可以从50减少到零。
We could start counting from 50 down to zero.
唯一的区别是我们必须做我减去减号而不是我加号。
The only difference being we have to do i minus minus instead of i plus plus.
同样，这是解决同一问题的三种不同方法。
So again, that's three different ways to solve the same problem.
再一次，你将开始拥有正确的直觉和肌肉记忆，
And again, you'll start to have the right instincts and muscle memory,
而且你还将开始在讲座代码中看到常见的模式，即TF
and you'll also start to see common patterns in lecture code, your TF
或在线的助教代码，书籍和参考资料。
or teaching assistants code, books and references online.
尽管所有这些都倾向于有做事的方法
There just tend to be the ways to do things even though all of these
还是对的。
are still right.
好的。
All right.
这里还有另一种循环方法。
One more approach to loops here.
事实证明，还有另外一个循环结构，它有点神秘，
It turns out there's another loop construct that's a little more cryptic,
它被称为for循环。
and it's called a for loop.
它使你可以自动化-或更确切地说，
And it allows you to automate-- or rather,
使你可以更简洁地表达所有这些步骤。
allows you to express all of those steps a little more concisely.
所以对于printf大家好，世界将使我们离印刷更近一步
So for printf hello, world is going to get us one step closer to printing
你好，世界50次。
hello, world 50 times.
但是for语句和while语句一样，
But the for statement, just like the while statement,
后面附有必要的括号，
comes with necessary parentheses after it,
但这一次你可以在括号中放入更多内容。
but this time you can put more stuff in the parentheses.
这不仅是布尔表达式。
It's not just a Boolean expression.
首先，括号中的第一件事
First, the first thing in the parentheses
你可以将想要的任何变量初始化为某个值。
is you can initialize any variable you want to some value.
我可能会说相遇等于零，或更简洁地说，
I might say encounter equals zero, or more succinctly,
int我等于零分号。
int i equals zero semicolon.
但是for循环的外观有点时髦。
But the way the for loop looks, it's a little funky.
你可以在一行上执行多项操作。
You can do multiple things on one line.
括号内的第二件事是for循环
The second thing inside of the parentheses to a for loop
是你要一次又一次地检查的条件。
is a condition that you want to check again and again and again.
还有for循环括号中的最后一件事
And the last thing in the parentheses of a for loop
是更新，还是递增或递减
is an update, or an incrementation or decrementation
由此你可以做到我等于我加一。
whereby you can do i equals i plus one.
或更确切地说，让我们做我加等于1的事情。
Or rather, let's just do i plus equals one.
或更简洁地说，我加加。
Or even more succinctly, i plus plus.
这也许是最传统的方式
This is perhaps the most conventional way
用C和其他编程语言执行50次操作，
in C and in other programming languages to do something 50 times,
或有限次数。
or a finite number of times.
到目前为止，我们所看到的情况与众不同。
It's different looking from the things we've seen thus far.
在怪异的地方有分号。
There's semicolons in weirder places.
括号中还有更多内容。
There's more stuff in parentheses.
再次重申，你将全面发展肌肉记忆。
So again, you'll develop the muscle memory overall.
但是现在，只要意识到这就是说，将i初始化为零即可。
But for now just realize this says, initialize i to zero.
检查条件。
Check the condition.
如果我的打印量少于50，则为世界。
And if i is less than 50 print hello, world.
然后更新我。
Then update i.
然后检查条件。
Then check the condition.
如果小于50，请打个招呼，世界。
If it's less than 50, print hello, world.
然后增加i。
Then increment i.
然后检查条件。
Then check the condition.
然后，如果不是那么，请打个招呼，世界。
Then if it's less then, print hello, world.
因此，变量的初始化只发生一次。
So the initialization of the variable happens once.
一切都一次又一次地发生
Everything else happens again and again and again
直到完成此操作约50次为止。
until you've done this some 50 times.
好的。
All right.
因此，有了这些构建基块，就可以了
So with those building blocks, that's kind of it
我们将Scratch转换为C。现在开始
for our translation of Scratch into C. Let's now start
在实践中建立一些更有趣的程序
to build up some more interesting programs in practice
例如抽象。
for instance, abstraction.
因此，回想一下，这就是解决问题的原则
So abstraction, recall, was this problem solving principle
从而可以简化其他更复杂的细节。
whereby you can simplify otherwise more complicated details.
抽象是在更复杂的细节之上的简化
And abstraction is a simplification on top of more complicated details
或程序员可能会说的实现细节。
or implementation details as a programmer might say.
例如，让我继续写
So for instance, let me go ahead and write
这里的程序叫做喵，类似于上周，但是这次是C语言。
a program here called meow, similar to last week, but this time in C.
为了让猫在文字上发出喵声，
And in order to make a cat meow textually,
让我在顶部给自己stdio.h。
let me give myself stdio.h at the top.
Int main void在这里。
Int main void down here.
同样，我在一个名为meow.c的文件中。
Again, I'm in a file called meow.c.
而且我包括了stdio.h和int main void。
And I've included stdio.h and int main void.
现在，我要继续做这样的事情。
And now I'm going to go ahead and just do something like this.
Printf，引用反引号，“喵”，反斜杠n。
Printf, quote unquote, "meow", backslash n.
我希望这只猫在文本上发出三声喵叫。
And I want this cat to meow textually three times.
让我保存该文件。
Let me save that file.
发出喵声。
Make meow.
好的。
All right.
现在，点斜线喵。
Now, dot slash meow.
喵，喵，喵都在文字上。
Meow, meow, meow all in text.
所以不像上周的那只猫那样可爱或漂亮，
So not nearly as cute or pretty as the one with the cat last week,
但这是正确的。
but it's correct.
但这不是很好的设计，对不对？
But it's not very well designed, right?
因为我在重复自己。
Because I'm repeating myself.
我从字面上复制和粘贴，这些都是不好的本能。
I literally copied and pasted, and those are bad instincts.
但是现在，我们可以使用循环来做事了。
But now we have the ability to do things with loops.
因此，让我实际删除该功能的这一部分。
So let me actually delete this part of the function.
让我尝试从前面的示例中记住。
And let me try to remember from the example before.
如果我想做三遍，可以使用while循环，
If I want to do something three times I could use a while loop,
但这感觉像是一堆代码。
but that felt like a bunch of lines of code.
我来做
Let me do this.
整数i等于零。
Int i equals zero.
我不到三岁。
i less than three.
我加加。
i plus plus.
如此神秘，但这再次是事实上的做某事的方式
So cryptic, but this, again, is the de facto way of doing something
有限的次数。
a finite number of times.
初始化一些变量，例如i到零，检查条件，
Initialize some variable, like i to zero, check a condition,
并不断增加变量一次又一次
and keep incrementing your variable again and again
因此它总共执行了多次。
so that it executes a total of that many times.
现在，让我继续打印并喵喵声-
Now, let me go ahead and printf meow--
柔和-里面发出喵呜声。
mellow-- meow on the inside.
让我继续，让喵喵重新编译喵喵。
Let me go ahead and recompile meow by make meow.
让我点点斜线喵叫声，瞧。
Let me dot slash meow, and voila.
现在可以说该程序的设计更好。
Now the program is arguably better designed.
但是，让我进一步迈出这一步。
But let me take this one step further.
回想一下上周的轨迹不仅要实现喵
Recall that the trajectory last week was to not only implement meow
具有更好的设计，而无需重复自己，从而使用了循环。
with better design, without repeating yourself, thereby using a loop.
但是请记住，我们介绍了
But remember we introduced the abstraction that
是一个叫做喵的定制拼图。
was a custom puzzle piece called meow.
因此，在C语言中，我们也有能力实现自己的功能。
So in C, turns out we have the ability to make our own functions as well.
语法需要一点时间来适应，但让我继续
And the syntax is going to take a little getting used to, but let me go ahead
并做到这一点。
and do this.
让我在这里摆脱我的printf。
Let me get rid of my printf here.
在文件的底部-实际上，在文件的顶部
And at the bottom of my file-- actually, at the top of my file
我将继续输入void meow void。
I'm going to go ahead and type void meow void.
对于今天来说，这是非常神秘的，但是，再次
Which is very cryptic for today, but again, this
可以用作样板，现在复制粘贴。
is fine to be boilerplate, copy pasted for now.
让我继续，然后在这里打印一下。
Let me go ahead and just printf meow here.
即使我们今天没有解释也不会解释
Even though we haven't explained and won't explain today
这个关键字void意味着什么，我在第三到第六行中做了什么
what this keyword void means, what I've done in lines three through six
是创建我自己的自定义函数。
is create my own custom function.
C没有附带名为meow的函数。
C does not come with a function called meow.
CS50的库没有附带名为meow的函数。
CS50's library does not come with a function called meow.
但是现在感谢我，存在一个功能
But now thanks to me, there exists a function
叫喵，生活中唯一的目的就是打印喵。
called meow whose sole purpose in life is just to print out meow.
但是现在最酷的是在这里
But what's cool about this now is that down here, just
就像上周使用Scratch一样，我现在可以调用一个名为meow的函数。
like with Scratch last week, I can now call a function called meow.
而且我的代码更具可读性，因为它宁可
And my code is a little more readable because it rather
仅通过函数名称来说明它的作用。
says what it does by just by way of the function's name.
现在让我继续进行编译。
And let me go ahead now and compile this.
发出喵声。
Make meow.
到目前为止，一切都很好。
So far so good.
点斜线喵，它似乎工作正常。
Dot slash meow, and it seems to work OK.
但我不喜欢我已经实行喵的事实
But I don't love the fact that I've implemented meow
在文件的顶部。
at the top of the file.
没什么大不了的。
It's not a big deal.
按照约定，我们通常将自定义函数放在文件的底部。
By convention we'll typically put custom functions at the bottom of the file.
为什么？
Why?
只是因为当一个程序员，或者在我们的情况下，
Only because when a programmer, or in our case,
一位老师想从上到下理解你的代码。
a teaching fellow wants to understand your code from top to bottom.
放置主程序（主要功能）只是人类的惯例，
It's just human convention to put the main program, the main function rather,
在文件的顶部。
at the top of your file.
问题是，当我这样做时，我会为自己创建一个问题。
The problem is when I do this, I'm going to have created a problem for myself.
当我跑步时请立即发出声音。
When I run make meow now, darn it.
生成了两个错误，因此有几个错误需要解决。
Two errors generated, and so there's a couple of bugs to be solved.
但是首先，布莱恩，这个小组的一个问题。
But first, Brian, a question from the group.
布莱恩·于（Brian Yu）：聊天中出现一个问题，即为什么
BRIAN YU: There was a question that came in from the chat about why
例如，在第五行，你没有
it is that on line five, for example, you don't have
for循环末尾的分号。
a semicolon at the end of the for loop.
在第11行，你没有分号
And on line 11 you don't have a semicolon
在函数名称的末尾。
at the end of the function name.
那么为什么有些行最后需要分号，而另一些行却不需要分号呢？
So why do some lines need semicolons at the end, but other lines don't?
大卫·马兰（David MALAN）：很好的问题。
DAVID MALAN: Really good question.
为什么其中一些行没有分号，而另一些却没有分号？
Why do some of these lines not have semicolons, but others do?
坦率地说，简短的答案（不要被嘲笑）仅是因为。
The short answer, not to be glib, is honestly just because.
语言的设计方式是你通常应该
The way the language was designed was that you should generally
表达动词或动作或功能时完成你的想法
finish your thoughts when expressing verbs or actions or functions
与分号。
with semicolons.
例如，在printf之后，我们已经看到了这一点。
And we've seen that after printf for instance.
喵喵之后，我们刚刚看到了这一点。
We've just seen that after meow.
但是，当你使用其他编程结构时，
However, when you're using other programming constructs,
像循环或像自定义函数一样，那里没有分号。
like loops or like custom functions, you don't have semicolons there.
为什么？
Why?
几年前，有些人才决定我们
Some humans years ago just decided that we
在那些地方不需要分号。
don't need semicolons in those places.
这是需要一段时间才能发展肌肉的事情之一
And this is one of those things that it will take a while to develop the muscle
记忆和识别这些东西去向的心理模型
memory and the mental model for recognizing where those things go
而且不要。
and don't.
但到目前为止，我们唯一见过分号的地方
But thus far the only places we've seen semicolons
在函数的末尾，例如此处的喵和printf。
are at the ends of functions, like meow and printf here.
现在，很奇怪的是，在for循环的括号内。
And now, admittedly weirdly, inside of the parentheses for the for loop.
但是同样，当解决问题时，首先要研究的是第一个实验，依此类推，
But again, when tackling problem sets one and the first lab and so forth,
你经常会想回头看幻灯片中的此类示例
you'll often want to refer back to examples like these in the slides
以及本节中的参考，以便你可以
and the references in your section so that you can
围绕这些模式全神贯注。
wrap your mind around these patterns.
因此，让我现在继续解决我似乎在这里造成的两个问题。
So let me go ahead now and solve the two problems I seem to have created here.
这有点不明显，但是让人想起我们以前看到的内容。
It's a little non obvious, but it's reminiscent of what we've seen before.
函数喵的隐式声明在C99中无效。
Implicit declaration of function meow is invalid in C99.
C99指的是我们使用的1999年版本的C语言，
C99 is referring to the 1999 version of C the language we're using,
但是它只是变得令人困惑，C在眼前。
but it's just getting confused, C is right now.
好吧，为什么呢？
Well, why is that?
好吧，让我在这里向上滚动，然后我直言不讳地指出C，
Well, let me scroll up here and let me make the point that frankly C,
反过来，我的编译器也不是那么亮。
and in turn my compiler, they're not that bright.
就像，他们只会按照我告诉他们的明确去做。
Like, they're only going to do what I tell them to do explicitly.
现在的问题是，当编译器读取我的代码时
And the problem at the moment is that when the compiler reads my code
从上到下，向左或向右，直到第11行
from top to bottom, left or right, it is not until line 11
喵功能甚至存在。
the meow function even exists.
但是，我目前正在尝试在第7行使用该喵函数。
However, I am trying on line seven at the moment to use that meow function.
所以坦率地说，我的编译器不知道
So my compiler, frankly, just doesn't know
叫声是因为它以后不必叫声了。
what meow is because it hasn't gotten to meow later.
而且编译器不够聪明
And the compiler is not smart enough, or not
用户友好到足以先阅读所有内容，然后再决定
user friendly enough to read everything first and then decide
如果有问题。
if there's a problem.
它只会从上到下阅读一次，
It's only going to read it once through top to bottom,
遇到问题时，它会大吼大叫。
and it's going to yell at you the moment it encounters the problem.
所以解决方案很简单，移动功能
So the solution to this is quite simply, move the function
到文件顶部。
to the top of your file.
但是同样，这最终会变得令人讨厌，因为那时你
But again, that just gets annoying eventually because then you
必须去钓鱼才能实现你的主要功能
have to go fishing for your main function which might
在文件中向下排数十行。
be dozens of lines down in the file.
或者还有另一种方法，我们也会在适当的时候对此进行解释。
Or there's another way, and we'll explain this in due time too.
但是，你也可以仅复制自定义函数的第一行。
But you can also copy the very first line only of your custom function.
将其放在main上方文件的顶部。
Put it at the top of your file above main.
然后，对布莱恩的问题以分号结束。
And then, to Brian's question end that with a semicolon.
所以这很奇怪。
So this is weird.
这就是通常所说的原型，仅是一个提示。
This is what's generally known as a prototype, which is a hint only.
这是一种告诉编译器在那里的聪明方法
It's sort of a clever way of telling the compiler there
将存在一个名为喵的函数，但还没有。
will exist a function called meow, but just not yet.
但是知道会的。
But know that it will.
这只是一种解决方法，一种常见的解决方法，
And it's just kind of a workaround, a common workaround,
对于那个特定的问题。
for that particular problem.
好的。
All right.
因此，让我继续进行另一项更改，在此进行另一项更改。
So let me go ahead and make one more change, one more change here.
假设我想真正结束这个喵的例子
Suppose that I want to really finish off this meow example
就像我们在Scratch中所做的一样。
just like we did in Scratch.
因此，我们还允许喵将一些喵作为输入。
Whereby we also allow meow to take some number of meows as input.
所以我不想在我的主要功能中再有这个for循环。
So I don't want to have this for loop anymore in my main function.
假设我只想在主要功能中说三声。
Suppose I just want to be able to say, meow three, inside of my main function.
因此，三个是喵功能的输入。
Three thereby being the input to the meow function.
现在，就像上周一样，我现在需要更改自定义功能，如下所示。
I now need to change my custom function, just like I did last week, as follows.
事实证明-以及未来几周的更多内容-
It turns out-- and more on this in the weeks to come--
第11行这里提到的void表示返回值或输出
that this mention a void here on line 11 refers to the return value or output
此功能。
of this function.
长话短说，我今天自定义的喵函数没有返回值。
Long story short, my custom meow function today has no return value.
它本身不输出任何东西，而是仅输出
It doesn't output anything per se, it instead only
具有在屏幕上视觉打印的副作用。
has a side effect of printing visually on the screen.
但是它确实有输入。
But it does have an input.
如果你想在C语言中使用输入或参数，
And if you want to function in C to take input or arguments,
你可以从字面上做类似你想要的类型的名称
you can literally do something like, the name of the type you want
以及所需变量的名称。
and the name of the variable that you want.
因此，假设我想让喵叫输入一些数字，我们将其称为n。
So suppose I want meow to take as input some number, we'll call it n.
我想循环使用该数字。
And I want to use that number in a loop.
然后，我可以做这样的事情。
I could then do something like this.
因为int我为零，所以我小于n，我为加号。
For int i gets zero, i is less than n, i plus plus.
然后，我可以用花括号将我的printf包围起来。
I can then surround my printf with curly braces.
现在请注意，就像上周我对喵的最终实现一样，
And now notice just like last week with my final implementation of meow,
我的自定义函数可以接受输入，如括号所示。一世
my custom function can take input as denoted by the parentheses. i
本身没有输出，这就是为什么我在这里留下空白。
doesn't have output per se, that's why I'm leaving void here.
但是，再次，我们将在以后详细解释void。
But again, we'll explain void more in detail down the road.
但是现在我在for循环中使用了该输入。
But now I'm using that input inside of the for loop.
因此，即使这是C语言的新实现，
So even though this is a new implementation in C,
我正在使用相同的构建基块。
I'm using the same building blocks.
我正在像以前一样使用for循环，但不是硬编码三个，
I'm using a for loop like before, but instead of hard coding three,
或50个像我之前做的那样，现在我实际上要继续
or 50 like I did earlier, now I'm actually going to go ahead and just
插件，就像Scratch一样允许我做同样的事情。
plug-in that variable just like Scratch allowed me to do as well.
好吧，如果我想做更出色的事情该怎么办。
Well, what if I want to do something even fancier.
你知道吗？
You know what?
让我继续执行此操作。
Let me go ahead and do this.
假设我们要从用户那里获得输入，
Suppose that we want to get input from the user,
但我们确实希望他们提供特定类型的输入。
but we really want them to provide a specific type of input.
让我继续介绍另一种类型的循环。
Let me go ahead and introduce one other type of loop.
我将继续从档案库中获取代码
And this one I'm going to go ahead and grab from my archives, the code
我今天带来的
that I brought with me today.
我要继续复制一个名为positive.c的文件，
And I'm going to go ahead and copy over a file called positive.c,
这将坚持要求用户给我一个积极的价值。
which is going to insist that the user give me a positive value.
这也可以在课程的网站上找到。
So this too is on the course's website.
让我来介绍一下我已经编写的代码。
And let me just walk us through code that I already wrote.
在文件的顶部，我包括一些现在很熟悉的标题
Here at the top of my file, I'm including some now familiar header
文件。
files.
在这里，我包括一个原型。
And down here, I'm including a prototype.
这暗示了将要调用的函数，
That is a hint for a function that's going to be called,
很简单，get_positive_int。
quite simply, get_positive_int.
所以这是一个只会得到正整数的函数。
So this is a function that's only going to get a positive integer.
然后在我的主要功能中，请注意我将使用此功能。
Then in my main function, notice I'm going to use this.
我将在第10行获得一个名为i的变量，
I'm going to get a variable called i on line 10,
并且我将从用户那里得到积极的理解。
and I'm going to get a positive int from the user.
然后我将要打印出来。
And then I'm just going to print it out.
但是现在有趣的是，我有了这个附加的抽象。
But what's interesting now is I have this additional abstraction.
CS50库没有附带名为get_positive_int的函数，
The CS50 library does not come with a function called get_positive_int,
但是它确实带有一个名为get_int的函数。
but it does come with a function called get_int.
并注意我在第15和24行之间所做的事情。
And notice what I've done down here between lines 15 and 24.
在这里，我声明了一个名为get_positive_int的函数，
Down here I've declared a function called get_positive_int,
并注意这是我自己的自定义函数名称。
and notice that's my own custom function name.
它不需要任何输入，只是从人类那里得到一个正整数。
It doesn't take any inputs, it just gets a positive integer from the human.
但是现在请注意，它确实具有返回值。
But now notice it does have a return value.
以前我用空这个词来表示没有输入
Previously I used the word void to say the absence of input
或没有输出。
or the absence of output.
在这里我使用的是说，没有输入。
Here I'm using it's still to say, no inputs.
它只是总是得到一个正整数。
It just always gets a positive int.
但是我在此自定义函数名称的左侧说的是int
But I'm saying int on the left hand side of this custom function's name
因为此功能确实有输出。
because this function does have output.
输出将是什么？
What is the output going to be?
我们将在第17行注意到这一点，我给自己一个变量，并将其称为n。
We'll, notice here on line 17, I give myself a variable and I call it n.
然后，我今天有了C的最后一个新功能，这个循环称为
Then I have one final new feature of C today, this loop which is called,
不是while循环，而是do while循环。
not a while loop, but a do while loop.
do while循环与while循环几乎相同，
A do while loop is almost the same as a while loop,
除了在检查条件之前先盲目地做一件事。
except that it blindly does one thing first before checking a condition.
因此请注意，我将执行以下操作。
So notice here I'm going to do the following.
使用此提示（正整数）调用get_int，
Call get_int with this prompt, positive integer,
然后将返回值存储到名为n的变量中。
and then store the return value into the variable called n.
然后在这里，注意我说的是n小于一。
Then down here, notice I'm saying while n less than one.
所以这是一种怪异的语法，但是如果从数学上讲
So this is kind of a weird syntax, but if mathematically I
希望用户给我一个正整数，
want the user to give me a positive integer,
从技术上讲，这与希望用户给我一个整数是一样的
that's technically the same thing as wanting the user to give me an integer
并确保它不少于一个。
and just make sure that it is not less than one.
因为如果小于1，则为零或负一，或者为负二，
Because if it's less than one, it's zero or negative one or negative two,
那显然不是正整数。
that's obviously not a positive integer.
那么我该如何用代码表达这一点呢？
So how can I express this in code?
现在唯一的新事物是事实
The only new thing at the moment now is the fact
存在这个叫做do while的东西。
that there exists this thing called do while.
再说一次，“做一会儿”的价值在于你至少会做某事
And again, the value of do while is that you will do things at least
一次，然后检查条件。
once and then check a condition.
while循环首先检查条件，然后执行一些操作。
A while loop checks the condition first and then does something instead.
不过，在这种情况下，这就是我想要的。
This is what I want in this case, though.
我想做这个。
I want to do this.
从用户获取一个整数，提示他们输入一个正整数。
Get an integer from the user prompting them for a positive integer.
那么当n小于1时，如果人类
Then while n is less than one-- so if the human
输入零，或负一，或负二，我要怎么做？
typed in zero, or negative one, or negative two, what do I want to do?
同一件事一次又一次。
The same thing again and again and again.
所以它读起来很语法。
So it reads rather grammatically.
当n小于1时，请执行以下操作。
Do the following while n is less than one.
然后最后，这里唯一的新行是返回n。
And then lastly, and the only other new line here is return n.
这是程序实际上可以向你返回一些值的方式。
This is the way that a program can actually return some value to you.
它可以让你退还价值，而不是通过在屏幕上打印出来，
It can hand you back a value, not by printing it on the screen,
而不是从猫的嘴里听到或听到它的声音。
not by saying it audibly or visually from a cat's mouth.
从某种意义上说，它返回了它
It returns it in the sense that what's being returned here
是n，它是与该函数的输出匹配的整数。
is n, which is an integer that matches the output of this function.
为什么这有用？
Why is this useful?
好吧，让我们向上滚动。
Well let's scroll back up.
现在让我们想当然地认为我们存在get_positive_int函数。
Let's now take for granted that we get_positive_int function exists.
现在注意我们如何在main中使用它。
And now notice how we can use it in main.
我在右边叫get_positive_int。
I call get_positive_int on the right.
它返回一个我声称是整数类型的值。
It returns a value I claim that is of type integer.
我将返回值存储在名为i的变量的左侧。
I'm storing that return value on the left in this variable called i.
然后我打印出我。
And then I'm printing out i.
就像上周在Scratch中的喵喵例子一样，
And just like last week with the meow example in Scratch,
现在我已经实现了get_positive_int，
now that I have implemented get_positive_int,
有点看不见，忘了。
it sort of out of sight, out of mind.
我知道这是可以做到的，我可以抽象出来
I know that it can be done, and I can abstract away
底层的实现细节只需通过其名称调用即可。
the underlying implementation details by just calling it by its name.
但我想指出一件事
But there's one weird thing that I do want to point out
关于这些实施细节。
about these implementation details.
为什么我在这里宣布n？
Why did I declare n out here?
每隔一次我创建一个变量，就完成了这一步。
Every other time I've created a variable, I've done this.
事实证明，我们一直很幸运，
It turns out we've been getting lucky this whole time,
每当我声明变量时，从技术上讲
and any time I've declared variables they've technically
在花括号之间。
been in between curly braces.
属于主要功能或其他功能的花括号
The curly braces belonging to the main function or my other functions
到目前为止，我已经写过了。
that I've written thus far.
但是在这种情况下，问题是
But in this case, the problem is when you
在花括号内声明一个变量，
declare a variable inside of curly braces,
你遇到了我们称之为范围问题的问题。
you run into what we'll call an issue of scope.
变量的范围是它所在的代码行。
The scope of a variable is the lines of code in which it exists.
变量的范围是你可以在其中使用该变量的代码行。
The scope of a variable are the lines of code where you can use that variable.
今天的经验法则是，如果你
And the rule of thumb for today is that if you
在花括号内声明一个变量
declare a variable inside of curly braces
就像第26和28行的内容一样
like those here on line 26 and 28, which you
必须做一个do while循环，那个变量n
must do for a do while loop, that variable, n,
仅存在于那些花括号内。
only exists inside of those curly braces.
这意味着你无法将其与第29行中的一个进行比较。
Which means you cannot compare it against one in line 29.
这意味着你不能在第30行中返回它。
Which means you cannot return it in line 30.
它不再存在。
It just no longer exists.
因此，你正在做所有这些工作，先获取变量n，然后进行繁荣。
So you're doing all of this work getting the variable n, and then boom.
一旦你从上到下退出这些花括号，它就消失了。
It's gone once you exit top to bottom these curly braces.
因此，坦白地说，这是很愚蠢的，
So the workaround for that, stupid though it is frankly,
是你可以在其自己的行25上初始声明n。
is that you can declare n initially on its own line, 25.
你甚至不需要为其分配值，因为
You don't need to assign it a value even, because you're
最终将为其分配一个值。
going to assign it a value eventually.
但是，正如我一直说的那样，创建一个变量就是声明一个变量。
But again, to create a variable, as I keep saying, is to declare a variable.
你无需将其定义为必须立即具有值。
You don't need to define it as having a value necessarily right away.
因此，这是解决范围问题的一种方法。
So this is a way to work around what's otherwise known as an issue of scope.
好吧，现在所有这些拼图都可以使用了，可以这么说，
All right, with all of these puzzle pieces now in place so to speak,
让我继续并提出解决方案
let me go ahead and propose that we solve
一些图形化的东西。
something a little more graphical.
因此，你当然会记得，超级马里奥兄弟是第一个问题
So you'll recall, of course, Super Mario Brothers is one of the first problem
我们提到上周的场景。
sets that we alluded to last week.
在这个游戏中，有很多视觉效果。
And within this game there's a whole bunch of visuals.
例如，早期的视觉效果
For instance, there's this visual early on where
天空中有四个问号。
there's four question marks in the sky.
这些问号，如果你跳到上面和下面，
And these question marks, if you jump up and underneath them,
例如给你硬币。
give you coins for instance.
因此，让我引起我们的注意，让我问，
So let me draw our attention to that, and let me ask, well,
我怎么能用C编写一个只打印出四个问号的程序？
how could I write a program in C that just prints out four question marks?
好吧，让我继续执行此操作。
Well, let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续编写一个名为mario.c的程序。
Let me go ahead and write a program called mario.c.
让我继续并将stdio.h包含在名为mario.c的文件中。
Let me go ahead and include stdio.h in a file called mario.c.
给自己一个主要功能，int main void。
Give myself a main function, int main void.
我将保持简单。
I'm going to keep this simple.
Printf一，二，三，四，反斜杠n分号。
Printf one, two, three, four, backslash n semicolon.
这不像老式游戏那么酷，也不漂亮，
This is not nearly as cool or pretty as the old school game,
但是如果我运行make mario然后再做点斜杠mario，瞧。
but if I run make mario and then do dot slash mario, voila.
我对天空中的这四个方块的估计非常差
I get a very poor approximation of these four blocks in the sky
仅使用Ascii，或真正称为Ascii艺术。
using just Ascii, or really called Ascii art.
但是我可以做得更好。
But I can do a little better than that.
回想一下，现在我们可以使用循环了。
Recall that now we have the ability to use loops.
所以我可以说我为零。
So I could say for int i gets zero.
我不到四个，我加号。
i is less than four, i plus plus.
然后我可以一次打印一个问号。
And then I could just print out one question mark at a time.
然后在程序的最后，我
And then at the very end of my program, I
可以打印出新行，只是在最后一刻移动光标。
could print out a new line just to move the cursor at the very last moment.
我不想每个问号都这样
I don't want to do that every question mark,
因为那样的话它将是垂直的。
because then it would be vertical.
我只想在最后做。
I want to do it only at the end.
所以现在如果我做马里奥，我现在就经营马里奥。
So now if I make mario, and I run mario now.
完全相同的结果，但在某种意义上要好一些
Same exact result, but a little better in the sense
现在它使用循环而不是硬编码值。
that now it's using a loop instead of a hard coded value.
但是，现在让我变得更聪明一点，让我来做。
But let me be a little more clever now, and let me do this instead.
让我借用那个正整数示例的逻辑
Let me borrow the logic of that positive integer example
并做这样的事情。
and do something like this.
让我给我自己一个变量，n表示一个数字。
Let me give myself a variable called, n, for a number.
让我像以前一样做以下事情。
And let me do the following just like before.
让我从用户那里得到一个整数，然后问用户
Let me get an integer from the user, and ask the user
我要打印的砖的宽度。
for the width of the bricks that I want to print.
因此并不总是四个。
So it's not always four.
也许这是一个可变数字。
Maybe it's a variable number.
然后让我继续，在n小于1时执行此操作。
And then let me go ahead and do this while n is less than one.
与我以前的逻辑完全相同。
So identical to my logic before.
然后你知道吗？
And then you know what?
一旦我得到n的值-
Once I have a value of n--
所以让我继续在这里给我自己一个评论。
so let me go ahead up here and give myself a comment.
从用户处获取正整数。
Get positive integer from user.
而是说了所有这些代码行的功能。
That rather says what all of these lines of code do.
我不需要注释每一行。
I don't need to comment every single line.
如果这样做合乎逻辑，则可以每隔几条发表评论。
You can comment every few if it makes logical sense to do so.
现在让我继续并打印出许多问号。
Let me go ahead now and print out that many question marks.
所以我可以做一个循环。
So I can do a loop.
因为int我为零，所以我这次小于n，我加上加号。
For int i gets zero, i is less than n this time, i plus plus.
现在，我可以打印出一个问号而无需换行。
And now I can print out a single question mark without a new line.
然后在程序的最后，我
And then at the very end of my program, I
可以打印出一个新的换行分号。
can print out a single new line semicolon.
现在让我继续，增加终端窗口的大小。
Let me go ahead now and increase the size of my terminal window.
让我做马里奥。
Let me do make mario.
现在-哦，该死的。
And now-- oh, darn it.
函数get_int的隐式声明。
Implicit declaration of function get_int.
在这里help50可能是我的朋友。
Here's where help50 might be my friend.
因此，让我继续运行help50 make mario。
So let me go ahead and run help50 make mario.
它会寻求帮助。
It's going to ask for help.
你似乎在第9行的mario.c中出错。
You seem to have an error in mario.c on line nine.
通过隐式声明get_int函数，
By implicit declaration of function get_int,
clang的意思是-这是编译器的名称，我们将在下周看到-
clang means-- which is the name of the compiler, which we'll see next week--
表示无法识别get_int。
means that it doesn't recognize get_int.
你是否忘了在其中包含get_int的cs50.h？
Did you forget to include cs50.h in which get_int
在文件顶部声明。
declared at top of your file.
确实，我做到了。
And indeed, I did.
所以让我解决这个问题。
So let me fix this.
因此包括cs50.h。
So include cs50.h.
保存文件。
Save the file.
用make mario重新编译。
Recompile with make mario.
现在让我继续做点斜杠马里奥，
And now let me go ahead and do dot slash mario,
我给我自己四个宽度。
and I'll give myself a width of four.
一样的。
It's the same.
让我给自己一个40的宽度。
Let me give myself a width of 40.
现在，我得到了这种动力。
Now I get that dynamism.
让我给自己一个50的宽度，依此类推。
Let me give myself a width of 50, and so forth.
所以现在我们有了一个更具动态性的程序，但是你知道吗？
So now we have a program that's much more dynamic, but you know what?
让我们继续进行进一步的增强。
Let's go ahead and enhance this a little further.
后来在《超级马里奥兄弟》中，有很多这样的黑社会
Later on in Super Mario Brothers, there's like a lot of this underworld
在这里，你可以看到这些砖砌的网格，
here where you see these grids of bricks,
让我引起我们的注意。
and let me draw our attention to this.
看起来在水平和垂直方向上都是多块砖。
This looks like multiple bricks both horizontally and vertically.
所以有一个宽度和一个高度。
So there's a width and a height.
因此，我该如何打印出来，也许是三乘三。
So how can I go about printing out, maybe that's three by three.
三块砖隔了三块砖。
Three bricks across by three bricks down.
让我实际上在这里进入我的程序。
Let me actually go into my program here.
摆脱以前所有的问号内容。
Get rid of all the question mark stuff from before.
并考虑如何打印出三乘三的网格。
And consider how I could print out a three by three grid.
好吧，这里的糟糕方法是，如果我回到我的代码中，
Well, the bad approach here, if I go back into my code,
将打印出其中的三个。
would be to print out three of these.
然后可能是三个。
And then maybe three more.
也许再增加三个，然后再增加三个。
Maybe three more, and then three more.
但是，当然，这种复制粘贴不会长期飞行，
But of course, this copy paste is not going to fly long term,
没关系
but that's fine.
让我做马里奥。
Let me do make mario.
马里奥（Mario）点斜线。
Dot slash mario.
好的。
All right.
我有点像这里有一个看起来像这个东西的网格。
I kind of sort of have a grid that looks like this thing here.
这不完全是，但至少是正确的主意。
It's not exactly, but at least it's the right idea.
但这不一定是最好的方法。
But this is not necessarily the best way to do this.
我真的很想跨三下三。
I really want to go three across and three down.
好吧，事实证明，使用C实际上我们也可以表达这一点。
Well, it turns out using C we can actually express that as well.
让我继续执行此操作。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我继续进行打印，例如，以下内容。
Let me go ahead and print out for instance, the following.
让我继续打印并不仅仅是散列，散列，散列
Let me go ahead and print out not just hash, hash, hash, again
一遍又一遍。
and again and again.
让我继续执行此操作。
Let me go ahead and do this.
让我一次打印出一行。
Let me print out one row at a time.
因此，对于int来说，我得到零，我不到三，加上加号。
So for int i gets zero, i less than three, plus plus.
我尚不知道要做什么，但我知道
I don't know what I'm about to do yet, but I know
我要去做三遍。
that I'm going to do it three times.
我想做什么三遍？
What do I want to do three times?
好吧，我要三行，每行我要三个哈希。
Well, I want three rows, and on every row I want three hashes.
所以你知道你能做什么？
So you know what you can do?
你可以嵌套循环。
You can nest loops.
让我做一下，因为int j变为零，j小于3，并且j加号。
Let me do for int j gets zero, j is less than three, and j plus plus.
我不知道我要做什么，但是我知道
I don't know what I'm going to do yet, but I do
知道我要做三遍。
know I'm going to do this three times.
你也许可以看到前进的方向。
And you can perhaps see where this is going.
三件事三遍，这将给我全部九块砖头。
Three things three times, that's going to give me all nine bricks.
可以说，只要在这个内部循环的内部，这个嵌套循环，
So long as inside of this inner loop, so to speak, this nested loop,
我打印这些哈希值之一。
I print one of those hashes.
只要循环之后，我就在这里打印出新的一行。
So long as after that loop, I print out a new line over here.
因此，要明确一点，即使乍一看并不明显，这是什么
So to be clear, even if it's not obvious at first glance what's
继续，我们已经知道这是你用于执行语法的类型
going on, we already know that this is the type of syntax you use for doing
有限多次，三次。
something finitely many times, three.
这是相同的语法，但是我使用了不同的变量名。
This is the same syntax, but I'm using a different variable name.
因此，我可以跟踪两个不同的值。
So I can keep track of two different values.
本质上是行和列。
Essentially, rows and columns.
然后我每次只打印一块砖。
And then I'm just printing a single brick each time.
但是，当我完成整行打印后，我
But after I'm done printing a whole row, I
确实要将光标移动到新行。
do want to move the cursor to a new line.
因此，让我尝试一下。
So let me try this.
让我继续，并在代码上设置马里奥。
Let me go ahead and do make mario on my code.
点斜线马里奥和瞧。
Dot slash mario, and voila.
现在，我正在使用嵌套循环来打印出这样的积木。
Now I'm using a nested loop to print out bricks like this.
我可以改变这一点。
And I can change this.
如果我想以10乘10来做，那么我要做的就是将其更改为一个位置。
If I want to do a 10 by 10, all I have to do is change that in one place.
或者，如果我真的想花哨的话，可以再次使用get_int。
Or if I really wanted to be fancy, I could go use get_int again.
我可以从用户那里获得宽度和高度
I could get the width and the height from the user
并完全动态地进行
and do it completely dynamically.
但是现在，例如，如果我按10乘10进行，至少可以看到更大的网格。
But now if I do 10 by 10 for instance, I can at least see an even bigger grid.
因此，如果你想知道超级马里奥兄弟（Super Mario Brothers）还是坦率地说
So if you wonder how things like Super Mario Brothers, or frankly
如今可以在PC或游戏机或手机上制作任何游戏，
any game nowadays on a PC or console or phone are made,
就是这种类型的地图。
it's with this kind of generation of maps.
也许早在他们被硬编码的那一天，也许它们是生成的。
Maybe back in the day they were hard coded, maybe they were generated.
使用代码，你可以完全想象生成一个接一个的积木
Using code you can absolutely imagine generating brick after brick
像这样的积木，最终，甚至是你的游戏，甚至是你的世界，
after brick like that so that, ultimately, your game even, your world,
是部分动态生成的。
is partly dynamically generated.
而且我们已经有了构建的基础。
And we already have the building blocks via which to do that.
不幸的是，我们还没有真正谈到限制
Unfortunately, we haven't really spoken to the limitations
计算机可以做什么。
of what computers can do.
在最后几分钟，我们认为我们已经为事情做好了准备
And in our final minutes we thought we'd set the stage for things
电脑不是很擅长
that computers aren't very good at.
实际上，几乎所有方面都存在潜在的问题
And in fact, problems that are latent in pretty much everything
我们今天已经完成，但是我一直非常小心地避免绊倒。
we've done today, but I've been very carefully avoiding tripping over.
此图是典型计算机内存的图，
This picture here is a picture of a typical computer's memory,
或RAM，随机存取存储器。
or RAM, random access memory.
这只是你要使用的硬件之一
It's just one of the pieces of hardware that you'd
这些天，你的手机，台式机和笔记本电脑中都有。
have in your phone, your desktop, your laptop these days.
它是程序运行时的存储位置。
And it's where programs are stored when they're running.
因此，在Mac或PC中，如果双击某个程序
So in a Mac or PC, if you double click a program
它最终存储在看起来像这样的硬件中。
it's ultimately stored in a piece of hardware that looks like this.
当你在斜杠上加点斜杠并在像这样的程序中按Enter键时，
When you dot slash mario and hit Enter in a program like this,
你使用的是CS50 IDE的RAM，尽管有相同的想法，
you're using CS50 IDE's RAM, but same idea, albeit,
云中的其他地方。
somewhere else in the cloud.
因此，事实证明，如果你只有有限的内存，
So it turns out, though, that if you only have a finite amount of memory,
这样，你只能做很多事情。
like this, you can only do so much with it.
你无法解决世界上所有的问题
You can't solve all of the world's problems
如果你只有有限的内存。
if you only have a finite amount of memory.
那我是什么意思呢？
And what do I mean by that?
好吧，让我继续在这里创建另一个名为imprecision.c的程序，
Well, let me go ahead and create another program here called imprecision.c,
我们马上就会知道为什么要如此命名。
and we'll see why I've named it that in just a moment.
让我继续并再次包含stdio.h和int main void
Let me go ahead and include stdio.h, again, and int main void just
给自己一些设置。
to give myself some set up here.
然后让我继续，非常合理地
And then let me go ahead and very reasonably very
只需向用户询问一个名为x的变量（作为类型float）即可。
simply ask the user for a variable called x as a type float.
让我像以前一样要求值。
Let me ask for the value just like before.
让我以y的形式要求另一个，请用引号引起来的“ y”。
Let me ask for another one in the form of y, quote unquote "y."
然后让我继续前进，你知道吗？
And then let me go ahead, and you know what?
让我继续，用百分比f打印x的值除以y。
Let me go ahead and print out with percent f the value of x divided by y.
因此，我很确定我们之前已经这样做了。
So I'm pretty sure we did this earlier.
我们按照价值观进行了划分。
We did division with values.
这次我正在使用浮点数，但让我们继续进行一下。
This time I'm using floats, but let's go ahead and just run this.
不精确-我在这里烦死了。
Make imprecision-- and I goofed here.
隐式-我一直在做-函数get_float的隐式声明。
Implicit-- I keep doing it-- implicit declaration of function get_float.
我没有练习我一直在讲的东西。
I didn't practice what I've been preaching.
我还需要包含cs50.h，这是它定义了get_float的地方。
I also need to include cs50.h, which is where it get_float is defined.
现在，让我重新编译。
Now, let me recompile.
现在可以了。
Now it works.
现在，让我继续不精确。
Now, let me go ahead and run imprecision.
让我继续输入十分之一。
And let me go ahead and type in one tenth.
好的。
OK.
因此，根据我这里非常简单的计算器，结果只有十分之一，
So one tenth it turns out, according to my very simple calculator here,
是0.100000。
is 0.100000.
但是我现在有点好奇了。
But I'm getting a little curious now.
事实证明，printf的功能比我们所见过的还要强大，
It turns out that printf is even more powerful than we've seen,
而且你实际上可以打印出多个位数。
and you can actually print out more than just single digits.
假设我要打印的不是六个有效数字，而是十个。
Suppose I want to print out not six significant digits, but maybe 10.
语法有点时髦，但是与其说百分比f，
It's a little funky the syntax, but instead of saying percent f,
你可以改写字面意义，用百分号表示数字
you can instead say literally, percent dot the number of digits
你想看然后按f。
you want to see and then the f.
因此，让我继续进行重新编译，使其变得不精确。
So let me go ahead and recompile this, make imprecision.
现在让我做点斜线的不精确度和十分之一
Now let me do dot slash imprecision and one tenth--
嗯。
uh-huh.
好吧，这有点好奇。
Well, that's a little curious.
我不记得知道十分之一的末尾有15。
I don't recall knowing that there's a 15 at the end of one tenth.
好吧，让我们再好奇一点。
Well, let's get a little more curious.
让我们打印出50个小数点，以真正了解这里的情况。
Let's print out 50 decimal points to really dig into what's going on here.
让我重新编译我的代码。
Let me recompile my code.
让我重新运行点斜线的不精确度，然后将其除以十，
And let me rerun dot slash imprecision and do one divided by ten,
哦，天哪。
and oh my God.
我很确定在小学时，我们都学过一除以十，
I am quite sure in grade school when we all learned one divided by ten,
老师确实告诉我们十分之一或0.1。
the teacher did tell us one tenth or 0.1.
他们从未提到过它是0.10000000149011的事实，依此类推。
And they never mentioned the fact that it's 0.10000000149011, and so forth.
那么发生了什么？
So what is going on?
好吧，事实证明它和计算机一样强大
Well, it turns out as powerful as computers
与我们今天一直在研究的所有语法一样，并且也是如此复杂
are and is as sophisticated as all of the syntax we've been looking at today
是的，我的天哪，一台计算机甚至无法正确计算十分之一。
is, my God, a computer can't even calculate one tenth correctly.
因此，我们在这里遇到了一个基本限制，
And so we're bumping up against a fundamental limitation here,
也就是说，如果计算机的容量有限。
which is that if computers are finite in their capacity.
他们只有这么多的RAM，那么多的硬件，那么多的位。
They only have so much RAM, so much hardware, so many bits.
好吧，这是有原因的，如果你只使用有限数量的位，
Well, it stands to reason that if you only are using a finite number of bits,
例如32或64。
32 for instance, or 64.
是的，你可以算得很高或很精确。
Yes, you can count pretty high or pretty precisely.
你不能无限地计数或无限精确地计数。
You cannot count infinitely high or infinitely precisely.
在某些时候，你必须开始近似值。
At some point you have to start to approximate values.
确实，这就是计算机的功能。
And indeed, that's what the computer is doing.
如果它只有有限数量的位，则32代表一个浮点数。
If it only has a finite number of bits, 32, via which to represent a float.
世界上有无数个浮点实数。
There's an infinite number of floating point real numbers in the world.
不幸的是，如果你的位数有限，
Unfortunately, if you have a finite number of bits,
你必须开始偷工减料。
you've got to start cutting some corners.
这就是计算机正在执行的操作。
And that's what the computer is doing.
它代表了尽可能近的十分之一，
It's representing one tenth as closely as it can,
这就是当你看到足够多的有效数字时所看到的。
and this is what you then see when you look enough significant digits out.
现在，对于大多数问题而言，这可能并不重要。
Now, for most problems that's probably not a big deal.
但是如果你在做数学的话，那将是非常大的事情，
But it could very well be a big deal if you're doing math,
你正在处理金融或货币价值或军事行动
you're dealing with finance or monetary values or military operations
从科学上讲，很多小数开始真正加起来。
where a lot of small numbers, scientifically, really start to add up.
实际上，在现实世界中有很多例子
And indeed, there have been many examples in the real world
由于这种所谓的不精确而在坏事发生的地方。
where bad things happen because of this so-called imprecision.
而且，计算机还会遇到另一个问题。
And there's another issue that computers run into.
不仅这种浮点数不精确，甚至整数
Not only this floating point imprecision, even integers
有其局限性。
have their limitations.
回想一下，整数当然可以用十进制或二进制表示。
Recall that integers, of course, can be represented in decimal or in binary.
如果我们有三个灯泡或三个位，
And if we have three light bulbs or three bits,
让我们考虑如何计算二进制数。
let's consider how we might count in binary.
零，零，零是我们上周开始的地方。
Zero, zero, zero is where we began last week.
001、010、011、100、101、110、111。
001, 010, 011, 100, 101, 110, 111.
现在，上周的召回事件是我们知道的十进制数字7。
And now, this recall from last week is the number we know is seven in decimal.
我如何算高一位数？
How do I count one digit higher?
好吧，我可以随身携带一个。
Well, I just carry the one, so to speak.
但是，如果我只有三个灯泡，或者只有三个灯泡，或者是32位，那么。
But if I only have three light bulbs or in turn three bits, or heck, 32 bits.
那个额外的进位消失了。
That additional bit, the carry, disappears.
因此，整数也存在这个问题。
And so there's this problem with integers too.
有人指出，当你尝试做20亿加20亿时，
And someone noted earlier when you tried to do 2 billion plus 2 billion,
它不适合结果。那是因为整数
it couldn't fit in the result. That's because integers
如果它们只有32位或较长的C语言，也是如此。如果只有64位，则它们很大
too if they're only 32 bits or a long in C. If it's only 64 bits, those are big
数字，但它们不是无限大的。
numbers, but they're not infinitely large.
我们人类一次又一次地绊倒了。
And we humans have tripped over this again and again.
你可能会回想起有关是否不能度过Y2K问题的消息。
You might recall hearing about if not living through the Y2K problem.
世界上有很多东西破裂或曾经在那里
Where a lot of stuff in the world broke or was
担心在2000年1月1日被打破，因为人类
worried to be broken on January 1st, 2000, because humans
做出了合理但又不是很长远的眼光
had made the reasonable but not very long sighted
决定仅使用两位数字存储年份。
decision to store years using just two digits.
因此1995将代表95、96、97、98、99。
So 1995 would be represented as 95, 96, 97, 98, 99.
然后是从1999年到2000年的变化，
Then around the change of the year from 1999 to 2000,
任何仍在使用两位数的计算机程序或系统
any computer program or system that was still using two digits
当然会在午夜时分加一。
would, of course, add one at the stroke of midnight.
不幸的是，如果没有可用的第三位数字，它将消失。
Unfortunately, if there's no third digit available it disappears.
全世界都把2000年和1900年搞混了，
And the entire world confuses the year 2000 for the year 1900,
因为假定1900为前缀。
because 1900 was assumed as being the prefix.
如果你可以相信，我们人类将再次这样做
And if you can believe it, we humans are about to do this again
在2038年，离现在不远了。
in the year 2038, which is not that far off from now.
我们将用完一些时间来跟踪时间。
We are going to run out of bits via which to keep track of time.
因为几年前，人类当时做出了合理的决定，
Because years ago, humans decided reasonably at the time,
他们将使用32位代表数字。
they are going to use 32 bits to represent numbers.
我们将使用32位来计算秒数
And we are going to use 32 bits to count up the number of seconds
从年份开始，即1970年1月1日。
from the year a date, January 1st, 1970.
所以从某种意义上讲，那是时间开始明智地进行计算的时候，
So that's when time began computing wise, in some sense,
从那时起，我们一直在数秒。
and we've been counting the seconds ever since.
不幸的是，使用32位，你只能算到40亿
Unfortunately, with 32 bits you can only count as high as 4 billion
给予或接受。
give or take.
不幸的是，我们将在1月19日达到40亿秒
And unfortunately, we are going to hit the four billionth second on January 19
在2038年。
in the year 2038.
因此，除非我们所有人都升级Mac和PCS，否则，
So unless all of us upgrade our Macs and PCS, and worse,
嵌入式系统和卫星以及烘焙到各种设备中的任何硬件
embedded systems and satellites and any hardware baked into various devices
我们现在使用的，我们将要遇到这个问题
that we now use, we're about to run into this problem
又是突然之间，就像1970年1月1日
again where all of a sudden and it's going to be like January 1st, 1970
再次。
again.
除非我们继续解决这个问题。
Unless we stay ahead of this problem.
因此，借助我们在C语言中看到的所有功能以及所有功能，
So with all the power we've seen in C and all of the capabilities
我们已经在C和Scratch中看到了
that we've seen in C and in Scratch, there are still
这些基本限制。
these fundamental limitations.
因此，在解决你自己的C问题以及CS50问题时，
So when it comes to solving your own problems in C and in turn CS50,
牢记这些限制将变得非常重要
it's going to be ever so important to be mindful of these constraints
并最终为这些问题找到解决方案。
and to, ultimately, find solutions even to these problems.
但是现在，我们将在这里休会，离开你
But for now, we'll adjourn here, and leave you
针对你在Mario C上的第一个问题以及更多内容。
for your first problem set in C on Mario and more.
下次见。
We'll see you next time.
[音乐播放]
[MUSIC PLAYING]